<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="154852" pubid="1512" publish="true">
<title>Historical Geography: Britain</title>
<subtitle></subtitle>
<section id="s1">
<head>HISTORICAL GEOGRAPHY: BRITAIN</head>
<section id="s2">
<head>ENGLAND</head>
<section id="s3">
<head>South</head>
<para id="p1"><emph type="i">An historical and political geography of Wessex.</emph> K.I. James. Wales M.A. 1950.</para>
<para id="p2"><emph type="i">The historical geography of Cornwall.</emph> N.J.G. Pounds. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1945.</para>
<page start="016"/>
<para id="p3"><emph type="i">The geographical development of west Cornwall.</emph> C.F.W.R. Gullick. Oxford B.Litt. 1934.</para>
<para id="p4"><emph type="i">The West Penwith peninsula of Cornwall, considered from the point of view of archaeological evidences concerning development of settlements.</emph> D.H. Watkins. Wales M.A. 1930.</para>
<para id="p5"><emph type="i">The evolution of settlement in Devon.</emph> W.L.D. Ravenhill. Wales M.A. 1951.</para>
<para id="p6"><emph type="i">A comparative study of Kingsbridge and Totnes.</emph> A. Dark. London M.Sc. 1961.</para>
<para id="p7"><emph type="i">The past agricultural utilisation of Dartmoor.</emph> E.G. Fogwill. London M.A. 1952.</para>
<para id="p8"><emph type="i">A study of rural settlement in Somerset.</emph> Beatrice M. Swainson. London M.A. (Ext.) 1932.</para>
<para id="p9"><emph type="i">The settlement pattern in north central Somerset.</emph> J.M. Jennings. Bristol M.A. 1957.</para>
<para id="p10"><emph type="i">The scarplands of the Wiltshire-Gloucestershire-Somerset borders - a regional study, with particular reference to urban and rural settlement.</emph> Irene G. Youldon. London M.A. 1945.</para>
<para id="p11"><emph type="i">The evolution of rural settlement in Dorset.</emph> L. Pritchard. Wales M.Sc. 1954.</para>
<para id="p12"><emph type="i">Late medieval Dorset: three essays in historical geography.</emph> B. Reynolds. London M.A. 1958.</para>
<para id="p13"><emph type="i">Southampton: a factor in the economic development of the Hampshire basin.</emph> Katharine C. Boswell. London M.Sc. (Ext.) 1936.</para>
<para id="p14"><emph type="i">The agricultural geography of the Adur basin in its regional setting.</emph> H.C.K. Henderson. London Ph.D. 1935.</para>
<para id="p15"><emph type="i">An analysis of some of the interactions of geography and history in the Arun and Adur valleys.</emph> Alice F.A. Mutton. London M.A. 1932.</para>
<para id="p16"><emph type="i">A contribution to the historical geography of the western Weald.</emph> E.M. Yates. London M.Sc. 1953.</para>
<para id="p17"><emph type="i">The influence of physical geography upon the history of settlement and distribution of population in Sussex.</emph> W.H. Parker. Oxford B.Sc. 1939.</para>
<para id="p18"><emph type="i">The Sussex gap towns: a geographical analysis.</emph> D. Burtenshaw. London M.A. 1963.</para>
<para id="p19"><emph type="i">The common lands and wastes of Sussex.</emph> P.F. Brandon. London Ph.D. 1963.</para>
<para id="p20"><emph type="i">Horsham: a geographical study.</emph> Florence A. Hamblin. London M.A. 1962.</para>
<para id="p21"><emph type="i">The field systems of Kent.</emph> A.R.H. Baker. London Ph.D. 1963.</para>
<para id="p22"><emph type="i">The Medway towns: their settlement, growth and economic development.</emph> H. Rees. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1955.</para>
<para id="p23"><emph type="i">The origins and changing functions of settlement in southeast London, with special reference to the flood-plain section of the borough of Deptford.</emph> Gladys M. Hickman. London Ph.D. 1951.</para>
<para id="p24"><emph type="i">The historical geography of Maidstone.</emph> Valerie E. Morant. London M.A. 1948.</para>
<para id="p25"><emph type="i">The manor of Tyburn and the Regent's Park, 1086&ndash;1965.</emph> Ann L. Saunders. Leicester Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<para id="p26"><emph type="i">The historical geography of the upper Brent.</emph> A.J. Garrett. London M.A. 1935.</para>
<para id="p27"><emph type="i">The city of St. Albans: a study in urban geography.</emph> H.S. Thurston. London M.Sc. 1951.</para>
<para id="p28"><emph type="i">The geography of Berkshire with special reference to agriculture.</emph> J. Stephenson. London M.A. 1936.</para>
<para id="p29"><emph type="i">The Vale of White Horse area: a regional study of settlement.</emph> M.W. Smith. London M.Sc. 1956.</para>
<para id="p30"><emph type="i">Settlement patterns in the Chilterns.</emph> J.W.R. Whitehand. Reading Ph.D. 1964.</para>
<para id="p31"><emph type="i">Studies in Chiltern field systems.</emph> D. Roden. London Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<page start="017"/>
</section>
<section id="s4">
<head>East and North</head>
<para id="p32"><emph type="i">The distribution and functions of urban settlements in East Anglia.</emph> R.E. Dickinson. London Ph.D. 1933.</para>
<para id="p33"><emph type="i">Historical geography of south-east Essex.</emph> R. Coles. London Ph.D. 1934.</para>
<para id="p34"><emph type="i">The changing geographical landscape of south-west Essex from Saxon times to 1600.</emph> R. Allison. London M.A. 1958.</para>
<para id="p35"><emph type="i">Chelmsford: the evolution of a county town.</emph> M.R.H. Innes. London M.A. 1951.</para>
<para id="p36"><emph type="i">Saffron Walden and its environs: a study in the development of a landscape.</emph> Mrs. Dorothy Monteith. London M.A. 1957.</para>
<para id="p37"><emph type="i">The open fields of Cambridgeshire.</emph> M.R. Postgate. Cambridge Ph.D. 1963/4.</para>
<para id="p38"><emph type="i">The field boundaries of Huntingdonshire.</emph> Mrs. Elizabeth Teather, <emph type="i">n&eacute;e</emph> Kenworthy. London Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p39"><emph type="i">Contributions towards the study of the historical geography of Norfolk, with special reference to west Norfolk.</emph> S.H. King. London M.A. 1937.</para>
<para id="p40"><emph type="i">The making of King's Lynn from the 11th to the 17th century.</emph> Vanessa S. Parker. Sheffield Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p41"><emph type="i">Contributions towards the study of the historical geography of Lincolnshire.</emph> S.H. King. London Ph.D. 1945.</para>
<para id="p42"><emph type="i">The historical geography of Co. Durham in the 12th and 13th centuries.</emph> G.H. Burden. London M.A. 1961.</para>
<para id="p43"><emph type="i">The historical geography of Co. Durham during the middle ages.</emph> P. Dickinson. Durham Ph.D. 1957.</para>
<para id="p44"><emph type="i">The geography of rural settlement in the Durham region.</emph> H. Thorpe. Durham M.Litt. 1936.</para>
<para id="p45"><emph type="i">The rural geography of the west Durham Pennines.</emph> D. Thompson. Manchester M.A. 1962.</para>
<para id="p46"><emph type="i">The historical geography of the Newark area as illustrating changes in the importance of geographical factors.</emph> Hilda M. Keating. London M.A. 1929.</para>
<para id="p47"><emph type="i">The factors which have influenced settlement and the movements of population within the plain of Nottingham.</emph> Hilda M. Keating. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1933.</para>
<para id="p48"><emph type="i">The development of Burton-upon-Trent: a study in urban geography.</emph> A.J. Halliday. London M.A. 1956.</para>
<para id="p49"><emph type="i">The making of the Peakland cultural landscape.</emph> J.P. Carr. Reading M.A. 1962.</para>
<para id="p50"><emph type="i">A consideration of the factors limiting land improvement and settlement on the upland east of the Derbyshire Derwent.</emph> S.R. Eyre. Sheffield Ph.D. 1954.</para>
<para id="p51"><emph type="i">Rural settlements in upland Derbyshire.</emph> L. Wharfe. Manchester M.A. 1955.</para>
<para id="p52"><emph type="i">Studies in the historical geography of the East Riding of Yorkshire.</emph> A. Harris. Hull Ph.D. 1962.</para>
<para id="p53"><emph type="i">Harrogate and Knaresborough: a study in urban development.</emph> J.A. Patmore. Oxford B.Litt. 1960.</para>
<para id="p54"><emph type="i">The urban plan of Leeds and the factors which have conditioned its growth.</emph> D. Ward. Leeds M.A. 1961.</para>
<para id="p55"><emph type="i">Village and field in the Pickering district of north Yorkshire: an essay in historical geography.</emph> Pamela Allerston. London M.Sc. 1966.</para>
<para id="p56"><emph type="i">Some aspects of the historical geography of the Vale of Pickering area, 1086&ndash;1350 A.D.</emph> W.R. Wightman. Durham Ph.D. 1963/4.</para>
<para id="p57"><emph type="i">A study of the settlements to the north of the Vale of Pickering.</emph> N.M. Musto. Durham M.Litt. 1962.</para>
<para id="p58"><emph type="i">Regional variations in land-use in mid-Ribblesdale since late medieval times.</emph> A. Digby. Leeds M.A. 1960.</para>
<para id="p59"><emph type="i">Regionalism in rural settlement in the Pennines of north-west Yorkshire.</emph> W.N. Teale. Durham M.Litt. 1958.</para>
<para id="p60"><emph type="i">Some aspects of economic history in the parish records of upper Wharfedale, upper Airedale and parts of north-west Yorkshire.</emph> Margaret Slack. Leeds M.A. 1954.</para>
<page start="018"/>
<para id="p61"><emph type="i">The historical geography of the rural landscape of Northumberland.</emph> R.A. Butlin. Liverpool M.A. 1961.</para>
<para id="p62"><emph type="i">The older settlements of north Northumberland: a study in geography and history.</emph> Constance P.M. Olsen. London M.A. 1947.</para>
<para id="p63"><emph type="i">The historical geography of south-west Lancashire prior to the Industrial Revolution.</emph> F. Walker. Liverpool M.A. 1937.</para>
<para id="p64"><emph type="i">Historical geography of the Makerfield district in south Lancashire.</emph> H. Fairhurst. Liverpool M.A. 1922.</para>
<para id="p65"><emph type="i">The rural landscape of the Furness peninsula: a study in historical geography.</emph> W. Rollinson. Manchester M.A. 1961.</para>
<para id="p66"><emph type="i">The urban geography of Barrow-in-Furness.</emph> A.D. Hammersley. Manchester M.A. 1965.</para>
<para id="p67"><emph type="i">Salford (Lancs.): its growth and morphology.</emph> E.T. Parham. Manchester M.A. 1957.</para>
<para id="p68"><emph type="i">The history of Standish.</emph> T.C. Porteus. Manchester M.A. 1924.</para>
<para id="p69"><emph type="i">Common lands and enclosure in Lancashire.</emph> G. Youd. Liverpool M.A. 1958.</para>
<para id="p70"><emph type="i">The origin of settlements in the Cheshire plain - an essay in historical geography.</emph> W.J. Varley. Wales M.A. 1934.</para>
<para id="p71"><emph type="i">Rural settlement in east Cheshire: a study in historical geography.</emph> Pauline F. Kenworthy. Manchester M.A. 1949.</para>
<para id="p72"><emph type="i">The land utilisation of Cheshire.</emph> E.P. Boon. London M.Sc. 1941.</para>
<para id="p73"><emph type="i">The reclamation and agricultural development of the mossland areas of north Cheshire and south Lancashire.</emph> D.B. Hardman. Manchester M.A. 1961.</para>
<para id="p74"><emph type="i">The relationship between the spread of settlement and agricultural changes in south Manchester and north Cheshire.</emph> E.L. Naylor. Manchester M.A. 1968.</para>
<para id="p75"><emph type="i">The early historical geography of Chester.</emph> G. Conzen. Manchester M.A. 1942.</para>
<para id="p76"><emph type="i">Settlement and economy in a selected area within the Lake District.</emph> T.C.F. Darley. Leicester M.A. 1966.</para>
<para id="p77"><emph type="i">The economic and social decline of the Rossendales.</emph> Christine M. Birdsall. Manchester M.A. 1968.</para>
</section>
<section id="s5">
<head>West and Midlands</head>
<para id="p78"><emph type="i">The historical geography (ancient) of Northamptonshire and the south-east Midlands.</emph> S.B. Harris. London M.Sc. (Ext.) 1945.</para>
<para id="p79"><emph type="i">A study of certain aspects in the cultural landscape of a region around the Malvern Hills.</emph> R.M.J. Marshall. Birmingham M.A. 1953.</para>
<para id="p80"><emph type="i">Patterns of rural settlement in Gloucestershire, Herefordshire and Worcestershire.</emph> P. Hamilton. Reading M.A. 1960.</para>
<para id="p81"><emph type="i">The historical geography of Worcestershire in the early middle ages.</emph> R.J. Cavill. Birmingham M.A. 1936.</para>
<para id="p82"><emph type="i">The development of industry and trade in the middle Severn valley.</emph> T.W. Birch. London M.Sc. (Ext.) 1933.</para>
<para id="p83"><emph type="i">The territorial evolution of Warwickshire: a study in historical and administrative geography.</emph> G.S. Miles. Wales M.A. 1961.</para>
<para id="p84"><emph type="i">Coventry: a study in urban continuity.</emph> R.F. Prosser. Birmingham M.A. 1955.</para>
<para id="p85"><emph type="i">Warwick: a study in urban geography.</emph> W.T. Rhys. Wales M.A. 1961.</para>
<para id="p86"><emph type="i">Population and land utilisation in the Warwickshire hundreds of Stoneleigh and Kineton (1086&ndash;1300): a study in historical geography.</emph> J.B. Harley. Birmingham Ph.D. 1960.</para>
<para id="p87"><emph type="i">The geographical distribution of the agricultural industries of Shropshire.</emph> E.J. Howell. London Ph.D. 1941.</para>
<para id="p88"><emph type="i">Geographical aspects of settlement in southern Shropshire.</emph> Julia M. Wilkes. Leicester M.A. 1961.</para>
<page start="019"/>
<para id="p89"><emph type="i">The history of the south Shropshire landscape, 1086&ndash;1800.</emph> R.T. Rowley. Oxford B.Litt. 1968.</para>
<para id="p90"><emph type="i">Shrewsbury, historical geography and present survey.</emph> G. Joan Fuller. London M.A. (Ext.) 1940.</para>
<para id="p91"><emph type="i">The evolution of rural settlement in Herefordshire.</emph> C.W. Atkin. Liverpool M.A. 1951.</para>
<para id="p92"><emph type="i">The Leintwardine area of north Herefordshire: its physical geography, land use and distribution of population.</emph> D.G. Bayliss. Manchester M.A. 1957.</para>
<para id="p93"><emph type="i">The historical geography of the Forest of Dean.</emph> F.T. Baber. Wales M.A. 1949.</para>
<para id="p94"><emph type="i">The Forest of Dean: a study of physical and historical geography.</emph> P.R.W. Haunton. London M.Sc. 1950.</para>
<para id="p95"><emph type="i">The history of the Forest of Dean as a timber-producing forest.</emph> C.E. Hart. Leicester Ph.D. 1964.</para>
<para id="p96"><emph type="i">The history of Scraptoft, Leics.</emph> Mrs. Nina K. Freebody. Leicester M.A. 1967.</para>
</section>
<section id="s6">
<head>WALES</head>
<para id="p97"><emph type="i">The morphology of Welsh border towns - a study in historical geography.</emph> P.D. Wood. Wales M.A. 1950.</para>
<para id="p98"><emph type="i">The development of the boundary between England and Wales.</emph> P.D. Wood. Reading Ph.D. 1958.</para>
<para id="p99"><emph type="i">Rural settlement in south-west Wales and Cornwall.</emph> Eluned H. Tropp. London M.A. 1951.</para>
<para id="p100"><emph type="i">An investigation into human influences on marsh development in the Burry estuary, South Wales.</emph> B.A.G. Plummer. Wales M.A. 1960.</para>
<para id="p101"><emph type="i">The evolution of settlement in the Teify valley.</emph> E. Jones. Wales M.Sc. 1945.</para>
<para id="p102"><emph type="i">A study of the character of the main changes in the production and distribution of agricultural produce in Cardiganshire in medieval and modern times.</emph> Gertrude M. Lyke. Wales M.A. 1917.</para>
<para id="p103"><emph type="i">Changing land utilisation, occupation and ownership in south-west Carmarthenshire.</emph> W.S.G. Thomas. London Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<para id="p104"><emph type="i">The distribution of woodland, present and past, in the Nant Ffrancon valley and other parts of Caernarvonshire.</emph> L.M. Hodgson. Wales M.Sc. 1933.</para>
<para id="p105"><emph type="i">The growth of settlement in the Swansea valley.</emph> J.M. Davies. Wales M.A. 1942.</para>
<para id="p106"><emph type="i">Rural settlement in the vale of Glamorgan.</emph> N.H. Harries. Birmingham M.A. 1956.</para>
<para id="p107"><emph type="i">The historical geography of the Neath region up to the eve of the Industrial Revolution.</emph> C.D.J. Trott. Wales M.A. 1946.</para>
<para id="p108"><emph type="i">The growth of rural settlement in south-eastern Monmouthshire.</emph> R.A. Worthington. Wales M.A. 1956.</para>
<para id="p109"><emph type="i">Settlement patterns and farm units in western Pembrokeshire: a study in historical geography.</emph> D.H.C. Bennett. Wales M.A. 1955.</para>
<para id="p110"><emph type="i">The evolution of rural settlement and land tenure in Merioneth.</emph> C. Thomas. Wales Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p111"><emph type="i">Little England beyond Wales as a regional unit.</emph> Mrs. Margaret F. Harris. London Ph.D. 1950.</para>
</section>
</section>
<section id="s7">
<head>SCOTLAND AND ISLE OF MAN</head>
<para id="p112"><emph type="i">Some aspects of the early historical geography of Scotland.</emph> H. Fairhurst. Liverpool M.A. 1933.</para>
<para id="p113"><emph type="i">The early historical geography of south-west Scotland.</emph> S.V. Morris. Liverpool M.A. 1935.</para>
<page start="020"/>
<para id="p114"><emph type="i">Land systems and settlement in the Isle of Man.</emph> E. Davies. Manchester Ph.D. 1937.</para>
<para id="p115"><emph type="i">The historical geography of the Shetland Islands.</emph> A.C. O'Dell. London M.Sc. 1933.</para>
<para id="p116"><emph type="i">The geography of Shetland fisheries.</emph> C.A. Goodlad. Aberdeen Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p117"><emph type="i">Changing cultural landscapes of the Orkney Islands.</emph> D.P. Willis. Aberdeen M.Litt. 1967.</para>
<para id="p118"><emph type="i">The political geography of north-east Scotland.</emph> R. Muir. Aberdeen Ph.D. 1970.</para>
</section>
<section id="s8">
<head>IRELAND</head>
<para id="p119"><emph type="i">Rundale and its social concomitants.</emph> D. McCourt. Belfast M.A. 1947.</para>
<para id="p120"><emph type="i">The Rundale system in Ireland: a study of its geographical distribution and social relations.</emph> D. McCourt. Belfast Ph.D. 1950.</para>
<para id="p121"><emph type="i">The evolution of settlement in Co. Antrim down to Norman times.</emph> E. Watson. Belfast M.A. 1940.</para>
<para id="p122"><emph type="i">The historical geography of Armagh.</emph> H.D.McC. Reid. Belfast M.A. 1954.</para>
<para id="p123"><emph type="i">Land utilisation of Co. Armagh.</emph> M.W. Wallace. Belfast M.A. 1951.</para>
<para id="p124"><emph type="i">Settlement and economy in Co. Down from the late bronze age to the Anglo-Norman invasion.</emph> V.B. Proudfoot. Belfast Ph.D. 1957.</para>
<para id="p125"><emph type="i">Land uses in Co. Down: a study in geographical analysis.</emph> F.W. Boal. Belfast M.A. 1958.</para>
<para id="p126"><emph type="i">The Dalradian highlands: a study of hill land utilisation in Kintyre and north Ulster.</emph> L.J. Symons. Belfast Ph.D. 1958.</para>
<para id="p127"><emph type="i">The pattern of farming in Co. Tyrone - a study in land use techniques.</emph> B.J. McHugh. Belfast M.A. 1959.</para>
<para id="p128"><emph type="i">The population and settlement in Northern Ireland.</emph> R.D. James. Wales M.A. 1948.</para>
<para id="p129"><emph type="i">Transhumance in Ireland, with special reference to its bearing on the evolution of rural communities in the West.</emph> Jean M. Graham. Belfast Ph.D. 1954.</para>
<para id="p130"><emph type="i">The history of water-power in Ulster.</emph> H.D. Gribbon. Belfast Ph.D. 1967.</para>
</section>
</section>
</report>
