<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="154850" pubid="1512" publish="true">
<title>Historiography</title>
<subtitle></subtitle>
<section id="s1">
<head>HISTORIOGRAPHY</head>
<section id="s2">
<head>ANCIENT HISTORIOGRAPHY</head>
<para id="p1"><emph type="i">An historical commentary on the <emph type="i">Hellenica Oxyrhynchia</emph>.</emph> I.A.F. Bruce. Sheffield Ph.D. 1963.</para>
<para id="p2"><emph type="i">A comparison of the principles and methods of Herodotus and Thucydides as historians.</emph> T.B. Davis. Wales M.A. 1901.</para>
<para id="p3"><emph type="i">Herodotus as a source for Greek colonisation.</emph> P. Slade. Manchester M.A. 1968.</para>
<para id="p4"><emph type="i">A historical commentary on Herodotus, Book VII, with a general introduction.</emph> O.K. Armayor. Oxford D.Phil. 1969.</para>
<para id="p5"><emph type="i">Public opinion in the history of Thucydides.</emph> T.J. Quinn. Manchester M.A. 1962.</para>
<para id="p6"><emph type="i">Power in Thucydides.</emph> H. Konishi. Liverpool Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p7"><emph type="i">The validity of the evidence of Diodorus Siculus for the Sicilian history, 413&ndash;405 B.C.</emph> L.J. Sanders. London M.A. 1966.</para>
<para id="p8"><emph type="i">The sources and composition of Livy, books xxxi&ndash;xlv.</emph> A.H. McDonald. Cambridge Ph.D. 1937/8.</para>
<para id="p9"><emph type="i">An historical commentary on Sallust's <emph type="i">Bellum Iugurthinum</emph>.</emph> G.M. Paul. London Ph.D. 1963.</para>
<para id="p10"><emph type="i">Historical commentary on Plutarch's Life of Brutus.</emph> Frances M. Wilson. London M.A. 1956.</para>
<para id="p11"><emph type="i">Plutarch's Life of Crassus, with historical commentary.</emph> A.S. Osley. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1942.</para>
<para id="p12"><emph type="i">An edition of Plutarch's Life of Marius.</emph> T.F. Carney. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1957.</para>
<para id="p13"><emph type="i">Plutarch's Life of Pericles.</emph> W.H. Plommer. Oxford D. Phil. 1948.</para>
<para id="p14"><emph type="i">An historical commentary on Plutarch's Life of Pompeius.</emph> D. J. Opie. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1955.</para>
<para id="p15"><emph type="i">The Annals of Tacitus.</emph> A. Splevins. Nottingham M.A. 1966.</para>
<para id="p16"><emph type="i">A commentary, mainly, but not exclusively, devoted to its historical aspects, on the <emph type="i">Vita divi Vespasiani</emph> of C. Suetonius Tranquillus.</emph> A.W. Braithwaite. Oxford B.Litt. 1926.</para>
<para id="p17"><emph type="i">A special study of the language and contents of Josephus' 'Jewish Antiquities', books xi&ndash;xx.</emph> R.J.H. Shutt. Durham Ph.D. 1936.</para>
<para id="p18"><emph type="i">Quintus Curtius Rufus: sources and historical value.</emph> E. I. McQueen. Cambridge M.Litt. 1969.</para>
<page start="002"/>
<para id="p19"><emph type="i">Cassius Dio.</emph> F.G.B. Millar. Oxford D.Phil. 1962.</para>
<para id="p20"><emph type="i">The 'Breviarium' of Festus: a critical edition with historical commentary.</emph> J.W. Eadie. London Ph.D. 1962.</para>
<para id="p21"><emph type="i">Ammianus Marcellinus: a study of his historiography and political ideas.</emph> R.C. Blockley. Nottingham Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p22"><emph type="i">The histories of Agathias: a literary and historical study.</emph> Mrs. Averil M. Cameron. London Ph.D. 1966.</para>
</section>
<section id="s3">
<head>MUSLIM HISTORIOGRAPHY</head>
<para id="p23"><emph type="i">The development of historical writing among the Moslems in Spain.</emph> S. Goldman. Oxford D.Phil. 1936.</para>
    <para id="p24"><emph type="i">An introduction to the <emph type="i">Kit&acirc;b al-Muhabbar</emph> of Muhammad ibn H&#x0323;ab&icirc;b, together with an edition of its first twenty folios, with indices and explanatory notes.</emph> Ilse Lichtenst&auml;dter. Oxford D.Phil. 1937.</para>
<para id="p25"><emph type="i">A study of Ab&umacr; Zakar&imacr;y&amacr;'s work together with the edition of the second volume of T&amacr;r&imacr;kh Al-Mausil.</emph> A.H.M. Habiba. Cambridge Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<para id="p26"><emph type="i">Fitnat al Qayrawan: a study of traditional Arabic historiography.</emph> M. Brett. London Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p27"><emph type="i">Sources of the contemporary history of Miskawaih (340&ndash;369 A.H.).</emph> M.S. Khan. Oxford D.Phil. 1958.</para>
    <para id="p28"><emph type="i">The S&imacr;ra of al-Mu'ayyad fi'd-D&imacr;n ash&#x0331;-Sh&#x0331;&imacr;r&amacr;zi.</emph> A.H. Al-Hamdani. London Ph.D. 1950.</para>
<para id="p29"><emph type="i">The composition of Ibn al-Athir's History of the Crusades, A.H. 490&ndash;516 = A.D. 1097&ndash;1122.</emph> C.P. Worlsey. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1954.</para>
<para id="p30"><emph type="i">A critical edition of M&uuml;nejjim B&amacr;shi's history of the Salj&umacr;qids of Iran (Great Salj&umacr;qs), with translation and introduction.</emph> S.A. Hasan. Cambridge Ph.D. 1956.</para>
<para id="p31"><emph type="i">Studies on the work of Ibn al-Azraq al-F&amacr;riq&imacr; together with an edition of the section on the Marw&amacr;nidi dynasty.</emph> B.A. el L. Awad. Cambridge Ph.D. 1955.</para>
<para id="p32"><emph type="i">Ideas of history in the historical literature of early medieval India.</emph> V.S. Pathak. London Ph.D. 1962.</para>
<para id="p33"><emph type="i">The Muslim historians of India, from 1205 to 1259.</emph> W.H. Andalib-i-Shadani. London Ph.D. 1934.</para>
<para id="p34"><emph type="i">Studies on the works of Abu Shama, 599&ndash;665 A.H. (1203&ndash;67).</emph> M.H.M. Ahmad. London Ph.D. 1951.</para>
<para id="p35"><emph type="i">A study and translation of the first book of the first volume of the compendium of histories by Ra&scaron;id al-din Fadl Allah, concerning the Turkish and Mongol tribes.</emph> D.G. Maitland Muller. London Ph.D. 1957.</para>
<para id="p36"><emph type="i">The treatment of history by medieval Indian Muslim historians, with special reference to Barni, Afif, Amir Khusrau, Isami and Yahya bin Ahmad Sihrindi.</emph> P. Hardy. London Ph.D. 1953.</para>
<para id="p37"><emph type="i">The <emph type="i">Fatawa-i-Jahandari</emph> of Zia-ud-din Barni: translation, with introduction and notes.</emph> Afsar Afzaluddin. London Ph.D. 1956.</para>
<para id="p38"><emph type="i">Historical studies on the <emph type="i">Inb&amacr;' Al-Ghumr</emph> of Ibn Hajar.</emph> H. Habashi. London Ph.D. 1955.</para>
<para id="p39"><emph type="i">A survey of the early Ottoman histories, with studies on their textual problems and their sources.</emph> V.L. M&eacute;nage. London Ph.D. 1961.</para>
<para id="p40"><emph type="i">Studies on Maqrizi.</emph> A.A.R. Elghawabi. Cambridge Ph.D. 1953.</para>
<para id="p41"><emph type="i">The Histories of Ottoman in Egypt attributed to Abu al-Surur al-Bakri.</emph> F.M. El-Mawi. St. Andrews Ph.D. 1970.</para>
</section>
<section id="s4">
<head>MEDIEVAL EUROPEAN HISTORIOGRAPHY INCLUDING CHRONICLES</head>
<para id="p42"><emph type="i">A commentary on the so-called <emph type="i">Opus historicum</emph> of Hilary of Poitiers.</emph> J. Fleming. Durham Ph.D. 1952.</para>
<page start="003"/>
<para id="p43"><emph type="i">A study of the Parker Chronicle (449&ndash;597 A.D.) in the light of more recent archaeological, place-name and topographical evidence.</emph> G.J. Copley. London Ph.D. 1947.</para>
<para id="p44"><emph type="i">An edition of the Parker Chronicle.</emph> J.B. Wynn. Wales M.A. 1951.</para>
<para id="p45"><emph type="i">Paul the Deacon and the 'Historia Langobardorum'.</emph> Mabel H. Blyton. London M.A. 1935.</para>
<para id="p46"><emph type="i">The history of the Albanians (Aluank') attributed to Movs&emacr;s Kalankatua&ccedil;i.</emph> C.J.F. Dowsett. Cambridge Ph.D. 1953/4.</para>
<para id="p47"><emph type="i">The chronicle of Aethelweard: with especial reference to the form of Anglo-Saxon Chronicle used by him.</emph> E.E. Barker. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1969.</para>
<para id="p48"><emph type="i">A critical study of the sources of the Annals of Winch-combe: Faustina B. 1 ff.21&ndash;9.</emph> E. John. Manchester M.A. 1950.</para>
<para id="p49"><emph type="i">An edition of annals 1070 to 1154 of the Peterborough Chronicle, with introduction, grammar, commentary and glossary.</emph> Cecily Clark. Oxford B.Litt. 1952.</para>
<para id="p50"><emph type="i">A critical edition of the <emph type="i">Historia Francorum</emph> of Raymond of Aguilers.</emph> J. France. Nottingham Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p51"><emph type="i">The unpublished Annals of Merton and Southwark compared.</emph> M. Tyson. Manchester M.A. 1923.</para>
<para id="p52"><emph type="i">The relationship and chronology of the historical manuscripts of Matthew Paris.</emph> R. Vaughan. Cambridge Ph.D. 1954.</para>
<para id="p53"><emph type="i">The Old French continuations of the Chronicle of William archbishop of Tyre, to 1232.</emph> Mrs. Margaret R. Morgan. Oxford D.Phil. 1970.</para>
<para id="p54"><emph type="i">An examination of the historical basis of the 'Roman d'Eustache le Moine'.</emph> Gwendolen A. Thorn. Leeds M.A. 1949.</para>
<para id="p55"><emph type="i">Rhymed chronicles, with special reference to Philippe Mousket (13th century).</emph> Juliette W. Jaques. London M.A. 1950.</para>
<para id="p56"><emph type="i">The <emph type="i">French Chronicle</emph> by the Anonyme de B&eacute;thune: a critical edition.</emph> Juliette W. Jaques. London Ph.D. 1955.</para>
<para id="p57"><emph type="i">An edition of part of the chronicle attributed to Robert of Gloucester, with a study of the original language of the poem.</emph> Anne M. Hudson. Oxford D.Phil. 1964.</para>
<para id="p58"><emph type="i">French historiography in the later middle ages, with special reference to the 'Grandes Chroniques de France'.</emph> Mrs. Sarah M. Farley. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p59"><emph type="i">A critical edition of the Bury St. Edmunds Chronicle in Arundel MS. 30 (College of Arms).</emph> Mrs. Antonia Gransden. London Ph.D. 1957.</para>
<para id="p60"><emph type="i">The Anglo-Norman Chronicle of Nicolas Trivet.</emph> A. Rutherford. London Ph.D. 1932.</para>
<para id="p61"><emph type="i">Nicholas Trevet: a study of his life and works, with special reference to his Anglo-Norman Chronicle.</emph> Ruth J. Dean. Oxford D.Phil. 1938.</para>
<para id="p62"><emph type="i">The chronicler of Pedro the Cruel: Pedro Lopez de Ayala.</emph> Lilias Taylor. Glasgow Ph.D. 1931.</para>
<para id="p63"><emph type="i">A contribution to the study of the life, personality and works of Pedro Lopez de Ayala, 1332&ndash;1407.</emph> E.W. Lloyd. London Ph.D. 1930.</para>
<para id="p64"><emph type="i">The chronicle of John Strecche for the reign of Henry V.</emph> F. Taylor. Manchester M.A. 1931.</para>
<para id="p65"><emph type="i">The 'Gesta Henrici Quinti' of Thomas Elmham, prior of Lenton (a re-edition with introduction and notes).</emph> F. Taylor. Manchester Ph.D. 1938.</para>
<para id="p66"><emph type="i">La Chronique de Mathieu d'Escouchy: an edition of an inedited manuscript of the chronicle of Mathieu d'Escouchy.</emph> G. J. Halligan. Cambridge M.Litt. 1963.</para>
<para id="p67"><emph type="i">A study of the unpublished 15th-century French prose chronicle: <emph type="i">Les anchiennes cronicques de Pise</emph>.</emph> I.M.P. Raeside. London Ph.D. 1955.</para>
<para id="p68"><emph type="i">The influence of Italian humanism on the historiography of Castile and Aragon during the 15th century.</emph> R.B. Tate. Belfast Ph.D. 1955.</para>
<page start="004"/>
<para id="p69"><emph type="i">Late 15th-century French historiography, as exemplified in the <emph type="i">Compendium</emph> of Robert Gaguin and the <emph type="i">De Rebus Gestis</emph> of Paulus Aemilius.</emph> Katharine L. Davies. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1954.</para>
</section>
<section id="s5">
<head>MODERN HISTORIOGRAPHY</head>
<para id="p70"><emph type="i">The <emph type="i">M&eacute;moires</emph> of Guillaume and Martin du Bellay - a contribution to the history of French historiography in the 16th century.</emph> J.D. Duncannon. London M.A. 1938.</para>
<para id="p71"><emph type="i">A critical edition of <emph type="i">Le Lettere Storiche</emph> of Luigi da Porto.</emph> C.H. Clough. Oxford D.Phil. 1961.</para>
<para id="p72"><emph type="i">A study of 17th-century historiographical literature relating to Wales.</emph> D. Watkins. Wales M.A. 1955.</para>
<para id="p73"><emph type="i">English influences on French historians during the 17th century.</emph> Ena A.E. Mitchell. Cambridge M.Litt. 1931/2.</para>
<para id="p74"><emph type="i">Early modern historiography, as illustrated by the work of G.J. Vossius, 1577&ndash;1649.</emph> J.N. Wickenden. Cambridge Ph.D. 1964.</para>
<para id="p75"><emph type="i">A critical commentary on the development of the art of writing history in English between 1603 and 1642.</emph> I.G. Jones. Wales M.A. 1950.</para>
<para id="p76"><emph type="i">English constitutional history and political ideas from the death of Oliver Cromwell to the fall of Clarendon.</emph> H.N. Mukherjee. Oxford B.Litt. 1933.</para>
<para id="p77"><emph type="i">Clarendon as a historian.</emph> D.D. Richards. Wales M.A. 1913.</para>
<para id="p78"><emph type="i">The value of Clarendon as a historian.</emph> N.M. Smith. Wales M.A. 1906.</para>
<para id="p79"><emph type="i">Henry de Boulainvilliers: historian and philosopher.</emph> J. Grace. Cambridge Ph.D. 1931/2.</para>
<para id="p80"><emph type="i">English historical writing on the English Reformation, 1680-1730.</emph> E. Jones. Cambridge Ph.D. 1959.</para>
<para id="p81"><emph type="i">Swift's views on history, and his relation to contemporary historians.</emph> M. Jones. Oxford B.Litt. 1954.</para>
<para id="p82"><emph type="i">Swift's works, 1710&ndash;15 and contemporary ideas of history and historiography.</emph> C.J. Parsons. London Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p83"><emph type="i">Paul Rapin de Thoyras and the English historiography of his time, 1700&ndash;30.</emph> D.W.L. Earl. Cambridge M.Litt. 1961.</para>
<para id="p84"><emph type="i">Voltaire's philosophy of history and historical method.</emph> J.H. Brumfitt. Oxford D.Phil. 1953.</para>
<para id="p85"><emph type="i">A study of Voltaire's <emph type="i">Histoire de Charles XII</emph>, with special reference to the author's sources and conception of history.</emph> Janina W. Felix. London Ph.D. 1961.</para>
<para id="p86"><emph type="i">A detailed study of Voltaire's <emph type="i">Histoire de Russie sous Pierre le Grand</emph>.</emph> Catherine M. Oakley. Exeter M.A. 1959.</para>
<para id="p87"><emph type="i">The historical writings of William Robertson D.D., 1721&ndash;93.</emph> H.G. Earnshaw. Bristol M.A. 1951.</para>
<para id="p88"><emph type="i">The attitude of Edward Gibbon towards ecclesiastical history.</emph> E.K. Roberts. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1954.</para>
<para id="p89"><emph type="i">Herder's contribution to the romantic philosophy of history, with special reference to the theological implications.</emph> G.W. Bromiley. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1943.</para>
<para id="p90"><emph type="i">British historical writing from Alexander Dow to Mountstuart Elphinstone on Muslim India.</emph> J.S. Grewal. London Ph.D. 1963.</para>
<para id="p91"><emph type="i">The English historians and the medieval church.</emph> R.H. Kiernan. Birmingham M.A. 1928/9.</para>
<para id="p92"><emph type="i">Prosper de Barante: the intellectual biography of a historian.</emph> S. Bann. Cambridge Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p93"><emph type="i">The English historiography of the French Revolution in the 19th century.</emph> Hedva Ben-Israel. Cambridge Ph.D. 1955.</para>
<para id="p94"><emph type="i">A study of John Lingard's historical work, with special reference to his treatment of the reign of Elizabeth I.</emph> E. Jones. Wales M.A. 1956.</para>
<para id="p95"><emph type="i">Sir Walter Scott and history.</emph> J. Anderson. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<page start="005"/>
<para id="p96"><emph type="i">Intellectual origins of Scott's view of history in the Waverley Novels.</emph> P.D. Garside. Cambridge Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p97"><emph type="i">German historiography and the evolution of German political ideas in the 19th century.</emph> J.W. Jennings. London Ph.D. 1949.</para>
<para id="p98"><emph type="i">The characteristics of British policy and imperial history as conceived by the German historians of the 19th century, 1848&ndash;1902.</emph> H.D. Schmidt. Oxford B.Litt. 1953.</para>
<para id="p99"><emph type="i">Chateaubriand as an historian.</emph> J.M. Sainsbury. Birmingham M.A. 1966.</para>
<para id="p100"><emph type="i">Guizot as a historian of England.</emph> G.N. Eeles. Oxford B.Litt. 1926.</para>
<para id="p101"><emph type="i">The 18th century seen by Taine and Renan.</emph> I.H. Birchall. Oxford B.Litt. 1965.</para>
<para id="p102"><emph type="i">La philosophie de l'histoire d'Hippolyte Taine.</emph> C.H. Evans. Wales M.A. 1961.</para>
<para id="p103"><emph type="i">The idea of conscience in the work of Lord Acton.</emph> J.S. Nurser. Cambridge Ph.D. 1958.</para>
<para id="p104"><emph type="i">Indian historical writing in English, 1870&ndash;1920, with special reference to the influence of nationalism.</emph> J.H. Voigt. Oxford D.Phil. 1968.</para>
<para id="p105"><emph type="i">The historians of the Action Fran&ccedil;aise, 1900&ndash;45.</emph> S. Wilson. Cambridge Ph.D. 1966.</para>
</section>
</section>
</report>
