<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="154854" pubid="1512" publish="true">
<title>Medieval England</title>
<subtitle></subtitle>
<section id="s1">
<head>MEDIEVAL ENGLAND</head>
<section id="s2">
<head>POLITICAL HISTORY</head>
<section id="s3">
<head>General</head>
<para id="p1"><emph type="i">Offa of Mercia in history and tradition.</emph> A.E. Smith. Leeds M.A. 1942.</para>
<para id="p2"><emph type="i">The life and times of Egbert, king of Wessex, 809&ndash;39.</emph> A. Jean Thorogood. Reading M.A. 1931.</para>
<para id="p3"><emph type="i">The Norse occupation of the Lake District.</emph> Marjorie J. Anderton. London M.A. 1953.</para>
<para id="p4"><emph type="i">The sokemen of the southern Danelaw in the 11th century.</emph> Barbara Dodwell. London M.A. 1936.</para>
<para id="p5"><emph type="i">The harrying of the North by William the Conqueror.</emph> Christine Cordingley. Leeds M.A. 1935.</para>
<para id="p6"><emph type="i">Earl Waltheof of Northumbria in history and tradition.</emph> F.S. Scott. Cambridge M.Litt. 1951.</para>
<para id="p7"><emph type="i">Richard Coeur de Lion before his accession to the throne.</emph> Hilda F.M. Prescott. Manchester M.A. 1921.</para>
<para id="p8"><emph type="i">William de Braose.</emph> M. Jones. Wales M.A. 1901.</para>
<para id="p9"><emph type="i">Some aspects of the history of England north of Trent and Ribble in Stephen's reign.</emph> H.A. Cronne. Belfast M.A. 1931.</para>
<para id="p10"><emph type="i">The 'northern' barons under John.</emph> J.C. Holt. Oxford D.Phil. 1952.</para>
<para id="p11"><emph type="i">Aliens in British politics during the reign of King John and the minority of King Henry III, 1204&ndash;24.</emph> M.J. Knight. Nottingham M.A. 1959.</para>
<para id="p12"><emph type="i">William the Marshal.</emph> Mary Salmon. Wales M.A. 1909.</para>
<para id="p13"><emph type="i">The relations between Crown and baronage in England between 1216 and 1232, with especial reference to the administration of Hubert de Burgh.</emph> Gladys Malbon. London M.A. (Ext.) 1940.</para>
<para id="p14"><emph type="i">Hubert de Burgh.</emph> S.H.F. Johnston. Oxford B.Litt. 1933.</para>
<para id="p15"><emph type="i">Hubert de Burgh.</emph> C. Ellis. Wales M.A. 1912.</para>
<para id="p16"><emph type="i">Richard Marshal and the rising of 1233&ndash;4.</emph> R.F. Walker. Wales M.A. 1950.</para>
<para id="p17"><emph type="i">The early years of Richard, earl of Cornwall.</emph> Lillian W. Kelley. Liverpool M.A. 1913.</para>
<para id="p18"><emph type="i">Richard of Cornwall, king of the Romans (1257&ndash;72).</emph> F.R. Lewis. Wales M.A. 1933/4.</para>
<para id="p19"><emph type="i">Edmund, earl of Cornwall, and his place in history.</emph> Laura M. Midgley. Manchester M.A. 1930.</para>
<para id="p20"><emph type="i">Peter of Rievaux.</emph> Mary Broxap. Manchester M.A. 1925.</para>
<para id="p21"><emph type="i">The Barons' Wars, 1258&ndash;67.</emph> R.F. Treharne. Manchester M.A. 1923.</para>
<para id="p22"><emph type="i">The preliminaries of the Barons' War, 1258&ndash;63.</emph> R.F. Treharne. Manchester Ph.D. 1925.</para>
<page start="033"/>
<para id="p23"><emph type="i">The personal disputes between Henry III and Simon and Eleanor de Montfort.</emph> Margaret M. Wade. Oxford B.Litt. 1939.</para>
<para id="p24"><emph type="i">Simon de Montford and his times.</emph> D.T. Hughes. Wales M.A. 1910.</para>
<para id="p25"><emph type="i">Baronial reform and rebellion in the time of Simon de Montfort.</emph> E.F. Jacob. Oxford D.Phil. 1923.</para>
<para id="p26"><emph type="i">The disinherited, 1265&ndash;80: a political and social study of the supporters of Simon de Montfort and the resettlement after the Barons' War.</emph> C.H. Knowles. Wales Ph.D. 1959.</para>
<para id="p27"><emph type="i">A biographical sketch of Robert Burnell, with materials for his life.</emph> Ursula W. Hughes. Oxford B.Litt. 1936.</para>
<para id="p28"><emph type="i">The battles of King Edward I.</emph> J.R. Richards. Wales M.A. 1914.</para>
<para id="p29"><emph type="i">Edward I as a foreign statesman.</emph> H. Instein. Oxford B.Litt. 1933.</para>
<para id="p30"><emph type="i">The enquiry into the complaints against the ministers of Eleanor of Castile, 1291&ndash;2: its administrative and legal significance.</emph> Muriel E. Fenwick. London M.A. 1931.</para>
<para id="p31"><emph type="i">The constitutional crisis in the closing years of the reign of Edward I.</emph> R.D. Morley. Wales M.A. 1970.</para>
<para id="p32"><emph type="i">Some financial and political aspects of the constitutional crisis of 1297.</emph> Deirdre Beddoe. Wales Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p33"><emph type="i">The lords ordainers and their work: a sketch of baronial government.</emph> S. Childs. London M.A. 1910.</para>
<para id="p34"><emph type="i">The career of Peter of Gavaston and his place in history.</emph> Aileen A. Taylor. London M.A. 1938.</para>
<para id="p35"><emph type="i">A preliminary study of the chronicles and instruments for a constitutional history of the years 1296&ndash;1301 in England.</emph> H. Rothwell. Cambridge Ph.D. 1929/30.</para>
<para id="p36"><emph type="i">The conduct of English diplomacy in the 14th century.</emph> G.P. Cuttino. Oxford D.Phil. 1938.</para>
<para id="p37"><emph type="i">William of Ockham's attitude to political authority and its relation to the history of his time.</emph> J.B. Morrall. Oxford B.Litt. 1949.</para>
<para id="p38"><emph type="i">Thomas of Lancaster, 1307&ndash;22.</emph> J.R.L. Maddicott. Oxford D.Phil. 1968.</para>
<para id="p39"><emph type="i">Constitutional and diplomatic aspects of the ordinances of 1311.</emph> Mabel H. Mills. London M.A. 1912.</para>
<para id="p40"><emph type="i">The career of Aymer de Valence, earl of Pembroke, with special reference to the period from 1312 to 1324.</emph> J.R.S. Phillips. London Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p41"><emph type="i">The government of Mortimer and Queen Isabella, 1327&ndash;30.</emph> S.J.T. Gibson. Manchester M.A. 1921.</para>
<para id="p42"><emph type="i">Henry of Grosmont, 1st duke of Lancaster, 1310&ndash;61.</emph> K.A. Fowler. Leeds Ph.D. 1962.</para>
<para id="p43"><emph type="i">A study of social and constitutional tendencies in the early years of Edward III, as illustrated more especially by the events connected with the ministerial inquiries of 1340 and the following years.</emph> Dorothy Hughes. London M.A. 1913.</para>
<para id="p44"><emph type="i">Uthred of Boldon: a study in 14th-century political theory.</emph> C.H. Thompson. Manchester Ph.D. 1936.</para>
<para id="p45"><emph type="i">The career of Thomas Arundel until his exile in 1397.</emph> Mrs. Margaret E. Aston. Oxford D.Phil. 1962.</para>
<para id="p46"><emph type="i">The baronial opposition to Richard II, 1377&ndash;89.</emph> J.A. Tuck. Cambridge Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p47"><emph type="i">The career of Thomas, duke of Gloucester.</emph> H.G. Wright. London M.A. 1931.</para>
<para id="p48"><emph type="i">Thomas of Woodstock, 1355&ndash;97.</emph> K. Wilson. Sheffield M.A. 1953.</para>
<para id="p49"><emph type="i">Civic factions in London and their relation to political parties, 1376&ndash;99.</emph> Ruth Bird. London M.A. 1922.</para>
<para id="p50"><emph type="i">Persons and politics in the early years of the reign of Richard II.</emph> N.B. Lewis. Manchester Ph.D. 1928.</para>
<para id="p51"><emph type="i">The economic and political preliminaries of the crusade of Henry Despenser, bishop of Norwich, in 1383.</emph> A.P.R. Coulborn. London Ph.D. 1931.</para>
<page start="034"/>
<para id="p52"><emph type="i">Richard the Second's <emph type="i">coup d'&eacute;tat</emph> of 1397.</emph> Lilian B. Meyer. London M.A. 1908.</para>
<para id="p53"><emph type="i">Royal political propaganda in England, 1399&ndash;1509.</emph> J.W. McKenna. Cambridge Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<para id="p54"><emph type="i">Studies in constitutional ideas in England during the 15th century.</emph> S.B. Chrimes. Cambridge Ph.D. 1933.</para>
<para id="p55"><emph type="i">The territorial settlement of the house of Lancaster, 1399&ndash;1401.</emph> S. Smith. Manchester M.A. 1940.</para>
<para id="p56"><emph type="i">The Crown lands and the parliamentary acts of resumption, 1399&ndash;1495.</emph> B.P. Wolffe. Oxford D.Phil. 1954.</para>
<para id="p57"><emph type="i">The alienation and resumption of Crown lands and revenues from 1399 to the outbreak of the Wars of the Roses.</emph> B.P. Wolffe. Oxford B.Litt. 1950.</para>
<para id="p58"><emph type="i">Rebellion and disaffection in the north of England, 1403&ndash;8.</emph> P. McNiven. Manchester M.A. 1967.</para>
<para id="p59"><emph type="i">The suppression of Sir John Oldcastle's rebellion in 1414.</emph> Hilda Lofthouse. Manchester M.A. 1934.</para>
<para id="p60"><emph type="i">John, 1st duke of Bedford, his work and policy in England, 1389&ndash;1435.</emph> S.B. Chrimes. London M.A. 1929.</para>
<para id="p61"><emph type="i">English diplomacy in the reign of Henry VI, 1422&ndash;61.</emph> J.T. Ferguson. Oxford D.Phil. 1967.</para>
<para id="p62"><emph type="i">Humphrey Stafford, 1st duke of Buckingham: an estimate of the significance of his political activities.</emph> H. Cole. London M.A. 1945.</para>
<para id="p63"><emph type="i">London and the Wars of the Roses, 1445&ndash;61.</emph> Margaret I. Peake. London M.A. 1925.</para>
<para id="p64"><emph type="i">John Tiptoft, earl of Worcester.</emph> Rosamund J. Mitchell. Oxford B.Litt. 1929.</para>
<para id="p65"><emph type="i">The Herberts of Raglan as supporters of the house of York in the second half of the 15th century.</emph> D.H. Thomas. Wales M.A. 1968.</para>
</section>
<section id="s4">
<head>Administration and Royal Household</head>
<para id="p66"><emph type="i">The drafting of royal charters in the reign of King Edgar.</emph> R.E.A. Poole. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1969.</para>
<para id="p67"><emph type="i">Royal provision for clerks to 1272.</emph> Cecily Davies. Liverpool M.A. 1952.</para>
<para id="p68"><emph type="i">The office of justiciar in Anglo-Norman England.</emph> F.J. West. Leeds Ph.D. 1951.</para>
<para id="p69"><emph type="i">The early history of the English Chapel Royal, <emph type="i">c</emph>.1066&ndash;1327.</emph> I.D. Bent. Cambridge Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p70"><emph type="i">The composition and work of the royal council in the reign of Henry II, 1154&ndash;89.</emph> Audrey D. Perkyns. London M.A. 1951.</para>
<para id="p71"><emph type="i">The court and household of King Henry II (1154&ndash;89).</emph> J.E. Lally. Liverpool Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p72"><emph type="i">The royal family in the reign of Henry II.</emph> R.J. Smith. Nottingham M.A. 1961.</para>
<para id="p73"><emph type="i">The English sheriffs in the reign of King John.</emph> B.E. Harris. Nottingham M.A. 1961.</para>
<para id="p74"><emph type="i">A study, mainly from royal wardrobe accounts, of the nature and organisation of the king's messenger service from the reign of John to that of Edward III, inclusive.</emph> Mary C. Hill. London M.A. 1939.</para>
<para id="p75"><emph type="i">English administrative families in the 12th and 13th centuries with special reference to the Cornhill family.</emph> W.R. Powell. Oxford B.Litt. 1952.</para>
<para id="p76"><emph type="i">The justiciarship in England, 1204&ndash;32.</emph> F.J. West. Cambridge Ph.D. 1956.</para>
<para id="p77"><emph type="i">The position and duties of the king's almoner, 1255&ndash;1327.</emph> Marguerite E. Lack. London M.A. 1949.</para>
<para id="p78"><emph type="i">The king's government in Yorkshire, 1258&ndash;1348.</emph> Helen M. Jewell. Leeds Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p79"><emph type="i">The clerical dynasties from Howdenshire, Lindsey and Nottinghamshire in the royal administration 1280&ndash;1340.</emph> J.L. Grassi. Oxford D.Phil. 1960.</para>
<para id="p80"><emph type="i">The local administration of the sheriff in the 13th century.</emph> Margaret A. Hennings. London M.A. 1916.</para>
<page start="035"/>
<para id="p81"><emph type="i">The sheriffs and shrievalty of Lancaster in the 14th century.</emph> A.D. King. Sheffield M.A. 1953.</para>
<para id="p82"><emph type="i">The sheriffs of Hampshire.</emph> P. White. London M.A. (Ext.) 1954.</para>
<para id="p83"><emph type="i">The sheriffs and sheriffdoms under Edward II.</emph> J. Wood. Manchester M.A. 1923.</para>
<para id="p84"><emph type="i">The financing and organisation of the household of the queens of England during the first part of the 14th century.</emph> Alice M. Best. London M.A. 1916.</para>
<para id="p85"><emph type="i">The chancery in the reign of Edward III.</emph> B. Wilkinson. Manchester M.A. 1921.</para>
<para id="p86"><emph type="i">The English chancery under Edward III and Richard II.</emph> B. Wilkinson. Manchester Ph.D. 1926.</para>
<para id="p87"><emph type="i">The Exchequer Chamber, being 'the assembly of all the judges of England'.</emph> Mary Hemmant. London Ph.D. 1929.</para>
<para id="p88"><emph type="i">The king's secretary and the signet office in the 15th century.</emph> Annette J. Otway-Ruthven. Cambridge Ph.D. 1937.</para>
<para id="p89"><emph type="i">The privy seal in the early 15th century.</emph> A.L. Brown. Oxford D.Phil. 1955.</para>
<para id="p90"><emph type="i">The great council in the 15th century.</emph> T.F.T. Plucknett. London M.A. 1917.</para>
<para id="p91"><emph type="i">The council under Henry IV.</emph> Phyllis G. Harvey. Oxford B.Litt. 1932.</para>
<para id="p92"><emph type="i">The royal household of Henry IV.</emph> A. Rogers. Nottingham Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p93"><emph type="i">Some aspects of the king's household in the reign of Henry V, 1413&ndash;22.</emph> Eileen H. de L. Fagan. London M.A. 1935.</para>
<para id="p94"><emph type="i">The king's council in England during the early years of the minority of Henry VI.</emph> J. Kirkland. Manchester M.A. 1940.</para>
<para id="p95"><emph type="i">The activities of household officials in the 15th century, as illustrated by the Hatteclyff family.</emph> G.E. Burtt. London M.A. 1955.</para>
<para id="p96"><emph type="i">The finance of the royal household, 1437&ndash;60.</emph> G.L. Harriss. Oxford D.Phil. 1953.</para>
<para id="p97"><emph type="i">The relations between the Crown and the boroughs in the mid 15th century.</emph> A.P.M. Wright. Oxford D.Phil. 1966.</para>
<para id="p98"><emph type="i">The administration of the Yorkist kings.</emph> J.R. Lander. Cambridge M.Litt. 1950.</para>
<para id="p99"><emph type="i">The household ordinances of Edward IV.</emph> A.R. Myers. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1956.</para>
<para id="p100"><emph type="i">The later medieval sheriff and the royal household (<emph type="i">c</emph>. 1437&ndash;1547).</emph> R.M. Jeffs. Oxford D.Phil. 1961.</para>
</section>
<section id="s5">
<head>Law</head>
<para id="p101"><emph type="i">In pursuit of the merchant debtor and bankrupt: 1066&ndash;1732.</emph> F.J.J. Cadwallader. London Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<para id="p102"><emph type="i">A comparative study of the language of the Anglo-Norman bills of eyre and similar documents of the Channel Isles, Gloucestershire, London and a northern area (Lancashire).</emph> C.J.H. Topping. London Ph.D. 1934.</para>
<para id="p103"><emph type="i">The court leet of Southampton and leet jurisdiction in general.</emph> F.J.C. Hearnshaw. London M.A. 1908.</para>
<para id="p104"><emph type="i">The writ of habeas corpus.</emph> H.P. Letcher. London LL.D. (Ext.) 1933.</para>
<para id="p105"><emph type="i">Some aspects of local jurisdiction in the 12th and 13th centuries, with special reference to private and county courts.</emph> Lorna E.M. Walker. London M.A. 1958.</para>
<para id="p106"><emph type="i">A study of the controversy as to the application of Roman canon law in England during the middle ages.</emph> B. Allen. Oxford B.Litt. 1923.</para>
<para id="p107"><emph type="i">Legal aspects of villeinage between Glanvill and Bracton.</emph> P.R. Hyams. Oxford D.Phil. 1968.</para>
<para id="p108"><emph type="i">The medieval coroner, 1194&ndash;1487, with special reference to the county of Sussex.</emph> R.F. Hunnisett. Oxford D.Phil. 1956.</para>
<para id="p109"><emph type="i">The early history of <emph type="i">placita coram rege</emph>.</emph> M. Tyson. Manchester Ph.D. 1927.</para>
<page start="036"/>
<para id="p110"><emph type="i">Royal wardship in the reign of King John, with reference to chapters 3&ndash;6 of Magna Carta.</emph> Mary Renshaw. Manchester M.A. 1947.</para>
<para id="p111"><emph type="i">The problem relating to the maintenance of law and order in 13th-century England, with particular reference to the 'custos pacis'.</emph> H. Ainsley. Wales Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p112"><emph type="i">The roll and writ file of the Berkshire eyre of 1248.</emph> M.T. Clanchy. Reading Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p113"><emph type="i">The Shropshire eyre roll of 1256.</emph> A. Harding. Oxford B.Litt. 1957.</para>
<para id="p114"><emph type="i">Judicial investigations under the dictum de Kenilworth.</emph> Margery L. Hoyle. Manchester Ph.D. 1934.</para>
<para id="p115"><emph type="i">The judicial proceedings under the dictum of Kenilworth in west Berkshire.</emph> Ellen Roberts. Manchester M.A. 1927.</para>
<para id="p116"><emph type="i">The judicial proceedings under the dictum of Kenilworth in east Berkshire.</emph> Alys L. Gregory. Manchester M.A. 1927.</para>
<para id="p117"><emph type="i">Judicial proceedings under the dictum of Kenilworth in north Buckinghamshire.</emph> J. Lunn. Manchester M.A. 1928.</para>
<para id="p118"><emph type="i">Judicial proceedings under the dictum of Kenilworth in south Buckinghamshire.</emph> Margery L. Hoyle. Manchester M.A. 1928.</para>
<para id="p119"><emph type="i">Judicial investigations under the dictum of Kenilworth (Cambridgeshire).</emph> C.C. Bayley. Manchester M.A. 1929.</para>
<para id="p120"><emph type="i">Judicial proceedings under the dictum of Kenilworth, Cambridgeshire.</emph> Assize Roll 83: membranes 9&ndash;16. Sarah Cohen. Manchester M.A. 1929.</para>
<para id="p121"><emph type="i">Judicial proceedings in Cambridgeshire under the dictum of Kenilworth.</emph> Assize Roll 83: membranes 17&ndash;24d. Kathleen H. Holden. Manchester M.A. 1929.</para>
<para id="p122"><emph type="i">Judicial proceedings under the dictum of Kenilworth in Essex.</emph> H. Roberts. Manchester M.A. 1928.</para>
<para id="p123"><emph type="i">Judicial investigations under the dictum of Kenilworth (Northamptonshire).</emph> Mary M. Rothwell. Manchester M.A. 1929.</para>
<para id="p124"><emph type="i">Judicial investigations under the dictum of Kenilworth (Northamptonshire).</emph> E.H. Graham. Manchester M.A. 1930.</para>
<para id="p125"><emph type="i">Judicial investigations under the dictum of Kenilworth: Northamptonshire.</emph> T.W. Byrne. Manchester M.A. 1932.</para>
<para id="p126"><emph type="i">Judicial proceedings under the dictum of Kenilworth in Surrey.</emph> Lucy M. Round. Manchester M.A. 1928.</para>
<para id="p127"><emph type="i">The judicial proceedings under the dictum of Kenilworth in Sussex, Surrey and Kent.</emph> Annie Buckley. Manchester M.A. 1927.</para>
<para id="p128"><emph type="i">The doctrine of judicial precedent: its history and importance as a source of law.</emph> T.E. Lewis. Cambridge Ph.D. 1927/8.</para>
<para id="p129"><emph type="i">Chester pentice and portmote courts under Edward I.</emph> A. Hopkins. Liverpool M.A. 1947.</para>
<para id="p130"><emph type="i"><emph type="i">Quo warranto</emph> proceedings in the reign of Edward I, 1278&ndash;94.</emph> D.W. Sutherland. Oxford D.Phil. 1956.</para>
<para id="p131"><emph type="i">The <emph type="i">quo warranto</emph> proceedings for the county of Lancaster, 1292.</emph> A. Cantle. London M.A. 1935.</para>
<para id="p132"><emph type="i">Aspects of the development of the crime of high treason.</emph> J.K. Barratt. Manchester LL.M. 1956.</para>
<para id="p133"><emph type="i">The law of treason in England in the later middle ages.</emph> J.G. Bellamy. Nottingham Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p134"><emph type="i">P.R.O. Assize Roll 505, edited with an introduction on the war-time administration of Lincolnshire, 1294&ndash;8.</emph> W.S. Thomson. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1939.</para>
<para id="p135"><emph type="i">Sir William de Bereford, <emph type="i">c</emph>. 1250&ndash;1326.</emph> C.P. Cottis. Oxford B.Litt. 1958.</para>
<para id="p136"><emph type="i">A history of the order of the serjeants at law.</emph> J.H. Baker. London Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p137"><emph type="i">Sir Geoffrey Le Scrope, chief justice of the king's bench, 1324&ndash;38.</emph> E.L.G. Stones. Glasgow Ph.D. 1950.</para>
<para id="p138"><emph type="i">The origin and early history of the office of notary.</emph> J.C. Brown. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1934/5.</para>
<para id="p139"><emph type="i">Proceedings in the court of chancery up to <emph type="i">c</emph>.1460.</emph> Margaret E. Avery. London M.A. 1958.</para>
<page start="037"/>
<para id="p140"><emph type="i">The working of the court of king's bench in the 15th century.</emph> Marjorie Blatcher. London Ph.D. 1936.</para>
<para id="p141"><emph type="i">The system of gaol delivery as illustrated in the extant gaol delivery rolls of the 15th century.</emph> Marguerite E.H.J. Gollancz. London M.A. 1936.</para>
<para id="p142"><emph type="i">Commissions of <emph type="i">oyer</emph> and <emph type="i">terminer</emph> in 15th-century England.</emph> Judith B. Avrutick. London M.Phil. 1967.</para>
</section>
<section id="s6">
<head>Parliament</head>
<para id="p143"><emph type="i">A study of the knights of the shire returned to parliament by Bedfordshire during the middle ages.</emph> Margery A. Fletcher. London M.A. 1933.</para>
<para id="p144"><emph type="i">The parliamentary representation of the county of York from the earliest parliaments to 1601.</emph> A. Gooder. Leeds Ph.D. 1933.</para>
<para id="p145"><emph type="i">Aspects of the history of the Commons in the 14th century.</emph> Doris Rayner. Manchester Ph.D. 1934.</para>
<para id="p146"><emph type="i">The parliamentary representation of the county of Lancaster in the reign of Edward II.</emph> E. Fox. Manchester M.A. 1956.</para>
<para id="p147"><emph type="i">County representatives in the parliaments of Edward III.</emph> Kathleen L. Wood-Legh. Oxford B.Litt. 1929.</para>
<para id="p148"><emph type="i">Suggestions concerning the date and authorship of the <emph type="i">Modus Tenendi Parliamentum</emph>.</emph> Dorothy K. Hodnett. Bristol M.A. 1918.</para>
<para id="p149"><emph type="i">The opening address to parliament, with particular reference to the period 1377&ndash;1484.</emph> F. Williamson. Manchester M.A. 1935.</para>
<para id="p150"><emph type="i">The parliamentary representation of Northamptonshire and Rutland, 1377&ndash;1422.</emph> F.A. Clifford. Manchester M.A. 1967.</para>
<para id="p151"><emph type="i">The parliamentary representation of Warwickshire and Leicestershire, 1377&ndash;1422.</emph> Margaret G. Webb. Nottingham M.A. 1961.</para>
<para id="p152"><emph type="i">The parliamentary representation of Essex and Hertfordshire, 1377&ndash;1422.</emph> Anthea Wade. Manchester M.A. 1967.</para>
<para id="p153"><emph type="i">The parliamentary representation of Bedfordshire and Buckinghamshire, 1377&ndash;1422.</emph> A.E. Goodman. Oxford B.Litt. 1965.</para>
<para id="p154"><emph type="i">Parliamentary representation of Norfolk and Suffolk, 1377&ndash;1422.</emph> E.L.T. John. Nottingham M.A. 1959.</para>
<para id="p155"><emph type="i">The parliamentary representation of Surrey and Sussex, 1377&ndash;1422.</emph> A. Rogers. Nottingham M.A. 1957.</para>
<para id="p156"><emph type="i">The knights of the shire for Worcestershire, 1377&ndash;1421.</emph> J.T.P. Driver. Liverpool M.A. 1962.</para>
<para id="p157"><emph type="i">The parliamentary representation of Nottinghamshire, Derbyshire and Staffordshire during the reign of Richard II.</emph> J.G. Bellamy. Nottingham M.A. 1961.</para>
<para id="p158"><emph type="i">Parliament in the reign of Richard II.</emph> May McKisack. Oxford B.Litt. 1923/4.</para>
<para id="p159"><emph type="i">Parliamentary representation in Derbyshire and Nottinghamshire in the 15th century.</emph> Elizabeth A. Ayres. Nottingham M.A. 1956.</para>
<para id="p160"><emph type="i">Petitions in parliament under the Lancastrians from, or relating to, towns.</emph> Miriam A. Rose. London M.A. 1926.</para>
<para id="p161"><emph type="i">The knights of the shire for the county of Lancaster, 1399&ndash;1437.</emph> J.S. Roskell. Manchester M.A. 1934.</para>
<para id="p162"><emph type="i">The personnel of parliament under Henry IV.</emph> Janet W. Muir. London M.A. 1924.</para>
<para id="p163"><emph type="i">A study of the parliamentary burgesses during the first half of the 15th century, based on the returns of London, York, Norwich, Bristol and Southampton, between 1413 and 1437.</emph> J. Lawson. Manchester M.A. 1936.</para>
<para id="p164"><emph type="i">Some aspects of the history of the Commons in the reign of Henry V and the minority of Henry VI (with special reference to parliamentary petitions).</emph> A.R. Myers. Manchester M.A. 1935.</para>
<page start="038"/>
<para id="p165"><emph type="i">Burgess representation of the county of Wiltshire, 1422&ndash;37: a local study of the social composition of the burgess element in parliament.</emph> J.T. Driver. Oxford B.Litt. 1951.</para>
<para id="p166"><emph type="i">The personnel of the house of commons in 1422.</emph> J.S. Roskell. Oxford D.Phil. 1941.</para>
<para id="p167"><emph type="i">The parliament of 1449&ndash;50.</emph> R. Virgoe. London Ph.D. 1964.</para>
<para id="p168"><emph type="i">The burgesses in the parliaments of Yorkist England.</emph> K.N. Houghton. Liverpool M.A. 1961.</para>
</section>
</section>
<section id="s7">
<head>MILITARY AND NAVAL HISTORY</head>
<para id="p169"><emph type="i">The military and naval terms in the Norman and Anglo-Saxon chronicles of the 12th century.</emph> G.C. Johnson. Leeds Ph.D. 1949.</para>
<para id="p170"><emph type="i">Military organisation in England, 1124&ndash;1254.</emph> J.S. Critchley. Nottingham Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p171"><emph type="i">The place of English castles in the administrative and military organisation 1154&ndash;1216, with special reference to the reign of John.</emph> R.A. Brown. Oxford D.Phil. 1953.</para>
<para id="p172"><emph type="i">Aspects of military organisation in England under King John: the foreign mercenaries, their place in the royal armies and in feudal society, and their relationship to the household.</emph> W.J. Smith. Wales M.A. 1951.</para>
<para id="p173"><emph type="i">Ireland's participation in the military activities of English kings in the 13th and early 14th centuries.</emph> J.F. Lydon. London Ph.D. 1955.</para>
<para id="p174"><emph type="i">The Welsh soldier in England's armies of the 13th and 14th centuries.</emph> T.L. Williams. Wales M.A. 1915.</para>
<para id="p175"><emph type="i">The Anglo-Welsh wars, 1217&ndash;67: with special reference to English military developments.</emph> R.F. Walker. Oxford D.Phil. 1954.</para>
<para id="p176"><emph type="i">Edward I's wars and their financing, 1294&ndash;1307.</emph> M.C. Prestwich. Oxford D.Phil. 1968.</para>
<para id="p177"><emph type="i">The administration of the navy in the reign of Edward III.</emph> R.M. Hedley. Manchester M.A. 1922.</para>
<para id="p178"><emph type="i">The employment of naval forces in the reign of Edward III.</emph> A.T. Hall. Leeds M.A. 1956.</para>
<para id="p179"><emph type="i">Military system of Edward III.</emph> A.E. Prince. Oxford B.Litt. 1929.</para>
<para id="p180"><emph type="i">Berwick upon Tweed in the wars of Edward III.</emph> Beryl L. Atkinson. Leeds M.A. 1959.</para>
<para id="p181"><emph type="i">Measures taken by the king to fortify and munition the royal castles of England between the years 1327 and 1345.</emph> A.J. Campbell. Durham M.A. 1956.</para>
<para id="p182"><emph type="i">Naval policy at the end of the 14th century.</emph> T. Booth. Leeds M.A. 1932.</para>
<para id="p183"><emph type="i">Royal administration and the keeping of the seas 1422&ndash;85.</emph> C.F. Richmond. Oxford D.Phil. 1963.</para>
<para id="p184"><emph type="i">The armourer and his methods, with some account of individual masters of the craft.</emph> C.J. ffoulkes. Oxford B.Litt. 1911.</para>
<para id="p185"><emph type="i">See also</emph> MEDIEVAL EUROPE AND BYZANTIUM: GENERAL AND POLITICAL HISTORY: England and France, including the Hundred Years War.</para>
</section>
<section id="s8">
<head>ECONOMIC AND SOCIAL HISTORY</head>
<section id="s9">
<head>Finance</head>
<para id="p186"><emph type="i">Moneyers of the late Anglo-Saxon coinage, 973&ndash;1016.</emph> Veronica J. Smart. Nottingham M.A. 1963.</para>
<para id="p187"><emph type="i">The organisation of the currency, <emph type="i">c</emph>. 1180&ndash;<emph type="i">c</emph>.1250.</emph> G.K. Tibbo. Reading M.A. 1954.</para>
<para id="p188"><emph type="i">The great roll of the pipe for the 9th year of the reign of King Richard I, Michaelmas 1197.</emph> Helen M. Grace. Reading M.A. 1929.</para>
<page start="039"/>
<para id="p189"><emph type="i">The carucage of 1200.</emph> P.W. Hasler. Reading M.A. 1955.</para>
<para id="p190"><emph type="i">The great roll of the pipe for the 7th year of the reign of King John, Michaelmas 1205.</emph> S. Smith. Reading Ph.D. 1937.</para>
<para id="p191"><emph type="i">The great roll of the pipe for the 14th and 16th years of the reign of King John.</emph> Patricia M. Barnes. Reading Ph.D. 1956.</para>
<para id="p192"><emph type="i">Pipe roll, 2 Henry III.</emph> Erica P. Ebden. Reading M.Phil. 1969.</para>
<para id="p193"><emph type="i">The great roll of the pipe for the 4th year of the reign of Henry III.</emph> B.E. Harris. Nottingham Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p194"><emph type="i">Jewish finance in England, 1216&ndash;90, with special reference to royal revenue.</emph> P. Elman. London M.A. 1935.</para>
<para id="p195"><emph type="i">Plea rolls of the exchequer of the Jews (Michaelmas Term 1277 - Hilary Term 1279) preserved in the Public Record Office.</emph> Sarah Cohen. London Ph.D. 1951.</para>
<para id="p196"><emph type="i">The financial relations between the Crown and the City of London in the reigns of Edward I to Henry VII (excluding parliamentary taxation).</emph> G.J. de C. Mead. London M.A. 1936.</para>
<para id="p197"><emph type="i">Clerical taxation and consent in the reign of Edward I.</emph> H.S. Deighton. Oxford B.Litt. 1935.</para>
<para id="p198"><emph type="i">Scutages and aids in England, particularly in the 14th century.</emph> Helena M. Chew. London M.A. 1921.</para>
<para id="p199"><emph type="i">The Stapeldon-Meldon exchequer reforms and their execution.</emph> Dorothy M. Broome. Manchester M.A. 1920.</para>
<para id="p200"><emph type="i">The exchequer under Edward III: a preliminary study.</emph> Dorothy M. Broome. Manchester Ph.D. 1922.</para>
<para id="p201"><emph type="i">The taxation of wool, 1327&ndash;48.</emph> F.R. Barnes. Manchester M.A. 1912.</para>
<para id="p202"><emph type="i">The London lay subsidy of 1332.</emph> Margaret Curtis. Manchester M.A. 1912.</para>
<para id="p203"><emph type="i">Studies in taxation and the development of parliament, 1336&ndash;48.</emph> W.N. Bryant. Cambridge Ph.D. 1964.</para>
<para id="p204"><emph type="i">The administration of the subsidies under Edward III, 1336&ndash;48.</emph> M.V. Gregory. Manchester M.A. 1921.</para>
<para id="p205"><emph type="i">Edward III's war finance 1337&ndash;41: transactions in wool and credit operations.</emph> E.B. Fryde. Oxford D.Phil. 1947.</para>
<para id="p206"><emph type="i">English government finance, 1399&ndash;1413.</emph> T. Kido. London Ph.D. 1966.</para>
</section>
<section id="s10">
<head>Land Tenure</head>
<para id="p207"><emph type="i">The Anglo-Saxon thegnage from 871 to <emph type="i">c</emph>.1100, with some comparison with the pre-feudal Frankish nobility of service.</emph> Mary C. Pinsent. London M.A. 1952.</para>
<para id="p208"><emph type="i">Agricultural enterprise on the red loams and culm measures of Devon - an analytical survey.</emph> J.R. Blunden. Exeter Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<para id="p209"><emph type="i">Studies in the geography of Domesday Book.</emph> I.B. Terrett. Liverpool Ph.D. 1950.</para>
<para id="p210"><emph type="i">Norman Lincolnshire.</emph> G.H. Marshall. Leeds M.A. 1948.</para>
<para id="p211"><emph type="i">Feudalism in Jersey.</emph> Agnes F. Luce. London M.A. 1924.</para>
<para id="p212"><emph type="i">The eperqueries of the Channel Islands and their analogues.</emph> Brenda M. Bolton. Leeds M.A. 1963.</para>
<para id="p213"><emph type="i">The lands and rights of Harold, son of Godwine, and their redistribution by William I.</emph> R.H. Davies. Wales M.A. 1968.</para>
<para id="p214"><emph type="i">Aspects of sub-infeudation on some Domesday secular fiefs.</emph> J.F.A. Mason. Oxford D.Phil. 1952.</para>
<para id="p215"><emph type="i">The king's thegns and serjeants in Domesday Book.</emph> Amy E. Watkinson. London M.A. 1958.</para>
<para id="p216"><emph type="i">The social structure of English Mercia in Domesday.</emph> Pauline M. Lehmann. London M.A. 1950.</para>
<para id="p217"><emph type="i">The Domesday survey of Middlesex.</emph> T.G. Pinder. London M.A. 1960.</para>
<para id="p218"><emph type="i">The Domesday survey of Dorset and the Dorset geld rolls.</emph> E. Ann Williams. London Ph.D. 1964.</para>
<page start="040"/>
<para id="p219"><emph type="i">The feudal aspect of the Domesday survey of Somerset and Dorset in connexion with the barony of Moiun (Dunster castle) and analogous feudal estates, based upon contemporary public and local records.</emph> Margaret F. Moore. London Ph.D. 1930.</para>
<para id="p220"><emph type="i">The Domesday geography of Somerset and Staffordshire.</emph> P. Wheatley. London M.A. 1951.</para>
<para id="p221"><emph type="i">A study of the lay fiefs of Norfolk at the time of the Domesday Survey.</emph> P. Carnell. Wales M.A. 1966.</para>
<para id="p222"><emph type="i">Feudal tenure in 11th-century England: the Norman conquest of Kent.</emph> G.R. Duncombe. Exeter M.A. 1967.</para>
<para id="p223"><emph type="i">The <emph type="i">Cartae Baronum</emph> of 1166.</emph> B.J. Feeney. Belfast M.A. 1970.</para>
<para id="p224"><emph type="i">Some contributions to 13th-century feudal geography.</emph> I.J. Sanders. Oxford D.Phil. 1938.</para>
<para id="p225"><emph type="i">English ecclesiastical baronies and knight service, especially in the 13th and 14th centuries.</emph> Helena M. Chew. London Ph.D. 1926.</para>
<para id="p226"><emph type="i">Frank almoign: a study of ecclesiastical tenure in England chiefly in the 14th and 15th centuries.</emph> Elisabeth G. Kimball. Oxford B.Litt. 1927.</para>
<para id="p227"><emph type="i">The Leicestershire survey, <emph type="i">c</emph>. A.D. 1130.</emph> C.F. Slade. Reading Ph.D. 1956.</para>
</section>
<section id="s11">
<head>Estates and Forests</head>
<para id="p228"><emph type="i">A study of the social and economic influence of the small unit of cultivation.</emph> E. Thomas. Oxford B.Litt. 1926.</para>
<para id="p229"><emph type="i">A contribution to the study of strip lynchets.</emph> G.W. Whittington. Reading Ph.D. 1959.</para>
<para id="p230"><emph type="i">Anglo-Saxon charters.</emph> Agnes J. Robertson. Cambridge Ph.D. 1933/4.</para>
<para id="p231"><emph type="i">The role of the Fenland in English history.</emph> H.C. Darby. Cambridge Ph.D. 1930/1.</para>
<para id="p232"><emph type="i">The Lincolnshire Fenland in the early middle ages: a social and economic history.</emph> H.E. Hallam. Nottingham Ph.D. 1957.</para>
<para id="p233"><emph type="i">The history of Pershore abbey and its estates.</emph> R.A.L. Smith. London M.A. 1938.</para>
<para id="p234"><emph type="i">Custodia Essexae: a study of the conventual property held by the priory of Christ Church, Canterbury, in the counties of Essex, Suffolk and Norfolk.</emph> J.F. Nichols. London Ph.D. 1930.</para>
<para id="p235"><emph type="i">The estates of the cathedral church of Hereford, 1066&ndash;1317.</emph> Marjorie Jones. Oxford B.Litt. 1958.</para>
<para id="p236"><emph type="i">The estates of the Clare family, 1066&ndash;1317.</emph> Jennifer C. Ward. London Ph.D. 1962.</para>
<para id="p237"><emph type="i">The family and honour of Mowbray in England and Normandy, 1100&ndash;91.</emph> Diana E. Greenway. Cambridge Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p238"><emph type="i">Some northern royal forests, north of Trent, 1066&ndash;1307.</emph> W.H. Liddell. Nottingham M.A. 1961.</para>
<para id="p239"><emph type="i">The administration and economy of the Forest of Feckenham during the early middle ages.</emph> J. West. Birmingham M.A. 1964.</para>
<para id="p240"><emph type="i">The administration and agrarian policy of the manors of Durham cathedral priory.</emph> Elizabeth M. Halcrow. Oxford B.Litt. 1949.</para>
<para id="p241"><emph type="i">The estates of Peterborough abbey, 1086&ndash;1310: the Norman settlement to the Edwardian administration.</emph> E.J. King. Cambridge Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p242"><emph type="i">Settlement, land use and population in the western portion of the Forest of Arden, Warwickshire, between 1086 and 1350: a study in historical geography.</emph> B.K. Roberts. Birmingham Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<para id="p243"><emph type="i">The reclamation of waste in the Forest of Knaresborough: a study in settlement and enclosure.</emph> Margaret Agerskow. Leeds M.A. 1958.</para>
<page start="041"/>
<para id="p244"><emph type="i">The Forest of Dean in its relations with the Crown during the 12th and 13th centuries.</emph> Margaret L. Bazeley. London M.A. 1911.</para>
<para id="p245"><emph type="i">The estates of Norwich cathedral priory during the 12th and 13th centuries.</emph> E. Stone. Oxford D.Phil. 1956.</para>
<para id="p246"><emph type="i">Ramsey abbey estates: a study in economic growth and organisation.</emph> J.A. Raftis. Cambridge Ph.D. 1954.</para>
<para id="p247"><emph type="i">A calendar of the de Hoghton deeds and papers at Preston Hoghton Towers, Lancs.</emph> J.H. Lumby. Liverpool M.A. 1936.</para>
<para id="p248"><emph type="i">The administration of the royal forests of England during the 13th century.</emph> R.K.J. Grant. Wales Ph.D. 1938.</para>
<para id="p249"><emph type="i">The forest books of the royal forest of Sherwood.</emph> Helen E. Boulton. Nottingham M.A. 1959.</para>
<para id="p250"><emph type="i">The monastic grange: a survey of the historical and archaeological evidence.</emph> C.P.S. Platt. Leeds Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p251"><emph type="i">The grange system and sheep farming activities of some Yorkshire Cistercian abbeys.</emph> Patricia B. Atkinson. London M.A. (Ext.) 1953.</para>
<para id="p252"><emph type="i">The estates of Glastonbury abbey in the later middle ages.</emph> I.J.E. Keil. Bristol Ph.D. 1964.</para>
<para id="p253"><emph type="i">The Worcestershire peasantry in the later middle ages.</emph> R.K. Field. Birmingham M.A. 1962.</para>
<para id="p254"><emph type="i">The peasant land market in Berkshire during the later middle ages.</emph> Mrs. Rosamund J. Faith. Leicester Ph.D. 1962.</para>
<para id="p255"><emph type="i">Agrarian conditions on the Wiltshire estates of the duchy of Lancaster, the Lords Hungerford and the bishopric of Winchester in the 13th, 14th and 15th centuries.</emph> Mrs. Richenda C. Scott. London Ph.D. 1940.</para>
<para id="p256"><emph type="i">English manorial accountancy in the 13th and early 14th centuries, with special reference to the didactic treatises on the subject.</emph> Dorothea Oschinsky. London Ph.D. 1942.</para>
<para id="p257"><emph type="i">The machinery of manorial administration, with special reference to the lands of the bishopric of Winchester, 1208&ndash;1454.</emph> Eleanor Swift. London M.A. 1930.</para>
<para id="p258"><emph type="i">The franchise in 13th-century England, with especial reference to the estates of the bishopric of Winchester.</emph> A.N. May. Cambridge Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p259"><emph type="i">Land and population on the bishop of Winchester's estates, 1209&ndash;1350.</emph> J.Z. Titow. Cambridge Ph.D. 1962.</para>
<para id="p260"><emph type="i">The pipe roll of the bishopric of Winchester, 1210&ndash;11: an edition of the text with an introductory essay on its value for administrative history.</emph> N.R. Holt. Manchester M.A. 1955.</para>
<para id="p261"><emph type="i">The estates of Titchfield abbey, <emph type="i">c</emph>. 1245 to <emph type="i">c</emph>. 1380.</emph> D.G. Watts. Oxford B.Litt. 1958.</para>
<para id="p262"><emph type="i">The organisation of the manor, with reference to the estates of Crowland abbey.</emph> Frances M. Page. Cambridge Ph.D. 1929/30.</para>
<para id="p263"><emph type="i">Accounts and surveys of the Wiltshire lands of Adam de Stratton, 1269&ndash;89.</emph> M.W. Farr. Birmingham M.A. 1959.</para>
<para id="p264"><emph type="i">A geographical study of agriculture on the Kentish manors of Canterbury cathedral priory, 1272&ndash;1379.</emph> Ann Smith. Liverpool M.A. 1961.</para>
<para id="p265"><emph type="i">The lands of Isabella de Fortibus, countess of Aumale: a study in 13th-century administration.</emph> N. Denholm-Young. Oxford B.Litt. 1929.</para>
<para id="p266"><emph type="i">The manorial administration of the bishopric of Winchester, 1282&ndash;1304.</emph> Jean Parke. Manchester M.A. 1947.</para>
<para id="p267"><emph type="i">The Dean Forest eyre of 1282.</emph> C.E. Hart. Bristol M.A. 1956.</para>
<para id="p268"><emph type="i">Bolton priory, 1286&ndash;1325: an economic study.</emph> I. Kershaw. Oxford D.Phil. 1969.</para>
<para id="p269"><emph type="i">Agrarian conditions in Herefordshire and the adjacent border during the later middle ages.</emph> A.J. Roderick. London Ph.D. 1938.</para>
<para id="p270"><emph type="i">The abbey of Chertsey and its manors under Abbot John de Rutherwyk, 1307&ndash;47.</emph> Elsie Toms. London Ph.D. 1935.</para>
<page start="042"/>
<para id="p271"><emph type="i">Aspects of the economic development of some Leicestershire estates in the 14th and 15th centuries.</emph> R.H. Hilton. Oxford D.Phil. 1940.</para>
<para id="p272"><emph type="i">The administration of the estates of Merton College in the 14th century, with special reference to the Black Death and the problems of labour.</emph> Mrs. Edith C. Lowry. Oxford D.Phil. 1932/3.</para>
<para id="p273"><emph type="i">The Woodlands Estate, 1357&ndash;1527.</emph> P.A. Crowther. Nottingham M.A. 1969.</para>
<para id="p274"><emph type="i">The lands and servants of the dukes of York to 1415.</emph> T.B. Pugh. Oxford B.Litt. 1948.</para>
<para id="p275"><emph type="i">The Stanley family, <emph type="i">c</emph>. 1385&ndash;1651: a study of the origins, power and wealth of a landowning family.</emph> B. Coward. Sheffield Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p276"><emph type="i">Christ Church, Canterbury, and its lands from the beginning of the priorate of Thomas Chillenden to the Dissolution (1391&ndash;1540).</emph> Mrs. Mary N. Birchall, <emph type="i">n&eacute;e</emph> Carlin. Oxford B.Litt. 1970.</para>
<para id="p277"><emph type="i">A study of landowners and their estates in Essex, Kent, Surrey and Sussex at the opening of the 15th century, based on the assessments for the land tax of 1412 (<emph type="i">Feudal Aids</emph>. VI, p.391 seq.).</emph> Mrs. Madeline J. Barber. Oxford B.Litt. 1949.</para>
<para id="p278"><emph type="i">The estates of the Pelham family in east Sussex before 1500.</emph> Marie Clough. Cambridge Ph.D. 1957.</para>
<para id="p279"><emph type="i">The estates of the Percy family, 1416&ndash;1537.</emph> J.M.W. Bean. Oxford D.Phil. 1952.</para>
<para id="p280"><emph type="i">Some Yorkshire estates of the Percies, 1450&ndash;1650.</emph> E.J. Fisher. Leeds Ph.D. 1955.</para>
<para id="p281"><emph type="i">An edition of the cartulary of John de Macclesfield.</emph> Julia L.C. Bruell. London M.A. (Ext.) 1969.</para>
<para id="p282"><emph type="i">The economy and administration of the estates of the dean and chapter of Exeter cathedral in the 15th century.</emph> D.J.B. Hindley. London M.A. (Ext.) 1958.</para>
<para id="p283"><emph type="i">For cartularies of religious houses</emph>, <emph type="i">see under</emph> ECCLESIASTICAL HISTORY: Monasticism and Religious Orders</para>
</section>
<section id="s12">
<head>Trade and Industry</head>
<para id="p284"><emph type="i">The Old English gild system.</emph> Mrs. Constance W. Dove. Leeds M.A. 1941.</para>
<para id="p285"><emph type="i">The growth of the organisation of the Cinque ports confederation.</emph> Katherine M.E. Murray. Oxford B.Litt. 1932.</para>
<para id="p286"><emph type="i">The Cinque port towns: a comparative geographical study.</emph> Marjorie Wright. London Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<para id="p287"><emph type="i">The location and development of the Hull fishing industry.</emph> G.S. Clark. Hull M.Sc. 1957.</para>
<para id="p288"><emph type="i">The history of the port of Hull to the end of the 14th century.</emph> W.R. Jones. Wales M.A. 1944.</para>
<para id="p289"><emph type="i">The pastoral custom and local wool trade of medieval Sussex, 1085&ndash;1485.</emph> A.M.M. Melville. London M.A. 1931.</para>
<para id="p290"><emph type="i">Medieval fairs in England.</emph> J. Bennison. London M.A. 1911.</para>
<para id="p291"><emph type="i">Yorkshire fairs and markets to the end of the 18th century.</emph> K.L. McCutcheon. Durham M.Litt. 1935.</para>
<para id="p292"><emph type="i">Historical survey of the Somerset and Bristol fairs.</emph> N.F. Hulbert. Bristol M.A. 1935.</para>
<para id="p293"><emph type="i">A glossary of textile fabrics used in England prior to 1500 A.D., with notes upon their history and application.</emph> Marjorie Leaf. Leeds M.A. 1934.</para>
<para id="p294"><emph type="i">The market for Flemish and Brabantine cloth in England from the 12th to the 14th century.</emph> Lorna J. Buyse. London M.A. 1956.</para>
<para id="p295"><emph type="i">The history of the London Weavers' Company.</emph> Frances Consitt. Oxford B.Litt. 1929.</para>
<para id="p296"><emph type="i">The medieval gilds of Stratford-on-Avon and the timber-framed building industry.</emph> T.H. Lloyd. Birmingham M.A. 1961.</para>
<page start="043"/>
<para id="p297"><emph type="i">The London fur trade in the later middle ages, with particular reference to the Skinners' Company.</emph> Elspeth M. Veale. London Ph.D. 1953.</para>
<para id="p298"><emph type="i">The medieval pottery industry in Great Britain.</emph> J.W.G. Musty. Bristol M.A. 1966.</para>
<para id="p299"><emph type="i">The medieval pottery of the Leicester region and its interpretation for social and economic history.</emph> J.F.O'N. Russell. Belfast M.A. 1966.</para>
<para id="p300"><emph type="i">The history of Reading in the later middle ages, considered with special reference to the importance of the gild merchant in medieval seignorial boroughs.</emph> N.H. Gibbs. Oxford D.Phil. 1935.</para>
<para id="p301"><emph type="i">The trade and industry of Devonshire in the later middle ages.</emph> Frances A. Mace. London M.A. 1925.</para>
<para id="p302"><emph type="i">The borough of Droitwich and its salt industry, 1215&ndash;1700.</emph> Elizabeth K. Gillan. Birmingham M.A. 1956.</para>
<para id="p303"><emph type="i">Economic change in Derbyshire in the late middle ages, 1272&ndash;1540.</emph> I.S.W. Blanchard. London Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p304"><emph type="i">A general sketch of the history of the Italian merchants in England, 1272&ndash;1399; especially in connexion with the wool trade.</emph> Ada Neild. London M.A. 1914.</para>
<para id="p305"><emph type="i">The English wool trade in the 13th century.</emph> F. Miller. Oxford B.Litt. 1921.</para>
<para id="p306"><emph type="i">The medieval wills of Bristol.</emph> Mrs. Gillian H. Nicolson, <emph type="i">n&eacute;e</emph> Sutcliffe. Birmingham M.A. 1970.</para>
<para id="p307"><emph type="i">The rise of the English merchants from the expulsion of the Jews to the peace of Bretigny.</emph> Ann K. Pattison. Liverpool M.A. 1953.</para>
<para id="p308"><emph type="i">The Wealden iron industry.</emph> Margaret Richards. London Ph.D. 1924.</para>
<para id="p309"><emph type="i">The import trade in salt into England in the 14th and 15th centuries.</emph> A.R. Bridbury. London Ph.D. 1953.</para>
<para id="p310"><emph type="i">The non-sweet wine trade of England during the 14th and 15th centuries.</emph> Margaret K. James. Oxford D.Phil. 1952.</para>
<para id="p311"><emph type="i">Some aspects of the trade of Newcastle upon Tyne in the 14th century.</emph> J.B. Blake. Bristol M.A. 1962.</para>
<para id="p312"><emph type="i">The port of Chester in the late middle ages: a study of the customs organisation, the trade and merchant community of Chester between 1301 and 1558.</emph> K.P. Wilson. Liverpool Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p313"><emph type="i">The borough and the merchant community of Ipswich, 1317&ndash;1422.</emph> G.H. Martin. Oxford D.Phil. 1955.</para>
<para id="p314"><emph type="i">The legal and economic relations between alien merchants and the central government in England, 1350&ndash;77.</emph> Alice Beardwood. Oxford D.Phil. 1928/9.</para>
<para id="p315"><emph type="i">The position of foreign merchants in England in the time of Edward III, mainly from the legal standpoint.</emph> Alice Beardwood. Oxford B.Litt. 1924.</para>
<para id="p316"><emph type="i">The societies of the Bardi and Peruzzi and their dealings with Edward III.</emph> E. Russell. Manchester M.A. 1912.</para>
<para id="p317"><emph type="i">The history of the Staple at Westminster in the reign of Richard II.</emph> Janet S.A. Macaulay. Oxford B.Litt. 1934.</para>
<para id="p318"><emph type="i">The ship-building industry on the east and south coasts of England in the 15th century.</emph> Mary A.S. Hickmore. London M.A. 1937.</para>
<para id="p319"><emph type="i">A study of the merchant class of London in the 15th century, with special reference to the Company of Grocers.</emph> Sylvia L. Thrupp. London Ph.D. 1931.</para>
<para id="p320"><emph type="i">The overseas trade of Bristol in the later middle ages: a study of English commerce, 1399&ndash;1485.</emph> Eleanora M. Carus-Wilson. London M.A. 1926.</para>
<para id="p321"><emph type="i">Women in the textile industries and trade of 15th century England.</emph> Marian K. Dale. London M.A. 1928.</para>
<para id="p322"><emph type="i">The port book of Southampton for 1439&ndash;40, edited, with an introduction relating to local port dues and the coastal trade of Southampton.</emph> H.S. Cobb. London M.A. 1957.</para>
<page start="044"/>
<para id="p323"><emph type="i">The brokage book of Southampton for 1443&ndash;4, edited, with an introduction on the Bargate tolls and the overland distribution of goods from Southampton.</emph> Olive P. Coleman. London M.A. 1957.</para>
<para id="p324"><emph type="i">The transactions between the merchants of the Staple and the Lancastrian government, 1449&ndash;61.</emph> Winifred I. Haward. London Ph.D. 1931.</para>
<para id="p325"><emph type="i">Prices and wages in England, 1450&ndash;1550.</emph> Y.S. Brenner. London M.A. 1960.</para>
<para id="p326"><emph type="i">The financing of trade in the later middle ages, with special reference to English foreign trade in the 15th century.</emph> M.M. Postan. London M.Sc. 1926.</para>
<para id="p327"><emph type="i">Plymouth Haven: a survey of the Haven in relation to the sea manuals and charts used in the home waters of north-west Europe from the late 14th century to 1693.</emph> A.E. Stephens. London M.Sc. 1936.</para>
<para id="p328"><emph type="i">The history of cartographical symbols.</emph> Eila M.J. Campbell. London M.A. 1946.</para>
</section>
<section id="s13">
<head>Social History</head>
<para id="p329"><emph type="i">Kingship and nobility in Anglo-Saxon England to the time of Alfred the Great.</emph> H.R. Loyn. Wales M.A. 1949.</para>
<para id="p330"><emph type="i">The family of de la Pomerai of Beri, 1066&ndash;1700 (with appendix post 1720).</emph> E.B. Powley. Liverpool M.A. 1941.</para>
<para id="p331"><emph type="i">The early history of the Davenports of Davenport.</emph> T.P. Highet. Manchester M.A. 1953.</para>
<para id="p332"><emph type="i">The Lacy family in England and Normandy, 1066&ndash;1194.</emph> W.E. Wightman. Leeds Ph.D. 1960.</para>
<para id="p333"><emph type="i">The Lacy family of Herefordshire before 1243: their influence on the political history of England, Normandy and Ireland.</emph> Barbara Donaldson. Bristol M.A. 1957.</para>
<para id="p334"><emph type="i">The character and use of domestic furnishings in England as discernible from documentary and archaeological evidence from the 11th to the 15th centuries.</emph> Mrs. Penelope Eames. Liverpool M.A. 1969.</para>
<para id="p335"><emph type="i">The social and economic condition of the unfree classes in England from the 12th to the 14th century, with special reference to the eastern counties.</emph> N. Neild. London M.A. 1908.</para>
<para id="p336"><emph type="i">The <emph type="i">acta</emph> of John, lord of Ireland and count of Mortain, with a study of his household.</emph> Margaret Preen. Manchester M.A. 1949.</para>
<para id="p337"><emph type="i">The development of West Riding surnames from the 13th to the 20th century.</emph> G. Redmonds. Leicester Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p338"><emph type="i">The Hungerford family in the later middle ages.</emph> J.L. Kirby. London M.A. 1939.</para>
<para id="p339"><emph type="i">The position and history of the Jews in England in the 13th century.</emph> E. Dakin. Wales M.A. 1913.</para>
<para id="p340"><emph type="i">The house of Bigod in the reign of Henry III.</emph> G. Goodall. Manchester M.A. 1925.</para>
<para id="p341"><emph type="i">The English view of usury and the distribution of wealth in the later middle ages.</emph> H.G. Richardson. London M.A. 1912.</para>
<para id="p342"><emph type="i">The distribution of lay wealth in south-east England in the early 14th century.</emph> R.E. Glasscock. London Ph.D. 1962.</para>
<para id="p343"><emph type="i">The career, lands and family of William Montague, earl of Salisbury, 1301&ndash;44.</emph> R. Douch. London M.A. (Ext.) 1950.</para>
<para id="p344"><emph type="i">Medieval administration in the 14th century, with special reference to the household of Elizabeth de Burgh, Lady of Clare.</emph> Clare A. Musgrave. London M.A. 1923.</para>
<para id="p345"><emph type="i">Foreign chivalry at the court of Edward III.</emph> F. Schenck. Oxford B.Litt. 1912.</para>
<para id="p346"><emph type="i">The Lords Grey of Ruthin, 1325 to 1490: a study in the lesser baronage.</emph> R.I. Jack. London Ph.D. 1961.</para>
<para id="p347"><emph type="i">The English nobility in the reign of Edward III.</emph> G.A. Holmes. Cambridge Ph.D. 1952.</para>
<page start="045"/>
<para id="p348"><emph type="i">The Black Death, 1348&ndash;9, with special reference to cathedral registers for the mortality of the clergy.</emph> J. Lunn. Cambridge Ph.D. 1930/1.</para>
<para id="p349"><emph type="i">Social life in England during the reign of Richard II.</emph> Grace B.C. Newell. Leeds M.A. 1931.</para>
<para id="p350"><emph type="i">The family of Talbot, Lords Talbot and earls of Shrewsbury, 1387&ndash;1473.</emph> A.J. Pollard. Bristol Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p351"><emph type="i">Medieval travel, as illustrated by the wardrobe accounts of Henry, earl of Derby, 1390&ndash;3.</emph> Grace Stretton. London M.A. 1924.</para>
<para id="p352"><emph type="i">The Yorkshire baronage, 1399&ndash;1433.</emph> C.D. Ross. Oxford D.Phil. 1950.</para>
<para id="p353"><emph type="i">East Anglian society in the 15th century: an historico-regional survey.</emph> G.E. Morey. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1951.</para>
<para id="p354"><emph type="i">Ralph, Lord Cromwell and his household: studies in relation to household accounts in the possession of Lord De l'Isle and Dudley.</emph> Evelyn M. Price. London M.A. 1948.</para>
<para id="p355"><emph type="i">The Bulkeleys of Baron Hill, 1440&ndash;1621.</emph> D.C. Jones. Wales M.A. 1958.</para>
<para id="p356"><emph type="i">The nobility of England, 1453&ndash;1558.</emph> P.J. Higson. Liverpool M.A. 1959.</para>
<para id="p357"><emph type="i">A new edition of the Cely Letters: 1472&ndash;88.</emph> Mrs. Alison H. Hanham, <emph type="i">n&eacute;e</emph> Forester. Bristol Ph.D. 1954.</para>
<para id="p358"><emph type="i">The Plumpton correspondence: an historical and social survey.</emph> Mrs. Shirley M. Walker, <emph type="i">n&eacute;e</emph> Thomas. Leeds M.A. 1962.</para>
<para id="p359"><emph type="i">The status and function of minstrels in England between 1350 and 1400.</emph> Margaret A. Price. Birmingham M.A. 1964/5.</para>
<para id="p360"><emph type="i">Music under the later Plantagenets.</emph> B.L. Trowell. Cambridge Ph.D. 1960.</para>
<para id="p361"><emph type="i">The royal entry in medieval and early Tudor England.</emph> Caroline L.W. Holt. Manchester Ph.D. 1969.</para>
</section>
</section>
<section id="s14">
<head>ECCLESIASTICAL HISTORY</head>
<section id="s15">
<head>General</head>
<para id="p362"><emph type="i">A short consideration of the influence of the Roman see in the conversion of Britain to Christianity.</emph> E.M. Swift. Belfast M.A. 1915.</para>
<para id="p363"><emph type="i">The archiepiscopal sees in England from St. Augustine to St. Dunstan.</emph> J.W. Lamb. Leeds Ph.D. 1953.</para>
<para id="p364"><emph type="i">The territorial possessions of St. Wilfrid and their influence upon his career.</emph> M. Roper. Manchester M.A. 1958.</para>
<para id="p365"><emph type="i">Theodore of Tarsus, archbishop of Canterbury 668&ndash;90.</emph> R.H. Whitaker. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1948.</para>
<para id="p366"><emph type="i">The autonomy of the Anglo-Saxon Church.</emph> J.G.M. Howard. Durham M.A. 1931.</para>
<para id="p367"><emph type="i">Anglo-Saxon ecclesiastical organisation in the kingdom of Wessex.</emph> P.G. Medd. Oxford B.Litt. 1958.</para>
<para id="p368"><emph type="i">A correlation of linguistic and archaeological evidence for Anglo-Saxon heathenism.</emph> Audrey L. Savill. Cambridge Ph.D. 1959.</para>
<para id="p369"><emph type="i">The Celtic Church in England after the synod of Whitby.</emph> J.L.G. Meissner. Belfast M.A. 1927.</para>
<para id="p370"><emph type="i">The origin of the parish.</emph> M.W. Neilson. Aberdeen Ph.D. 1928.</para>
<para id="p371"><emph type="i">Some aspects of Northumbrian history in the 11th century, with particular reference to the four last Anglo-Saxon archbishops of York, 1002-69.</emph> Janet M. Cooper. Cambridge Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p372"><emph type="i">The king's government and episcopal vacancies in England, 11th to 14th century.</emph> Margaret E. Howell. London Ph.D. 1955.</para>
<para id="p373"><emph type="i">The bishops of Chichester and the administration of their diocese from the Norman Conquest to 1207, with a collection of <emph type="i">acta</emph>.</emph> H.M.R.E. Mayr-Harting. Oxford D.Phil. 1961.</para>
<page start="046"/>
<para id="p374"><emph type="i">Church and state during the reign of William I.</emph> J.W. Lamb. Leeds M.A. 1933.</para>
<para id="p375"><emph type="i">The Norman episcopate during the reign of William the Conqueror.</emph> P.L. Hull. Bristol M.A. 1954.</para>
<para id="p376"><emph type="i">The church of Exeter in the Norman period.</emph> D.W. Blake. Exeter M.A. 1970.</para>
<para id="p377"><emph type="i">The parish in Domesday Book: a study of the mother churches, manorial churches and rural chapels in the late Saxon and early Norman periods.</emph> Daphne H. Gifford. London Ph.D. 1952.</para>
<para id="p378"><emph type="i">The English Church under Henry I.</emph> M. Brett. Oxford D.Phil. 1969.</para>
<para id="p379"><emph type="i">Anselm and his circle; a study of the historical importance of his letters.</emph> Winifred M. Mitchiner. London M.A. 1945.</para>
<para id="p380"><emph type="i">The correspondence of Archbishop Lanfranc: a critical edition with notes and a historical introduction.</emph> Mrs. V. Helen Clover. Cambridge Ph.D. 1962.</para>
<para id="p381"><emph type="i">Themes and traditions in saints' legends in Britain and Ireland.</emph> B.K. Martin. Cambridge M.Litt. 1958.</para>
<para id="p382"><emph type="i">English hagiology, 1100&ndash;35.</emph> D.F.H. Farmer. Oxford B.Litt. 1967.</para>
<para id="p383"><emph type="i">Jacobean pilgrims from England from the early 12th to the late 15th century.</emph> Mrs. Constance M. Storrs. London M.A. 1964.</para>
<para id="p384"><emph type="i">The activities of rural deans in England in the 12th and 13th centuries.</emph> J. Foster. Manchester M.A. 1955.</para>
<para id="p385"><emph type="i">The statutes of the provincial courts of Canterbury and York.</emph> C.E. Welch. Southampton Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p386"><emph type="i">The archiepiscopate of William of Corbeil, 1123&ndash;36.</emph> D.L.T. Bethell. Oxford B.Litt. 1963.</para>
<para id="p387"><emph type="i">An edition and translation of the 'Vita domini Roberti de Betune Herfordensis episcopi', by William de Wycumba, with introduction and notes.</emph> Betty J. Parkinson. Oxford B.Litt. 1951.</para>
<para id="p388"><emph type="i">The life of Theobald, archbishop of Canterbury.</emph> A.A. Saltman. London Ph.D. 1951.</para>
<para id="p389"><emph type="i">The life and acts of Robert of Chesney, bishop of Lincoln, 1148&ndash;66.</emph> H.P. King. London M.A. 1955.</para>
<para id="p390"><emph type="i">Roger, bishop of Worcester, 1164&ndash;79.</emph> Mary G. Hall. Oxford B.Litt. 1940.</para>
<para id="p391"><emph type="i">The <emph type="i">acta</emph> of Archbishops Richard and Baldwin, 1174&ndash;90.</emph> Bridgett E.A. Jones. London Ph.D. 1964.</para>
<para id="p392"><emph type="i">Gilbert Glanville, bishop of Rochester, 1185&ndash;1214, and the relationship of the see of Rochester to Canterbury to 1238.</emph> J. Moule. Manchester M.A. 1954.</para>
<para id="p393"><emph type="i">An edition of William of Malmesbury's Treatise on the Miracles of the Virgin, with an account of its place in his writings and in the development of Mary legends in the 12th century.</emph> P.N. Carter. Oxford D.Phil. 1960.</para>
<para id="p394"><emph type="i">Contribution to the study of the life of Thomas Becket with special reference to the manuscripts of the poem <emph type="i">De Sancto Thoma Archiepiscopo Cantuariensi</emph>.</emph> H.H. Hodge. London M.A. 1923.</para>
<para id="p395"><emph type="i">The tradition of St. Thomas of Canterbury in literature, art and religion.</emph> A.B. Cottle. Wales M.A. 1947.</para>
<para id="p396"><emph type="i">Th&oacute;mas saga Erkibyskups: a new collation.</emph> Margaret Orme. London M.A. 1964.</para>
<para id="p397"><emph type="i">The organisation and administration of the see and diocese of Durham, 1195&ndash;1229.</emph> P.C. Brooke. Newcastle M.Litt. 1967.</para>
<para id="p398"><emph type="i">The episcopal constitutions of the diocese of Durham in the century after the Fourth Lateran Council.</emph> E. Featherstone. Durham M.A. 1960.</para>
<para id="p399"><emph type="i">Some aspects of the chantry system in Lancashire.</emph> Mary F. Coogan. Manchester M.A. 1944.</para>
<page start="047"/>
<para id="p400"><emph type="i">The minor corporations of the secular cathedrals of the province of Canterbury (excluding the Welsh sees) between the 13th century and 1536, with special reference to the minor canons of St. Paul's cathedral from their origin in the 12th century to the visitation of Bishop Gibson in 1724.</emph> A.R.B. Fuller. London M.A. 1947.</para>
<para id="p401"><emph type="i">The administrative machinery of the archbishopric of Canterbury as illustrated chiefly by records at Lambeth and Canterbury.</emph> Irene J. Churchill. Oxford D.Phil. 1930.</para>
<para id="p402"><emph type="i">Christ Church, Canterbury and the <emph type="i">sede vacante</emph> jurisdiction of Canterbury during the 13th century.</emph> Marjorie M. Morgan. Oxford B.Litt. 1938.</para>
<para id="p403"><emph type="i">John de Gray, bishop of Norwich.</emph> G.M. Budge. Manchester M.A. 1946.</para>
<para id="p404"><emph type="i">A study of the archiepiscopal household of Stephen Langton and a collection of his <emph type="i">acta</emph>.</emph> Kathleen Major. Oxford B.Litt. 1931.</para>
<para id="p405"><emph type="i">The questions of Stephen Langton.</emph> Alys L. Gregory. Manchester Ph.D. 1929.</para>
<para id="p406"><emph type="i">Stephen Langton as a defender of English liberty.</emph> Eva D. Parry. Wales M.A. 1923.</para>
<para id="p407"><emph type="i">The Lincoln cathedral chapter under Bishop Hugh of Wells, 1209&ndash;35.</emph> G.E. Milburn. Manchester M.A. 1969.</para>
<para id="p408"><emph type="i">The administration of Hugh of Wells, bishop of Lincoln, 1209&ndash;35.</emph> D.M. Smith. Nottingham Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p409"><emph type="i">An examination of the theory and practice of appointments in the reigns of Henry III and Edward I (1216&ndash;1307), and of their historical significance.</emph> Phyllis H. Scotney. London M.A. 1927.</para>
<para id="p410"><emph type="i">Disputes about episcopal elections in England in the reign of Henry III, with special reference to some unpublished Durham documents.</emph> W.K. Evers. Oxford B.Litt. 1936.</para>
<para id="p411"><emph type="i">The episcopate in the reign of Henry III.</emph> Marion E. Gibbs. Oxford B.Litt. 1932.</para>
<para id="p412"><emph type="i">Edition of Liber Albus I of Wells cathedral, fos. 9&ndash;61.</emph> Alison E. Cavendish. London M.A. 1959.</para>
<para id="p413"><emph type="i">English preaching, 1221&ndash;93.</emph> Jennifer M. Sweet. Oxford B.Litt. 1950.</para>
<para id="p414"><emph type="i">Ecclesiastical letter-books of the 13th century.</emph> Rosalind M.T. Hill. Oxford B.Litt. 1936.</para>
<para id="p415"><emph type="i">A study of certain letter-books in the possession of the dean and chapter of Durham as illustrations of the life of the church in England in the later 13th century.</emph> F. Barlow. Oxford B.Litt. 1934.</para>
<para id="p416"><emph type="i">Anglo-Norman letters and archives from the 13th to the 15th centuries, with especial reference to the archives of the dean and chapter of Durham.</emph> J.L. Freer. Durham M.A. 1956.</para>
<para id="p417"><emph type="i">The relations of the bishops and citizens of Salisbury (New Sarum) between 1225 and 1612.</emph> Fanny Street. London M.A. 1915.</para>
<para id="p418"><emph type="i">An edition of the metrical life of St. Robert of Knaresborough (together with the other pieces in Middle English contained in the British Museum MS. Egerton 3143).</emph> Joyce Bazire. Leeds M.A. 1949.</para>
<para id="p419"><emph type="i">Ralph Neville, bishop of Chichester and chancellor.</emph> Jeanne M.B. Fradin. Oxford B.Litt. 1942.</para>
<para id="p420"><emph type="i">The <emph type="i">Speculum Ecclesie</emph> of St. Edmund of Abingdon: a critical study of the text, with edition.</emph> Helen P. Forshaw (Mother Mary Philomena). London M.A. 1965.</para>
<para id="p421"><emph type="i">A critical study and edition of the biographies of St. Edmund of Abingdon, archbishop of Canterbury.</emph> C.H. Lawrence. Oxford D.Phil. 1955.</para>
<para id="p422"><emph type="i">The life of St. Edmund Rich in the south English legendary.</emph> J.T. Morris. Liverpool M.A. 1963/4.</para>
<para id="p423"><emph type="i">A critical edition of <emph type="i">The Life of St. Edmund</emph>, by John Lydgate.</emph> Mrs. Audrey Eccles. London M.A. 1957.</para>
<page start="048"/>
<para id="p424"><emph type="i">Aspects of the career of Boniface of Savoy, archbishop of Canterbury, 1241&ndash;70.</emph> D.T. Williams. Wales Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p425"><emph type="i">Ecclesiastical patronage in the diocese of York, 1258&ndash;1316.</emph> Joan C. Sinar. Manchester M.A. 1949.</para>
<para id="p426"><emph type="i">The register of Walter Bronescombe, bishop of Exeter 1258&ndash;80.</emph> Mrs. Olivia F. Robinson. London Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<para id="p427"><emph type="i">Edward I and the church.</emph> Florence E. Sweetinburgh. Birmingham M.A. 1917.</para>
<para id="p428"><emph type="i">The church in the reign of Edward I.</emph> Dorothea T. Price. Wales M.A. 1907.</para>
<para id="p429"><emph type="i">The church in the reign of Edward I, with special reference to the register of Archbishop Peckham.</emph> Blanche E. Brimson. Wales M.A. 1909.</para>
<para id="p430"><emph type="i">Archbishop Peckham.</emph> T.W. Pay. Leeds M.A. 1917.</para>
<para id="p431"><emph type="i">The religious policy of Archbishop Peckham.</emph> H. Cox. Leeds M.A. 1911.</para>
<para id="p432"><emph type="i">Some aspects of the life and work of Archbishop Peckham.</emph> Dorothy Sutcliffe. Manchester M.A. 1919.</para>
<para id="p433"><emph type="i">The archbishops and province of York, 1279&ndash;99.</emph> Mrs. Gwendolen M. Hallas. Leeds M.Phil. 1969.</para>
<para id="p434"><emph type="i">The metropolitan jurisdiction of the archbishops of York (1279&ndash;96).</emph> R.J. Brentano. Oxford D.Phil. 1952.</para>
<para id="p435"><emph type="i">Tutorial appeal to the archbishops of Canterbury and York in the 13th century.</emph> Priscilla J. Wood. Edinburgh M.Litt. 1969/70.</para>
<para id="p436"><emph type="i">Life of Antony Bek, bishop of Durham.</emph> Constance M. Fraser. Durham Ph.D. 1951.</para>
<para id="p437"><emph type="i">The life and work of Anthony Bek, bishop of Durham.</emph> G. Thomas. Wales M.A. 1915.</para>
<para id="p438"><emph type="i">The career of Robert Wihchelsey, archbishop of Canterbury.</emph> J.H. Denton. Cambridge Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p439"><emph type="i">Archbishop Winchelsey: a sketch of a critical period in the relations between church and state.</emph> F. Barton. London M.A. 1912.</para>
<para id="p440"><emph type="i">A history of Walter Langton, bishop of Coventry and Lichfield, 1296&ndash;1321.</emph> D. Whomsley. Wales M.A. 1959.</para>
<para id="p441"><emph type="i">Grievances of the English clergy in the late 13th and early 14th centuries, with special reference to the <emph type="i">gravamina</emph> of 1309.</emph> Ursula R.Q. Henriques. Oxford B.Litt. 1940.</para>
<para id="p442"><emph type="i">The administration of a medieval diocese in the last quarter of the 13th century and the first half of the 14th century, illustrated from the Hereford registers.</emph> J.A. Darbyshire. Manchester M.A. 1923.</para>
<para id="p443"><emph type="i">The administration of ecclesiastical courts in the province of Canterbury during the later middle ages.</emph> C.E. Welch. Liverpool M.A. 1953.</para>
<para id="p444"><emph type="i">Pre-Reformation church courts in the diocese of Canterbury.</emph> B.L. Woodcock. Oxford B.Litt. 1950.</para>
<para id="p445"><emph type="i">York church courts.</emph> C.I.A. Ritchie. St. Andrews Ph.D. 1952.</para>
<para id="p446"><emph type="i">The clergy of the English secular cathedrals of the 14th century with special reference to the clergy of Salisbury.</emph> Kathleen Edwards. Manchester Ph.D. 1940.</para>
<para id="p447"><emph type="i">The episcopal administration of the diocese of Exeter in the 14th century, with special reference to the registers of Bishops Stapeldon, Grandisson and Brantingham.</emph> D.J. Cawthron. London M.A. (Ext.) 1951.</para>
<para id="p448"><emph type="i">The administration of the diocese of Worcester in the first half of the 14th century.</emph> R.M. Haines. Oxford D.Phil. 1959.</para>
<para id="p449"><emph type="i">The chapter of Ripon in the later middle ages.</emph> L.W. Kitchen. Manchester M.A. 1939.</para>
<para id="p450"><emph type="i">The church in Chester, 1300&ndash;1540.</emph> D.H. Jones. Liverpool M.A. 1953.</para>
<para id="p451"><emph type="i">John de Dalderby, bishop of Lincoln 1300&ndash;20.</emph> C. Clubley. Hull Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<page start="049"/>
<para id="p452"><emph type="i">The evolution of the theory and doctrine of the church in England as exemplified by Ockham, Wyclif and Cranmer.</emph> W.L. Moser. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1927.</para>
<para id="p453"><emph type="i">A survey of the origins and circulation of theological writings in English in the 14th, 15th and early 16th centuries, with special consideration of the part of the clergy therein.</emph> A.I. Doyle. Cambridge Ph.D. 1952/3.</para>
<para id="p454"><emph type="i">Thomae de Chobham Summa confessorum: editio prioris partis.</emph> F. Broomfield. Cambridge Ph.D. 1960.</para>
<para id="p455"><emph type="i">The administration of the diocese and province of York under Archbishop William Greenfield, 1306&ndash;15.</emph> Mrs. Katherine Wood. Leeds M.A. 1962.</para>
<para id="p456"><emph type="i">An edition, with introduction, of the Winchester cathedral custumal.</emph> Katharine A. Hanna. London M.A. (Ext.) 1954.</para>
<para id="p457"><emph type="i">Adam de Orleton.</emph> G.A. Usher. Wales M.A. 1953.</para>
<para id="p458"><emph type="i">The chapter of Lichfield cathedral in the 14th century.</emph> Mrs. Hester T. Jenkins. Oxford B.Litt. 1956.</para>
<para id="p459"><emph type="i">St. Peter Thomas, 1305&ndash;66.</emph> S.T. Manbr&eacute;. Liverpool M.A. 1937.</para>
<para id="p460"><emph type="i">The personnel and political activities of the English episcopate during the reign of Edward II.</emph> Kathleen Edwards. London M.A. 1937.</para>
<para id="p461"><emph type="i">Episcopal appointments and patronage in the reign of Edward II.</emph> W.E.L. Smith. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1930/1.</para>
<para id="p462"><emph type="i">Patronage and the church: a study in the social structure of the secular clergy in the diocese of Durham, 1311&ndash;1540.</emph> R. Donaldson. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1955.</para>
<para id="p463"><emph type="i">The episcopate of Richard de Kellawe, bishop of Durham. 1311&ndash;16.</emph> D.B. Foss. Durham M.A. 1966.</para>
<para id="p464"><emph type="i">An edition of the archdeaconry of Cleveland section of the register of Archbishop Melton of York, 1317&ndash;40, with an introduction studying aspects of the clergy in the diocese.</emph> D.B. Robinson. Cambridge Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p465"><emph type="i">Some aspects of church life in England during the reign of Edward III.</emph> Kathleen L. Wood-Legh. Cambridge Ph.D. 1932/3.</para>
<para id="p466"><emph type="i">The history of the church in the reign of Edward III.</emph> Hilda M. Jones. Wales M.A. 1914.</para>
<para id="p467"><emph type="i">John Grandisson, bishop of Exeter, 1327&ndash;69.</emph> R.A. Horsfield. Leeds M.A. 1966.</para>
<para id="p468"><emph type="i">The life and register of Bishop Wolstan de Bransford.</emph> R.M. Haines. Durham M.Litt. 1954.</para>
<para id="p469"><emph type="i">The central and local financial organisation and administrative machinery of the royal free chapel of St. George within the castle of Windsor from its foundation (1348) to the treasurership of William Gillot (1415&ndash;16).</emph> A.K. Babette Roberts. London Ph.D. 1943.</para>
<para id="p470"><emph type="i">The relations between the church and the English Crown from the death of Archbishop Stratford to the opening of the Great Schism, 1349&ndash;78.</emph> J.R.L. Wighfield. Oxford D.Phil. 1951.</para>
<para id="p471"><emph type="i">Parish clergy in the diocese of Exeter in the century after the Black Death.</emph> G.R. Dunstan. Leeds M.A. 1939.</para>
<para id="p472"><emph type="i">Parochial administration in the archdeaconry of Chester, 1350&ndash;1400.</emph> W. Mather. Manchester M.A. 1932.</para>
<para id="p473"><emph type="i">The distribution of religious groups in England and Wales, 1350&ndash;1550: a study in social geography.</emph> F.H. Hansford Miller. London M.Sc. 1965.</para>
<para id="p474"><emph type="i">Medieval preaching in England, as illustrated by the period <emph type="i">c</emph>. 1350 to 1450.</emph> G.R. Owst. London Ph.D. 1924.</para>
<para id="p475"><emph type="i">John Sheppey, bishop of Rochester, as preacher and collector of sermons.</emph> G. Mifsud. Oxford B.Litt. 1954.</para>
<para id="p476"><emph type="i">Simon Sudbury, bishop of London and archbishop of Canterbury.</emph> W.L. Warren. Oxford D.Phil. 1956.</para>
<para id="p477"><emph type="i">Wyclif and Lollardy in England.</emph> W.H. Leighton. Birmingham M.A. 1925.</para>
<page start="050"/>
<para id="p478"><emph type="i">Lollard doctrine, with special reference to the controversy over image-worship and pilgrimages.</emph> J. Crompton. Oxford B.Litt. 1950.</para>
<para id="p479"><emph type="i">The Lollard movement in the dioceses of Bath and Wells, Worcester and Hereford.</emph> N.J. Davies. Wales M.A. 1966.</para>
<para id="p480"><emph type="i">An edition of the register of Henry Wakefield, bishop of Worcester 1375&ndash;95, with an introduction.</emph> W.M. Doody. London Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p481"><emph type="i">Ralph Erghum, with special reference to his tenure of the see of Salisbury 1375&ndash;88.</emph> Sylvia E. Overton. Oxford B.Litt. 1961.</para>
<para id="p482"><emph type="i">Clergy and laity in London 1376&ndash;1531.</emph> J.A.F. Thomson. Oxford D.Phil. 1960.</para>
<para id="p483"><emph type="i">The organisation of a college of secular priests as illustrated by the records of the college of Holy Trinity, Arundel, 1380&ndash;1544.</emph> R.B.K. Petch. London M.A. 1942.</para>
<para id="p484"><emph type="i">Robert Braybrooke, bishop of London (1381&ndash;1404), and his kinsmen.</emph> L.H. Butler. Oxford D.Phil. 1951.</para>
<para id="p485"><emph type="i">The life and writings of Adam Easton, O.S.B.</emph> L.J. Macfarlane. London Ph.D. 1955.</para>
<para id="p486"><emph type="i">Thomas of Chillenden's register: the earliest surviving register of testaments, 1396&ndash;1455, kept by the commissary-general of Canterbury.</emph> Brenda M. Duncombe (Mother Mary de Sales). London M.A. 1963.</para>
<para id="p487"><emph type="i">The English Church in the 15th century.</emph> F.R. Wortz. Leeds M.A. 1914.</para>
<para id="p488"><emph type="i">The episcopate in England and Wales in the reign of Henry IV.</emph> R.G. Davies. Manchester M.A. 1968.</para>
<para id="p489"><emph type="i">Some aspects of the religious history of Norfolk in the 15th century.</emph> C.B. Firth. London M.A. 1910.</para>
<para id="p490"><emph type="i">The place of the secular clergy in the society of 15th-century England.</emph> G. Templeman. London M.A. 1936.</para>
<para id="p491"><emph type="i">The church under the Lancastrians.</emph> P.H. Jones. Wales M.A. 1910.</para>
<para id="p492"><emph type="i">The cult of St. Bridget of Sweden in 15th-century England.</emph> F.R. Johnston. Manchester M.A. 1947.</para>
<para id="p493"><emph type="i">Reginald Pecock - a contribution to his biography.</emph> T. Kelly. Manchester M.A. 1945.</para>
<para id="p494"><emph type="i">Richard Ullerston, canon of Salisbury.</emph> A.H. Wood. Manchester M.A. 1936.</para>
<para id="p495"><emph type="i">The episcopal administration in the diocese of Hereford, 1400-<emph type="i">c</emph>. 1535.</emph> Enid L. Lonsdale. Liverpool M.A. 1957.</para>
<para id="p496"><emph type="i">The administration of the diocese of Bath and Wells, 1401&ndash;91.</emph> R.W. Dunning. Bristol Ph.D. 1963.</para>
<para id="p497"><emph type="i">The career of Henry Bowet, bishop of Bath and Wells, later archbishop of York.</emph> J.J.N. Palmer. Oxford B.Litt. 1964.</para>
<para id="p498"><emph type="i">Parliament and Convocation, with special reference to the pontificate of Henry Chichele, 1413&ndash;43.</emph> M. Oldfield. Manchester M.A. 1938.</para>
<para id="p499"><emph type="i">The Constitutions of Archbishop Chichele.</emph> Bridgett G. Carroll. Manchester M.A. 1932.</para>
<para id="p500"><emph type="i">New liturgical observances in later medieval England.</emph> R.W. Pfaff. Oxford D.Phil. 1965.</para>
<para id="p501"><emph type="i">Report on the chapter acts of Lincoln cathedral, 1402&ndash;27.</emph> Margaret Archer. Liverpool M.A. 1936.</para>
<para id="p502"><emph type="i">The diocese of Lincoln under Bishops Repingdon and Fleming.</emph> Margaret Archer. Oxford B.Litt. 1936.</para>
<para id="p503"><emph type="i">The administration of the see of London under Bishops Roger Walden (1405&ndash;6) and Nicholas Bubwith (1406&ndash;7), with a transcript of their registers.</emph> Una C. Hannam. London M.A. 1951.</para>
<para id="p504"><emph type="i">Thomas Langley, statesman and bishop.</emph> R.L. Storey. Durham Ph.D. 1954.</para>
<para id="p505"><emph type="i">Bishop Hallum of Salisbury and the reforming activities of his time.</emph> F.D. Hodgkiss. Manchester M.A. 1931.</para>
<page start="051"/>
<para id="p506"><emph type="i">An edition of the register of Robert Hallum, bishop of Salisbury 1408&ndash;17, with an introduction.</emph> Joyce M. Wilkinson. Oxford B.Litt. 1960.</para>
<para id="p507"><emph type="i">Studies in the Lollard heresy, being an examination of the evidence from the dioceses of Norwich, Lincoln, Coventry and Lichfield and Ely, during the period 1430&ndash;1530.</emph> J.D. Fines. Sheffield Ph.D. 1964.</para>
<para id="p508"><emph type="i">The ecclesiastical career of George Neville, 1432&ndash;76.</emph> Mrs. Gillian I. Keir, <emph type="i">n&eacute;e</emph> Stannard. Oxford B.Litt. 1970.</para>
<para id="p509"><emph type="i">John Carpenter, bishop of Worcester, 1444&ndash;76.</emph> M.J. Morgan. Birmingham M.A. 1960.</para>
<para id="p510"><emph type="i">Parish clergy in England, 1450&ndash;1530.</emph> P. Heath. London M.A. 1961.</para>
<para id="p511"><emph type="i">Thomas Rotherham, archbishop of York and chancellor of England: his life and times.</emph> Mary F.H. Robinson. Sheffield M.A. 1940.</para>
<para id="p512"><emph type="i">Edward Storey, bishop of Chichester (1422&ndash;1503): a study in 15th-century ecclesiastical administration.</emph> F.C. Walden-Aspy. London M.A. 1951.</para>
</section>
<section id="s16">
<head>Monasticism and Religious Orders</head>
<para id="p513"><emph type="i">English monasticism before 735.</emph> R.T. Timson. London M.A. 1957.</para>
<para id="p514"><emph type="i">The history of Winchcombe abbey.</emph> G.T. Haigh. Durham M. Litt. 1944.</para>
<para id="p515"><emph type="i">The history of the abbey of St. Albans.</emph> L.F.R. Williams. Oxford B.Litt. 1913.</para>
<para id="p516"><emph type="i">The anti-monastic reaction in England in the 10th century.</emph> J. Matthews. Manchester M.A. 1970.</para>
<para id="p517"><emph type="i">The pre-Conquest charters of Christchurch, Canterbury.</emph> N.P. Brooks. Oxford D.Phil. 1969.</para>
<para id="p518"><emph type="i">The relations of the Norman monasteries with their English properties during the middle ages.</emph> D.J.A. Matthew. Oxford D.Phil. 1958.</para>
<para id="p519"><emph type="i">The English priories and manors of the abbey of Bec-Hellouin.</emph> Marjorie M. Morgan. Oxford D.Phil. 1942.</para>
<para id="p520"><emph type="i">Barking abbey: a study in its external and internal administration from the Conquest to the Dissolution.</emph> Winifrid M. Sturman. London Ph.D. 1961.</para>
<para id="p521"><emph type="i">Canterbury cathedral priory: a study in monastic administration.</emph> R.A.L. Smith. Cambridge Ph.D. 1941.</para>
<para id="p522"><emph type="i">Two obedientiary rolls of Selby abbey.</emph> Mrs. Beryl Smith, <emph type="i">n&eacute;e</emph> Holt. Leeds M.A. 1949.</para>
<para id="p523"><emph type="i">Prior Dominic of Evesham and the survival of the English tradition after the Norman Conquest.</emph> J.C. Jennings. Oxford B.Litt. 1958.</para>
<para id="p524"><emph type="i">The history of the Cluniacs in England and Wales.</emph> Ethel M. Fussell. Wales M.A. 1917.</para>
<para id="p525"><emph type="i">The greater English monasteries and their knights, 1066&ndash;1215.</emph> J.D. Anderson. Oxford B.Litt. 1948.</para>
<para id="p526"><emph type="i">Odo of Ostia's history of the translation of St. Milburga and its connection with the early history of Wenlock abbey.</emph> Angela J.M. Edwards. London M.A. 1960.</para>
<para id="p527"><emph type="i"><emph type="i">Historia Eliensis</emph>, Book III.</emph> E.O. Blake. Cambridge Ph.D. 1953.</para>
<para id="p528"><emph type="i">The derivation of the English monastic office-books as seen in the core of the <emph type="i">Liber Responsalis</emph>.</emph> J.D. Brady. Cambridge M.Litt. 1963.</para>
<para id="p529"><emph type="i">A historical and archaeological account of Much Wenlock priory and its dependent churches from the earliest times to 1307.</emph> E.A. Gee. Birmingham M.A. 1937.</para>
<para id="p530"><emph type="i">The history of the Augustinian canons in England before 1215, with special reference to the spread of their foundations and their relations with the secular clergy.</emph> J.C. Dickinson. Oxford B.Litt. 1937.</para>
<page start="052"/>
<para id="p531"><emph type="i">A study of the <emph type="i">Narratio de Fundatione</emph> of Fountains abbey.</emph> L.G.D. Baker. Oxford B.Litt. 1967.</para>
<para id="p532"><emph type="i">The ecclesiastical relations of the reign of Stephen, with special reference to St. Bernard and the Cistercian reforming party, 1135&ndash;54.</emph> Margaret I. Megaw. Belfast M.A. 1939.</para>
<para id="p533"><emph type="i">The geographical significance of Cistercian foundations in England.</emph> R.A. Donkin. Durham Ph.D. 1953.</para>
<para id="p534"><emph type="i">The Cistercian movement in the north of England, with special reference to the early history of Byland abbey.</emph> Phyllis Auty. Oxford B.Litt. 1934.</para>
<para id="p535"><emph type="i">The monasteries and the medieval development of northeast Yorkshire.</emph> B.F. Waites. London M.A. 1957.</para>
<para id="p536"><emph type="i">The cartulary of the priory of Tocwith in the West Riding of Yorkshire.</emph> Gwenllian C. Ransome. Manchester M.A. 1930.</para>
<para id="p537"><emph type="i">An edition of the cartulary of Breedon priory, with introduction and critical apparatus.</emph> R.A. McKinley. Manchester M.A. 1950.</para>
<para id="p538"><emph type="i">Edition of the Kenilworth cartulary.</emph> C. Watson. London Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p539"><emph type="i">The foundation of Reading abbey and the growth of its possessions and privileges in England in the 12th century.</emph> B.R. Kemp. Reading Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p540"><emph type="i">Faversham abbey.</emph> C.R. Broughton. Durham M.A. 1952.</para>
<para id="p541"><emph type="i">The cartulary of Meaux: a critical edition.</emph> G.V. Orange. Hull Ph.D. 1964.</para>
<para id="p542"><emph type="i">An edition of the cartulary of Canonsleigh abbey (Harl. MS. 3660).</emph> Vera C.M. London. Liverpool M.A. 1962.</para>
<para id="p543"><emph type="i">Religious life for women in 12th-century canon law, with special reference to English houses.</emph> Zela M. Procter. London M.Phil. 1967.</para>
<para id="p544"><emph type="i">The history of the nunnery of St. Mary and St. Michael outside Stamford.</emph> Winifred M. Sturman. London M.A. 1944.</para>
<para id="p545"><emph type="i">An edition of the cartulary of Burscough priory.</emph> A.N. Webb. Liverpool M.A. 1966.</para>
<para id="p546"><emph type="i">Dieulacres abbey.</emph> M.J.C. Fisher. Keele M.A. 1967.</para>
<para id="p547"><emph type="i">St. Francis and England.</emph> G.R. Whitaker. Leeds M.A. 1919.</para>
<para id="p548"><emph type="i">The Franciscans in medieval English life.</emph> V. Green. Oxford B.Litt. 1936.</para>
<para id="p549"><emph type="i">Some later followers of St. Francis.</emph> Constance Mawson. Leeds M.A. 1918.</para>
<para id="p550"><emph type="i">The friars in England.</emph> Elizabeth E. Smith. Birmingham M.A. 1909.</para>
<para id="p551"><emph type="i">The work and influence of the friars in England for the first fifty years.</emph> Eulalie M. Davies. Birmingham M.A. 1915.</para>
<para id="p552"><emph type="i">Some aspects of the history of the English friars in the 13th century.</emph> W.J. Whitehouse. Birmingham M.A. 1923.</para>
<para id="p553"><emph type="i">Some political activities of the Franciscans in England in the 13th century.</emph> I.J. Sanders. Wales M.A. 1935.</para>
<para id="p554"><emph type="i">The Franciscans and Dominicans in Yorkshire.</emph> L.M. Goldthorp. Leeds M.A. 1932.</para>
<para id="p555"><emph type="i">Aelred of Rievaulx: a study of his works and of their place in Cistercian literature.</emph> K.A.J. Squire. Oxford B.Litt. 1958.</para>
<para id="p556"><emph type="i">An examination of the charges brought against the friars by Matthew Paris.</emph> Winifred Alty. Wales M.A. 1911.</para>
<para id="p557"><emph type="i">Critical edition of the cartulary of St. Gregory's priory, Canterbury.</emph> Audrey M. Murray. Oxford B.Litt. 1951.</para>
<para id="p558"><emph type="i">Edition of Blyth cartulary.</emph> R.T. Timson. London Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<para id="p559"><emph type="i">The organisation and financing of monastic building in England in the later middle ages.</emph> R.A. Smith. London M.A. 1952.</para>
<para id="p560"><emph type="i">Relations between English monasteries and their patrons in the 13th century.</emph> Susan M. Chenevix Trench. Oxford B.Litt. 1950.</para>
<page start="053"/>
<para id="p561"><emph type="i">The importance of Halesowen abbey in the life of the English people.</emph> A.G. Pound. Birmingham M.A. 1926.</para>
<para id="p562"><emph type="i">The establishment and early development of the Carmelite order in England.</emph> K.J. Egan. Cambridge Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<para id="p563"><emph type="i">A study of the nunnery of St. Mary Clerkenwell and its property with an edition of its cartulary.</emph> W.O. Hassall. Oxford D.Phil. 1941.</para>
<para id="p564"><emph type="i">Some chapters in the history of English nunneries in the later middle ages, <emph type="i">c</emph>. 1250&ndash;1535.</emph> Eileen E. Power. London M.A. 1916.</para>
<para id="p565"><emph type="i">Studies in 13th-century English Dominican history.</emph> W.A. Hinnebusch. Oxford D.Phil. 1939.</para>
<para id="p566"><emph type="i">Some secular activities of the English Dominicans during the reigns of Edward I, Edward II and Edward III (1272&ndash;1377).</emph> R.D. Clarke. London M.A. 1930.</para>
<para id="p567"><emph type="i">Monasticism in Cheshire, 1285&ndash;1377.</emph> H.J. Hewitt. Liverpool M.A. 1917.</para>
<para id="p568"><emph type="i">The development of the constitution of the Order of Preachers in the 13th and 14th centuries.</emph> Mrs. Georgina R. Galbraith. Manchester Ph.D. 1922.</para>
<para id="p569"><emph type="i">The memorandum book of Henry of Eastry, prior of Christ Church, Canterbury.</emph> T.L. Hogan. London Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p570"><emph type="i">The Order of Minoresses in England.</emph> A.F. Claudine Bourdillon. Manchester M.A. 1925.</para>
<para id="p571"><emph type="i">The relations between the mendicant friars and the secular clergy in England during the century after the issue of the bull <emph type="i">super cathedram</emph> (1300).</emph> Jean L. Copeland. London M.A. 1937.</para>
<para id="p572"><emph type="i">The Templars in England.</emph> Agnes M. Sandys. Manchester M.A. 1917.</para>
<para id="p573"><emph type="i">The fate of the Knights Templar in England, with special reference to their lands.</emph> H.I. Millard. Wales M.A. 1918.</para>
<para id="p574"><emph type="i">The organisation, personnel and functions of the medieval hospital in the later middle ages.</emph> Margaret A. Seymour. London M.A. 1946.</para>
<para id="p575"><emph type="i">Some aspects of the English Carmelites in the 15th century.</emph> Margaret E. Turner. Manchester M.A. 1933.</para>
<para id="p576"><emph type="i">The English province of the Franciscans Conventual in the 15th century.</emph> D.W. Whitfield. Bristol M.A. 1953.</para>
<para id="p577"><emph type="i">The priory of Durham in the time of John Wessington, prior 1416&ndash;46.</emph> R.B. Dobson. Oxford D.Phil. 1963.</para>
<para id="p578"><emph type="i">Henry V and the monastic orders.</emph> K.M. Keeley. Manchester M.A. 1936.</para>
<para id="p579"><emph type="i">The abbey of St. Albans under John of Whethamstede.</emph> C. Esther Hodge. Manchester Ph.D. 1933.</para>
</section>
<section id="s17">
<head>Relations with Papacy</head>
<para id="p580"><emph type="i">The jurisdiction of the papacy in cases of appeal and of first instance in England, with particular reference to the southern province, 1198&ndash;1254.</emph> Jane E. Sayers. Oxford B.Litt. 1960.</para>
<para id="p581"><emph type="i">Twelfth-century decretal collections and their importance in English history.</emph> C. Duggan. Cambridge Ph.D. 1955.</para>
<para id="p582"><emph type="i">Anglo-papal relations during the later years of the reign of King John, 1213&ndash;16.</emph> Stella M. Whileblood. Manchester M.A. 1947.</para>
<para id="p583"><emph type="i">The enforcement of the Lateran decrees in England in the reign of Henry III.</emph> Eleanor M. Lang. Oxford B.Litt. 1931.</para>
<para id="p584"><emph type="i">The legation of Cardinal Otto, 1237&ndash;41.</emph> Dorothy Williamson. Manchester M.A. 1947.</para>
<para id="p585"><emph type="i">The English activities of the Cardinal Ottobuono, legate of the Holy See.</emph> A. Lewis. Manchester M.A. 1937.</para>
<para id="p586"><emph type="i">The decretals of Gregory IX in relation to English history.</emph> P.G. Ward. Cambridge M.Litt. 1924.</para>
<page start="054"/>
<para id="p587"><emph type="i">The concordats between the Holy See and England in the 14th and 15th centuries.</emph> Mary J. George. Liverpool M.A. 1915.</para>
<para id="p588"><emph type="i">The relations between the church and the English Crown during the pontificates of Clement V and John XXII, 1305&ndash;34.</emph> J.R. Wright. Oxford D.Phil. 1967.</para>
<para id="p589"><emph type="i">England and the Great Schism of the West.</emph> Catherine M. Saum. Liverpool M.A. 1916.</para>
<para id="p590"><emph type="i">English views on reforms to be undertaken in the general councils (1400&ndash;18), with special reference to the proposals made by Richard Ullerston.</emph> Margaret M. Harvey. Oxford D.Phil. 1964.</para>
<para id="p591"><emph type="i">Some aspects of the work of the English 'nation' at the Council of Constance till the election of Martin V.</emph> C.M.D. Crowder. Oxford D.Phil. 1953.</para>
<para id="p592"><emph type="i">England and the Council of Basel.</emph> A.N.E.D. Schofield. London Ph.D. 1957.</para>
<para id="p593"><emph type="i">The English notaries at the papal curia in the early 15th century, with special reference to William Swan.</emph> Mrs. Dorothy Newell. Manchester Ph.D. 1934.</para>
</section>
</section>
<section id="s18">
<head>INTELLECTUAL LIFE AND SCHOLARSHIP</head>
<para id="p594"><emph type="i">A study of the history of optics from ancient times to the end of the 13th century.</emph> N.E. Woodcock. Exeter M.A. 1969.</para>
<para id="p595"><emph type="i">A history of the teaching of physics in England up to 1650.</emph> G.D. Bishop. London M.A. 1956.</para>
<para id="p596"><emph type="i">A study of mathematical methods in England to the 13th century.</emph> Florence A. Yeldham. London Ph.D. 1931.</para>
<para id="p597"><emph type="i">History of the Vulgate in England from Alcuin to Roger Bacon.</emph> H.H. Glunz. Cambridge Ph.D. 1931/2.</para>
<para id="p598"><emph type="i">Greek quotations in Anglo-Saxon writings.</emph> Annie Anderson. Oxford B.Litt. 1921.</para>
<para id="p599"><emph type="i">The authenticity of Asser's Life of Alfred.</emph> Mrs. Rosalind M. Lavington. Manchester M.A. 1969.</para>
<para id="p600"><emph type="i">Aelfric's 'Catholic Homilies', first series: the text and manuscript tradition.</emph> P.A.M. Clemoes. Cambridge Ph.D. 1956.</para>
<para id="p601"><emph type="i">A critical edition of the Handboc or Enchiridion of Byrhtferth.</emph> S.J. Crawford. Oxford D.Phil. 1929/30.</para>
<para id="p602"><emph type="i">Guthlac: an edition of the Old English prose life, together with the poems in the Exeter Book.</emph> Jane A. Crawford. Oxford D.Phil. 1967.</para>
<para id="p603"><emph type="i">The influence of bishops and of members of cathedral bodies in the intellectual life of England, 1066&ndash;1216.</emph> Eleanor Rathbone. London Ph.D. 1936.</para>
<para id="p604"><emph type="i">The place of Archbishop Lanfranc in 11th-century scholastic development.</emph> Margaret T. Gibson. Oxford D.Phil. 1967.</para>
<para id="p605"><emph type="i">Anglo-Norman political songs.</emph> Isabel S.T. Aspin. Oxford B.Litt. 1950.</para>
<para id="p606"><emph type="i">The <emph type="i">Vita Wulfstani</emph> of William of Malmesbury.</emph> R.R. Darlington. Reading Ph.D. 1929/30.</para>
<para id="p607"><emph type="i">A study of the <emph type="i">Tractatus Eboracenses</emph>.</emph> Ruth C. Nineham. Oxford B.Litt. 1951.</para>
<para id="p608"><emph type="i">Literary activity in the old English Benedictine houses during the 12th century.</emph> Mother Norah Lester. Newcastle M.Litt. 1967.</para>
<para id="p609"><emph type="i">Biblical commentators of the 12th and 13th centuries, viewed as historical material and with special reference to Stephen Langton.</emph> Beryl Smalley. Manchester Ph.D. 1929.</para>
<para id="p610"><emph type="i">Manuscripts and commentaries on Boethius <emph type="i">De Consolatione Philosophiae</emph> in England in the middle ages.</emph> Diane K. Bolton. Oxford B.Litt. 1966.</para>
<page start="055"/>
<para id="p611"><emph type="i">A critical edition of the text of the letters of John of Salisbury.</emph> W.J. Millor. London Ph.D. 1939.</para>
<para id="p612"><emph type="i">Early medieval humanism, as exemplified in the life and writings of John of Salisbury.</emph> H. Liebeschuetz. London M.A. (Ext.) 1947.</para>
<para id="p613"><emph type="i">John of Salisbury's <emph type="i">Entheticus de dogmate philosophorum</emph>: the light it throws on the educational background of the 12th century.</emph> C.R. Elrington. London M.A. 1954.</para>
<para id="p614"><emph type="i">John of Salisbury and the Becket conference.</emph> Sybil V. Lumb. Leeds M.A. 1920.</para>
<para id="p615"><emph type="i">Learning and literature of English Cistercians, 1167&ndash;1214, with special reference to John of Ford.</emph> C.J. Holdsworth. Cambridge Ph.D. 1960.</para>
<para id="p616"><emph type="i">A study of private book collections in England between <emph type="i">c</emph>. 1200 and the early years of the 16th century, with special reference to books belonging to ecclesiastical dignitaries.</emph> R.H. Bartle. Oxford B.Litt. 1957.</para>
<para id="p617"><emph type="i">A contribution to the study of French as taught in England, 13th to 15th centuries.</emph> Jennifer Nicholson. London Ph.D. 1936.</para>
<para id="p618"><emph type="i">The value of the romance of Fulk and Fitzwarren as a source for 13th-century English history.</emph> G.G. Stephenson. Oxford B.Litt. 1953.</para>
<para id="p619"><emph type="i">An edition of some later letters of Peter of Blois (written while he was archdeacon of London) from MS. Erfurt Amplonianus F. 71.</emph> Margaret E. Reveil. Oxford B.Litt. 1958.</para>
<para id="p620"><emph type="i">The teaching of grammar in England in the later middle ages.</emph> J.N.T. Miner. London Ph.D. 1959.</para>
<para id="p621"><emph type="i">The Mendicants and English education in the 13th century.</emph> Ivy H. Tolley. London M.A. 1924.</para>
<para id="p622"><emph type="i">The problem of the plurality of forms at the University of Oxford in the 13th century.</emph> D.A.P. Callus. Oxford D.Phil. 1938.</para>
<para id="p623"><emph type="i">English canonists in the later middle ages: a historical, biographical and literary study.</emph> K.R.N.St.J. Wykeham-George. Oxford B.Litt. 1937.</para>
<para id="p624"><emph type="i">William de Montibus.</emph> H. Mackinnon. Oxford D.Phil. 1959.</para>
<para id="p625"><emph type="i">Robert of Orford and his place in the scholastic controversies at Oxford in the late 13th century, with an edition of his <emph type="i">Reprobationes</emph> of Giles of Rome.</emph> A.P. Vella. Oxford B.Litt. 1946.</para>
<para id="p626"><emph type="i">Robert Winchelsea and his place in the intellectual movement of 13th-century Oxford, with an edition of his Quaestiones in MS. Magdalen College, Oxford 217.</emph> A.J.C. Smith. Oxford B.Litt. 1953.</para>
<para id="p627"><emph type="i">Thomas Sutton's place in the development of Aristotelianism and Thomism at Oxford in the last quarter of the 13th century.</emph> F.M.E. Kelley. Oxford B.Litt. 1966.</para>
<para id="p628"><emph type="i">Studies in the life and philosophy of Robert Kilwardby.</emph> Eleonore Sommer. Cambridge Ph.D. 1935/6.</para>
<para id="p629"><emph type="i">A study of the writings of William Rothwell, a 13th-century Dominican.</emph> J.J.H. Martin. Oxford B.Litt. 1960.</para>
<para id="p630"><emph type="i">Schools and education in Gloucestershire and the neighbouring counties from 1280 until the Reformation.</emph> N.I. Orme. Oxford D.Phil. 1969.</para>
<para id="p631"><emph type="i">The use of Anglo-Norman in private and public documents of the 14th and 15th centuries.</emph> Helen Richardson. Oxford B.Litt. 1939.</para>
<para id="p632"><emph type="i">A study of certain kinds of scripts used in England in the late 14th and 15th centuries, and the origins of the 'Tudor Secretary' hand.</emph> M.B. Parkes. Oxford B.Litt. 1959.</para>
<para id="p633"><emph type="i">An Anglo-Norman metrical 'Brut' of the 14th century.</emph> V.P. Underwood. London Ph.D. 1937.</para>
<para id="p634"><emph type="i">A study of the English mystics of the 14th century, with special reference to the writings of Richard Rolle of Hampole.</emph> W.B. Brash. Oxford B.Litt. 1918.</para>
<page start="056"/>
<para id="p635"><emph type="i">The <emph type="i">Incendium Amoris</emph> of Richard Rolle of Hampole.</emph> Margaret Deanesly. Manchester M.A. 1915.</para>
<para id="p636"><emph type="i">The philosophic character of English 14th-century mysticism.</emph> J. Short. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1929.</para>
<para id="p637"><emph type="i">Early 14th-century physics of the Merton School with special reference to Dumbleton and Heytesbury.</emph> J.A. Weisheipl. Oxford D.Phil. 1957.</para>
<para id="p638"><emph type="i">Alexander Neckam.</emph> R.W. Hunt. Oxford D.Phil. 1936.</para>
<para id="p639"><emph type="i">Life and works of Odo of Cheriton.</emph> A.C. Friend. Oxford D. Phil. 1936.</para>
<para id="p640"><emph type="i">Roger Bacon.</emph> W.H. Johnson. Birmingham M.A. 1913.</para>
<para id="p641"><emph type="i">The life and writings of Adam of Buckfield, with special reference to his commentary on the <emph type="i">De Anima</emph> of Aristotle.</emph> Helen Powell. Oxford B.Litt. 1964.</para>
<para id="p642"><emph type="i">A study of Thomas Bradwardine's <emph type="i">De Causa Dei</emph> and its relation to contemporary Oxford thought.</emph> G. Leff. Cambridge Ph.D. 1955.</para>
<para id="p643"><emph type="i">A study of some Oxford schoolmen of the middle of the 14th century, with special reference to Worcester Cathedral MS. F. 65.</emph> S.L. Forte. Oxford B.Litt. 1947.</para>
<para id="p644"><emph type="i">The influence of the religious literature of Germany and the Low Countries on English spirituality <emph type="i">c</emph>. 1350&ndash;1475.</emph> R.W. Lovatt. Oxford D.Phil. 1965.</para>
<para id="p645"><emph type="i"><emph type="i">Piers Plowman</emph> as a work of moral theology.</emph> Grethe Hjort. Cambridge Ph.D. 1931/2.</para>
<para id="p646"><emph type="i">A study of John Wyclif's <emph type="i">Summa de Ente</emph> and its relation to contemporary Oxford philosophy.</emph> J.A. Robson. Cambridge Ph.D. 1958.</para>
<para id="p647"><emph type="i">A study of John Wyclif's treatise <emph type="i">De Mandatis Divinis</emph>.</emph> J.F. McCristal. Oxford B.Litt. 1958.</para>
<para id="p648"><emph type="i">William Woodford, O.F.M., <emph type="i">c</emph>. 1330-<emph type="i">c</emph>. 1397.</emph> R.J.A.I. Catto. Oxford D.Phil. 1969.</para>
<para id="p649"><emph type="i">English Benedictines in the century preceding the Dissolution, with special reference to their connexion with the universities and with learning.</emph> Winifred D. Coates. Oxford B.Litt. 1931.</para>
<para id="p650"><emph type="i">John of Bromyard.</emph> Catherine Houlihan. Birmingham M.A. 1959.</para>
<para id="p651"><emph type="i">The teaching and study of arts in the University of Oxford <emph type="i">c</emph>. 1400-<emph type="i">c</emph>. 1520.</emph> J.M. Fletcher. Oxford D.Phil. 1961.</para>
<para id="p652"><emph type="i">The constitutions for the promotion of university graduates, 1417&ndash;38.</emph> J. Flitcroft. Manchester M.A. 1937.</para>
<para id="p653"><emph type="i">Humanism in England during the 15th century up to 1485.</emph> R. Weiss. Oxford D.Phil. 1938.</para>
<para id="p654"><emph type="i">Studies in intellectual life in England from the middle of the 15th century till the time of Colet.</emph> Naomi D. Hurnard. Oxford D.Phil. 1935.</para>
<para id="p655"><emph type="i">The life and works of Thomas Gascoigne.</emph> Winifred A. Pronger. Oxford B.Litt. 1932.</para>
<para id="p656"><emph type="i">The early history and organisation of the King's Hall, Cambridge.</emph> A.B. Cobban. Cambridge Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<para id="p657"><emph type="i">'The Equatorie of the Planetis', edited from Peterhouse MS. 75. 1.</emph> D.J. Price. Cambridge Ph.D. 1954.</para>
<para id="p658"><emph type="i">Thomas Chaundler.</emph> Shirley F. Bridges. Oxford B.Litt. 1949.</para>
<para id="p659"><emph type="i">William Caxton and Burgundy: a study of political and cultural relations in the late 15th century.</emph> Margaret L. Kekewich. London M.A. 1963.</para>
<para id="p660"><emph type="i">A biographical study of William Caxton, with special reference to his life and work in the Low Countries.</emph> W.J.B. Crotch. London M.A. 1927.</para>
<page start="057"/>
</section>
<section id="s19">
<head>ART, ARCHITECTURE AND ARCHAEOLOGY</head>
<para id="p661"><emph type="i">The survival and rediscovery of Egyptian antiquities in western Europe from late antiquity until the close of the 16th century.</emph> Anne H.M. Roullet. Oxford D.Phil. 1969.</para>
<para id="p662"><emph type="i">Celtic art in north Britain before A.D. 400.</emph> Mrs. Morna Simpson. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1965/6.</para>
<para id="p663"><emph type="i">The historical significance of Dark Age Celtic metal-work in the British Isles.</emph> Mrs. Elizabeth Fowler. Oxford B.Litt. 1962.</para>
<para id="p664"><emph type="i">Some aspects of Old English vocabulary in the light of recent archaeological evidence.</emph> Rosemary J. Cramp. Oxford B.Litt. 1958.</para>
<para id="p665"><emph type="i">The site of Ad Gefrin: an investigation of its archaeological and historical significance.</emph> B.K. Hope-Taylor. Cambridge Ph.D. 1961.</para>
<para id="p666"><emph type="i">The Anglo-Saxon cemetery at Loveden hill, Hough-on-the-Hill, Lincolnshire, and its significance in relation to Dark Age settlement of the eastern Midlands.</emph> K.R. Fennell. Nottingham Ph.D. 1964.</para>
<para id="p667"><emph type="i">The cemeteries at Barrington and Haslingfield in relation to the Anglo-Saxon settlement of England.</emph> Patricia Hilton. Leeds Ph.D. 1961/2.</para>
<para id="p668"><emph type="i">The Saxon and medieval palaces at Cheddar.</emph> P.A. Rahtz. Bristol M.A. 1964.</para>
<para id="p669"><emph type="i">Anglo-Saxon churches of Durham and Northumberland.</emph> E.C. Gilbert. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1954.</para>
<para id="p670"><emph type="i">The saucer brooch and its significance in Anglo-Saxon England.</emph> Mrs. Margaret Saunders. Oxford B.Litt. 1958.</para>
<para id="p671"><emph type="i">The spear in Anglo-Saxon times.</emph> M.J. Swanton. Durham Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p672"><emph type="i">The inscriptions on Anglo-Saxon rune stones.</emph> R.I. Page. Nottingham Ph.D. 1959.</para>
<para id="p673"><emph type="i">Some leading types of the Anglian province of culture, 5th to 7th century A.D., with their overseas connexions.</emph> H.E.-F. Vierck. Oxford B.Litt. 1967.</para>
<para id="p674"><emph type="i">Anglo-Saxon non-runic inscriptions.</emph> Elisabeth Barty. Cambridge Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p675"><emph type="i">The sculpture of Cumberland in the Anglo-Saxon period: a survey and historical introduction.</emph> R.N. Bailey. Durham M.A. 1959.</para>
<para id="p676"><emph type="i">Anglo-Saxon decorative metalwork from Baginton, Warwickshire.</emph> J.B. Hicks. Birmingham M.A. 1957.</para>
<para id="p677"><emph type="i">An architectural and documentary study of town defences in England and Wales, 1087&ndash;1520.</emph> Hilary L. Turner. Oxford D.Phil. 1968.</para>
<para id="p678"><emph type="i">The excavation of the old church of Perranzabuloe.</emph> T.F.G. Dexter. St. Andrews Ph.D. 1922.</para>
<para id="p679"><emph type="i">Minor medieval monumental sculpture of the east Midlands.</emph> L.A.S. Butler. Nottingham Ph.D. 1961.</para>
<para id="p680"><emph type="i">Norman domestic architecture in England.</emph> Margaret E. Wood. London M.A. 1934.</para>
<para id="p681"><emph type="i">The Canterbury school of illumination (1066&ndash;1200).</emph> C.R. Dodwell. Cambridge Ph.D. 1951.</para>
<para id="p682"><emph type="i">Medieval painted glass in England, 1170&ndash;1501.</emph> P. Nelson. Liverpool Ph.D. 1930.</para>
<para id="p683"><emph type="i">Schools of glass-painting in the Midlands, 1275&ndash;1430.</emph> P.A. Newton. London Ph.D. 1962.</para>
<para id="p684"><emph type="i">Regional schools in English sculpture in the 12th century.</emph> G. Zarnecki. London Ph.D. 1951.</para>
<para id="p685"><emph type="i">The decoration of Norman baptismal fonts in relation to English 12th-century sculpture.</emph> Ren&eacute;e Marcous&eacute;. London Ph.D. 1940.</para>
<para id="p686"><emph type="i">The scriptorium of Bury St. Edmunds in the 12th century.</emph> Elizabeth Parker. London Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<para id="p687"><emph type="i">The king's master masons, 1245&ndash;1515.</emph> B.G. Morgan. Liverpool Ph.D. 1957/8.</para>
<page start="058"/>
<para id="p688"><emph type="i">Contributions to the development of English medieval architecture based largely on a first-hand study of various monuments in Oxford.</emph> G.P. Brookfield. Oxford B.Litt. 1925.</para>
<para id="p689"><emph type="i">A study of medieval timber-framed construction based on Worcestershire.</emph> F.W.B. Charles. Liverpool M.A. 1962/3.</para>
<para id="p690"><emph type="i">The fabric rolls of Exeter cathedral.</emph> D.F. Findlay. Leeds Ph.D. 1939.</para>
<para id="p691"><emph type="i">MS. K. 26 in the library of St. John's College, Cambridge: a study of the style and iconography of its 13th-century illustrations.</emph> G.D.S. Henderson. Cambridge Ph.D. 1960.</para>
<para id="p692"><emph type="i">The development of armour and costume from the 14th century to the 17th century as illustrated in the memorial brasses of Essex.</emph> A.C. Edwards. Bristol M.A. 1937.</para>
<para id="p693"><emph type="i">The collegiate architecture of Oxford, from the late 14th century to the early 16th century.</emph> E.A. Gee. Oxford D.Phil. 1950.</para>
<para id="p694"><emph type="i">Figure paintings on rood screens in the churches of Norfolk and south Devonshire.</emph> Audrey M. Baker. London Ph.D. 1938.</para>
<para id="p695"><emph type="i">East Anglian church architecture of the 14th and 15th centuries, with special reference to the churches of the Stour valley.</emph> Cora J. Ough. London M.A. 1939.</para>
<para id="p696"><emph type="i">English medieval alabaster carvings.</emph> P. Nelson. Liverpool M.A. 1924.</para>
<para id="p697"><emph type="i">The use of plant-motives in marginalia of English illuminated manuscripts of the 14th and 15th centuries.</emph> Alice M. Houghton. Manchester M.A. 1942.</para>
<para id="p698"><emph type="i">St. Stephen's Chapel and the architecture of the 14th century in London.</emph> J.M. Hastings. Cambridge Ph.D. 1946/7.</para>
<para id="p699"><emph type="i">Exeter houses, 1400&ndash;1700.</emph> D. Portman. Exeter Ph.D. 1962.</para>
<para id="p700"><emph type="i">Some late medieval fortified manor-houses: a study of the building works of Sir John Fastolf, Ralph, Lord Cromwell, and Edward Stafford, 3rd duke of Buckingham.</emph> A.D.K. Hawkyard. Keele M.A. 1969.</para>
</section>
<section id="s20">
<head>LOCAL HISTORY</head>
<para id="p701"><emph type="i">The occupation of the counties Northumberland, Durham, Cumberland and Westmorland from the 4th to the 8th centuries, as revealed by the archaeological and historical evidence.</emph> G.S. Keeney. Oxford B.Litt. 1935.</para>
<para id="p702"><emph type="i">An analysis of the dwelling sites established in Cornwall and Devon between the 5th and the 11th centuries, and their contribution to the modern settlement pattern.</emph> W.L.D. Ravenhill. London Ph.D. 1957.</para>
<para id="p703"><emph type="i">Britain in the 5th century: a survey of the archaeological and literary evidence.</emph> Alison Birch. London M.A. 1954.</para>
<para id="p704"><emph type="i">The early Saxon occupation of Essex, with particular reference to the settlement at Mucking.</emph> Mrs. Barbara J. Kinnes, <emph type="i">n&eacute;e</emph> Thomas. Leeds M.Phil. 1969.</para>
<para id="p705"><emph type="i">The Anglo-Saxon settlement of Warwickshire.</emph> Helen A. Maynard. Birmingham M.A. 1970.</para>
<para id="p706"><emph type="i">A study of the place-names of the pre-Conquest Kentish charters.</emph> T.E.A. Acum. London M.A. 1923.</para>
<para id="p707"><emph type="i">Somersetshire charters to A.D. 900.</emph> E.E. Barker. London M.A. (Ext.) 1961.</para>
<para id="p708"><emph type="i">Pre-Domesday geography in northern Berkshire.</emph> M. Staveley. Reading M.A. 1965.</para>
<para id="p709"><emph type="i">The development of rural settlement in the Isle of Wight before 1086.</emph> Christine Sibbit. Leicester M.A. 1967.</para>
<para id="p710"><emph type="i">The growth of self-government in the borough of Southampton as illustrated by its charters and letters patent.</emph> H.W. Gidden. London Ph.D. 1923.</para>
<page start="059"/>
<para id="p711"><emph type="i">The importance of Winchester as the capital of England from the 10th to the 12th century.</emph> P. Meadows. London M.A. 1911.</para>
<para id="p712"><emph type="i">The medieval history of St. James's, Bristol.</emph> F.W.P. Hicks. Bristol M.A. 1932.</para>
<para id="p713"><emph type="i">A short history of the growth of Redcliffe.</emph> G. Holgate. Bristol M.A. 1934.</para>
<para id="p714"><emph type="i">The manor of Writtle, Essex, <emph type="i">c</emph>. 1086-<emph type="i">c</emph>. 1500.</emph> K.C. Newton. Leicester M.A. 1967.</para>
<para id="p715"><emph type="i">Medieval Newcastle-under-Lyme.</emph> T. Pape. Manchester M.A. 1926.</para>
<para id="p716"><emph type="i">The social structure of the English shires on the Welsh border between the Norman Conquest and the 14th century.</emph> Margaret U. Apps. Leeds Ph.D. 1944.</para>
<para id="p717"><emph type="i">Shrewsbury - topography and domestic architecture to the middle of the 17th century.</emph> J.T. Smith. Birmingham M.A. 1953.</para>
<para id="p718"><emph type="i">The medieval borough of Shrewsbury.</emph> J.G. Speake. Wales M.A. 1939.</para>
<para id="p719"><emph type="i">Some aspects of the history of the lordship of Oswestry to 1300 A.D.</emph> D.C. Roberts. Wales M.A. 1939.</para>
<para id="p720"><emph type="i">Kenilworth castle and priory.</emph> Edith N. Wells. Birmingham M.A. 1923.</para>
<para id="p721"><emph type="i">A study of Plymouth.</emph> Margaret I. Lattimore. Exeter M.A. 1958.</para>
<para id="p722"><emph type="i">The hundred of Leyland after the Conquest.</emph> F. Jackson. Liverpool M.A. 1913.</para>
<para id="p723"><emph type="i">The history of Bromsgrove in the medieval and early Tudor period, 1066&ndash;1533.</emph> R.M. Haines. Durham M.A. 1948.</para>
<para id="p724"><emph type="i">The manor of Spofforth.</emph> E.J. Fisher. Leeds M.A. 1933.</para>
<para id="p725"><emph type="i">Bradford dale: the history and descent of some manors in the neighbourhood of Bradford.</emph> W. Robertshaw. Leeds M.A. 1935.</para>
<para id="p726"><emph type="i">The early history of the manor and parish of Bradford, W. Riding, Yorks.</emph> H.I. Judson. London M.A. 1933.</para>
<para id="p727"><emph type="i">The history of the parish of Phillack.</emph> J.H. Rowe. Leeds M.A. 1931.</para>
<para id="p728"><emph type="i">A survey of the history of Bosley.</emph> R.W. Lloyd-Jones. Liverpool M.A. 1943.</para>
<para id="p729"><emph type="i">The history of the manor of Islip from 1066 until the Dissolution.</emph> Barbara F. Harvey. Oxford B.Litt. 1953.</para>
<para id="p730"><emph type="i">The manor of Headington.</emph> Evangeline Evans. Oxford B.Litt. 1927.</para>
<para id="p731"><emph type="i">The honor of Leicester: a study in descent and administration, with special reference to the Leicestershire fees of the honor.</emph> L. Fox. Manchester M.A. 1938.</para>
<para id="p732"><emph type="i">The economic organisation of the medieval borough, with special reference to Leicester and its guild merchants.</emph> E.H. Smith. Wales M.A. 1912.</para>
<para id="p733"><emph type="i">Early rentals and charters relating to the borough of Canterbury.</emph> W.G. Urry. London Ph.D. 1956.</para>
<para id="p734"><emph type="i">A history of the manors of Witney and Adderbury from the 13th to the 16th century.</emph> Mrs. Patricia G.M. Hyde. Oxford B.Litt. 1955.</para>
<para id="p735"><emph type="i">The history of Cuxham (co. Oxon.) with special reference to social and economic conditions during the middle ages.</emph> P.D.A. Harvey. Oxford D.Phil. 1960.</para>
<para id="p736"><emph type="i">The medieval borough of Henley. (1) Its history. (2) Its constitution.</emph> Phyllis M. Briers. Oxford B.Litt. 1935.</para>
<para id="p737"><emph type="i">The economic and social structure of the parishes of Bromley, Hackney, Stepney and Whitechapel from the 13th to the 16th century.</emph> K.G.T. McDonnell. London Ph.D. 1958.</para>
<para id="p738"><emph type="i">An edition of the Lincolnshire final concords for the reign of John, 1199&ndash;1216.</emph> Margaret S. Rogers. Reading M.A. 1951.</para>
<para id="p739"><emph type="i">Feet of fines of Warwickshire and Leicestershire for the reign of King John, 1199&ndash;1214.</emph> Margaret O. Harris. Reading M.A. 1956.</para>
<page start="060"/>
<para id="p740"><emph type="i">An edition of the feet of fines of the reign of John.</emph> G.M.D. Croton. Reading M.A. 1955.</para>
<para id="p741"><emph type="i">Alciston manor, Sussex, in the later middle ages.</emph> Judith Wooldridge. Bristol M.A. 1965.</para>
<para id="p742"><emph type="i">The manors of Great and Little Wymondley in the later middle ages.</emph> F.B. Stitt. Oxford B.Litt. 1951.</para>
<para id="p743"><emph type="i">The earls and earldom of Chester to 1254.</emph> A.B. Targett. Wales M.A. 1913.</para>
<para id="p744"><emph type="i">The chancery of the Anglo-Norman earls of Chester.</emph> A.P. Duggan. Liverpool M.A. 1951.</para>
<para id="p745"><emph type="i">A study of the earldom of Hereford in the 12th century, with an appendix of illustrative documents.</emph> D.G. Walker. Oxford D.Phil. 1954.</para>
<para id="p746"><emph type="i">A study of the administration of the Channel Islands in the 13th and early 14th centuries based mainly upon the assize rolls and other unprinted documents.</emph> J.H. Le Patourel. Oxford D.Phil. 1934.</para>
<para id="p747"><emph type="i">North Lancashire, its economic condition in the 13th and 14th centuries.</emph> H. Horton. Manchester M.A. 1949.</para>
<para id="p748"><emph type="i">Social and constitutional developments in 13th-century London: a study in social tendency.</emph> G.A. Williams. Wales M.A. 1952.</para>
<para id="p749"><emph type="i">London, 1216&ndash;1337: a study of the main factors in the social and constitutional development of the city.</emph> G.A. Williams. London Ph.D. 1960.</para>
<para id="p750"><emph type="i">The correspondence of the City of London, 1298&ndash;1370.</emph> G.F. Chappie. London Ph.D. 1938.</para>
<para id="p751"><emph type="i">Burgage tenure in medieval Bristol.</emph> E.W.W. Veale. London LL.D. 1931.</para>
<para id="p752"><emph type="i">The administration of Cheshire in the 13th and early 14th century.</emph> Margaret Tout. Manchester M.A. 1919.</para>
<para id="p753"><emph type="i">Contributions to the history of the earldom and county of Chester, 1237&ndash;1399, historical, topographical and administrative, with a study of the household of Edward the Black Prince and its relations with Cheshire.</emph> Mrs. Margaret Sharp, <emph type="i">n&eacute;e</emph> Tout. Manchester Ph.D. 1925.</para>
<para id="p754"><emph type="i">The economic and social history of Cheshire in the reign of the three Edwards.</emph> H.J. Hewitt. London Ph.D. 1926.</para>
<para id="p755"><emph type="i">The administration of the counties of Norfolk and Suffolk in the reign of Henry IV.</emph> G.E. Morey. London M.A. 1941.</para>
<para id="p756"><emph type="i">The honour of Tutbury in the 14th and 15th centuries.</emph> Jean R. Birrell. Birmingham M.A. 1962.</para>
<para id="p757"><emph type="i">The court rolls of Alrewas in the 14th century.</emph> Mrs. Christine Kelly. Durham M.A. 1970.</para>
<para id="p758"><emph type="i">Some aspects of the economy of York in the later middle ages, 1300&ndash;1550.</emph> J.N. Bartlett. London Ph.D. 1958.</para>
<para id="p759"><emph type="i">Beverley Minster, government and society, 1381&ndash;1540.</emph> N. Heard. Hull Ph.D. 1962.</para>
<para id="p760"><emph type="i">The history of the borough of Great Yarmouth in the 14th century.</emph> Iris M. Nunn. Leeds M.A. 1931.</para>
<para id="p761"><emph type="i">Colchester and the countryside in the 14th century: a search for interdependence between urban and rural economy.</emph> R.H. Britnell. Cambridge Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p762"><emph type="i">The economic geography of Sussex during the 14th century, with special reference to the county's relations with lands across the sea.</emph> R.A. Pelham. Wales M.A. 1930.</para>
<para id="p763"><emph type="i">The social and economic history of Flixton in South Elmham, Suffolk, 1300&ndash;1600.</emph> J.M. Ridgard. Leicester M.A. 1970.</para>
<para id="p764"><emph type="i">A history of Clare, Suffolk, with special reference to its development as a borough during the middle ages, and to its importance as a centre of the woollen industry in the 15th, 16th and 17th centuries.</emph> Gladys A. Thornton. London Ph.D. 1927.</para>
<page start="061"/>
<para id="p765"><emph type="i">The decay of the manorial system during the first half of the 15th century, with special reference to manorial jurisdiction and to the decline of villeinage as exemplified in the records of twenty-six manors in the counties of Berks., Hants and Wilts.</emph> Lucy C. Latham. London M.A. 1928.</para>
<para id="p766"><emph type="i">King's Lynn, 1400&ndash;1600: developments in civic government.</emph> E.C. Glover. London M.Phil. 1970.</para>
<para id="p767"><emph type="i">The government of London and its relations with the Crown, 1400&ndash;50.</emph> Mrs. Caroline M. Barron. London Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p768"><emph type="i">Some aspects of parish life in the City of London from 1429 to 1529.</emph> E.G. Ashby. London M.A. 1950</para>
<para id="p769"><emph type="i">Personnel for the administration of Cambridgeshire in the reign of Henry VI.</emph> A.F. Bottomley. London M.A. 1952.</para>
<para id="p770"><emph type="i">The lordship of Middleham, especially in Yorkish and early Tudor times.</emph> Mrs. Gladys M. Coles. Liverpool M.A. 1961.</para>
<para id="p771"><emph type="i">The topography of medieval Oxford.</emph> D.A.M. Sturdy. Oxford B.Litt. 1965.</para>
<para id="p772"><emph type="i">The assessionable manors of the duchy of Cornwall in the later middle ages.</emph> M.J.J.R. Hatcher. London Ph.D. 1967.</para>
</section>
</section>
</report>
