<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="154857" pubid="1512" publish="true">
<title>Medieval Ireland</title>
<subtitle></subtitle>
<section id="s1">
<head>MEDIEVAL IRELAND</head>
<para id="p1"><emph type="i">Ships and shipping in ancient and medieval Ireland.</emph> J.E. O'Neill. Belfast M.A. 1934.</para>
<para id="p2"><emph type="i">A descriptive and bibliographical list of Irish figure sculptures of the early Christian period, with a critical assessment of their significance.</emph> E.H.L. Sexton. Oxford B.Litt. 1940.</para>
<para id="p3"><emph type="i">S. Finnian of Clonard.</emph> Kathleen W. Hughes. London Ph.D. 1951.</para>
<para id="p4"><emph type="i">St. Columban.</emph> G.S.M. Walker. St. Andrews Ph.D. 1952/3.</para>
<para id="p5"><emph type="i">The F&iacute;s Adamn&aacute;m: a comparative study.</emph> J.J. Colwell. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1952.</para>
<para id="p6"><emph type="i">The Saxon element in early Irish history.</emph> Anne M. Scarre. Liverpool M.A. 1908.</para>
<para id="p7"><emph type="i">The decline of the native Irish monasticism from the 9th to the 12th centuries.</emph> R.B. Knox. Belfast M.A. 1944.</para>
<para id="p8"><emph type="i">The Irish druids.</emph> Christine Standing. Leeds M.A. 1916.</para>
<para id="p9"><emph type="i">The contacts between Britain and Ireland in the century preceding the Anglo-Norman invasion of Ireland.</emph> Brigid A. Fitzgerald. Keele M.A. 1966.</para>
<para id="p10"><emph type="i">The Cistercians in Ireland and their economy, 1142&ndash;1541.</emph> S.A. Geraldine Carville. Belfast M.A. 1969.</para>
<para id="p11"><emph type="i">A history of Waterford: its life and government from 1150 to 1800.</emph> F.C. Morris. Wales M.A. 1915.</para>
<para id="p12"><emph type="i">A study of the English dialects of Ireland, 1172&ndash;1800.</emph> P.J. Irwin. London Ph.D. 1935.</para>
<para id="p13"><emph type="i">An investigation into the history of the use of English in Ireland in medieval times, with special reference to the nature of the dialects and the influence of standard English.</emph> J.J. Hogan. Oxford B.Litt. 1926.</para>
<para id="p14"><emph type="i">The medieval Irish parliament.</emph> Helen Scott. London M.A. 1914.</para>
<para id="p15"><emph type="i">The De Burgh earls of Ulster.</emph> Olga F. Lamont. Belfast M.A. 1947.</para>
<para id="p16"><emph type="i">English law and its administration in Ireland <emph type="i">c</emph>.1290 to <emph type="i">c</emph>.1324, with special reference to the court of the justiciar.</emph> G.J. Hand. Oxford D.Phil. 1960.</para>
<para id="p17"><emph type="i">An essay introductory to the <emph type="i">De Pauperie Salvatoris</emph> of Richard Fitzralph, archbishop of Armagh, with transcript of books V, VI, VII of the <emph type="i">De Pauperie Salvatoris</emph>.</emph> Helen C. Hughes. Manchester Ph.D. 1929.</para>
<page start="066"/>
<para id="p18"><emph type="i">The council in Ireland, 1399&ndash;1452.</emph> Margaret C. Griffith. Oxford B.Litt. 1935.</para>
<para id="p19"><emph type="i">A study in the structure and history of the registers of Archbishops Prene and Mey, together with an edition of the register of Mey and a calendar of the register of Prene.</emph> W.G.H. Qui&gacute;ley and E.F.D. Roberts. Belfast Ph.D. 1955.</para>
</section>
</report>
