<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="154851" pubid="1512" publish="true">
<title>Ancient History</title>
<subtitle></subtitle>
<section id="s1">
<head>ANCIENT HISTORY</head>
<section id="s2">
<head>GENERAL</head>
<para id="p1"><emph type="i">Climate in Roman times, with special reference to theories of great climatic changes since then.</emph> T.W. McDougall. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1956.</para>
<para id="p2"><emph type="i">Money and monetary policy in early times.</emph> A.R. Burns. London Ph.D. 1926.</para>
<para id="p3"><emph type="i">Land transport in the Mediterranean in pre-Roman times.</emph> G. Kellett. London M.A. 1963.</para>
<para id="p4"><emph type="i">An historical account of beekeeping in Greece and Rome during the classical period.</emph> H.M. Fraser. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1930.</para>
<para id="p5"><emph type="i">Quaestiones hydraulicae.</emph> E.J.A. Kenny. Cambridge M.Litt. 1935/6.</para>
<para id="p6"><emph type="i">Archery in the ancient world, with special reference to Greece.</emph> D.J.F. Hill. Leeds Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p7"><emph type="i">Archery in the Roman world.</emph> D.J.F. Hill. Durham M.A. 1954.</para>
<para id="p8"><emph type="i">Milling and baking techniques in the Greek and Roman world in classical antiquity.</emph> L.A. Moritz. Oxford D.Phil. 1954.</para>
<para id="p9"><emph type="i">The historical geography of Bithynia, Paphlagonia, and Pontus in the Greek and Roman periods: a new survey, with particular reference to surface remains still visible.</emph> D.R. Wilson. Oxford B.Litt. 1961.</para>
<para id="p10"><emph type="i">The catapult: a survey of the role and importance of ancient artillery in military and general history between 400 and 10 B.C.</emph> E.W. Marsden. Cambridge Ph.D. 1955.</para>
<para id="p11"><emph type="i">Ancient mining in Spain.</emph> Annie O'Donovan. Cambridge M.Litt. 1934/5.</para>
</section>
<section id="s3">
<head>ANCIENT GREECE</head>
<para id="p12"><emph type="i">Mycenean influence in the western Mediterranean.</emph> Lord W.D. Taylour. Cambridge Ph.D. 1955.</para>
<para id="p13"><emph type="i">The chronological problem of the Trojan War.</emph> V.R.d'A. Desborough. Oxford B.Litt. 1939.</para>
<page start="006"/>
<para id="p14"><emph type="i">The history and nature of the dowry among the ancient Greeks.</emph> Frances A. Collie. Wales M.A. 1905.</para>
<para id="p15"><emph type="i">The evolution of religion in Greece from earliest times to the time of Hesiod.</emph> A. Le Marchant. Belfast M.A. 1920.</para>
<para id="p16"><emph type="i">Topography, movement and supply in the warfare of ancient Greece, south of Thessaly and Epirus.</emph> W.W. Cruickshank. London Ph.D. 1955.</para>
<para id="p17"><emph type="i">Early Greek armour and weapons from the end of the bronze age to <emph type="i">c</emph>.600 B.C.</emph> A.McE. Snodgrass. Oxford D.Phil. 1962.</para>
<para id="p18"><emph type="i">Plundering in war and other depredations in Greek history from 800 B.C. to 146 B.C.</emph> A.H. Jackson. Cambridge Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p19"><emph type="i">The relations between Greek colonies and their mother cities.</emph> A.J. Graham. Cambridge Ph.D. 1956.</para>
<para id="p20"><emph type="i">Relations between Greece and the Levant in the archaic age.</emph> M.M. Austin. Cambridge Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p21"><emph type="i">Cults of Boeotia.</emph> A. Schachter. Oxford D.Phil. 1966.</para>
<para id="p22"><emph type="i">The place of coinage in Greek foreign trade down to the end of the 5th century B.C.</emph> A.H. Lloyd. Cambridge Ph.D. 1928/9.</para>
<para id="p23"><emph type="i">Early Corinth.</emph> J.B. Salmon. Oxford D.Phil. 1970.</para>
<para id="p24"><emph type="i">Athen an propertied families, 600&ndash;300 B.C.</emph> J.K. Davies. Oxford D.Phil. 1965.</para>
<para id="p25"><emph type="i">The Eleusinian mysteries.</emph> R.H. Harte. Belfast M.A. 1927.</para>
<para id="p26"><emph type="i">A study of the conditions which led to the Athenian and Spartan tyrannies, and the effect of these tyrannies on the foreign policy of other states.</emph> Mrs. Margaret O. Wason. Glasgow Ph.D. 1946.</para>
<para id="p27"><emph type="i">The history of the Peisistratid tyranny at Athens.</emph> Patricia M. Davies. Wales M.A. 1952.</para>
<para id="p28"><emph type="i">A history of the electrum coinage of Mytilene.</emph> J.F. Healy. Cambridge Ph.D. 1954.</para>
<para id="p29"><emph type="i">Greek bronze coinage, <emph type="i">c</emph>.450&ndash;150 B.C., its introduction, circulation and value, with particular reference to the series of Corinth.</emph> M.J. Price. Cambridge Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p30"><emph type="i">The growth of knowledge among the ancient Greeks of the Atlantic coast of Europe, with special reference to the British Isles.</emph> A.J. Sweetland. London M.A. 1957.</para>
<para id="p31"><emph type="i">Knowledge of India among educated Greeks down to the time of Arrian.</emph> T.R. Robinson. Belfast M.A. 1960.</para>
<para id="p32"><emph type="i">The Indo-Greeks: a numismatic and historical study.</emph> A.K. Narain. London Ph.D. 1954.</para>
<para id="p33"><emph type="i">History of Samos to 438.</emph> J.P. Barron. Oxford D.Phil. 1961.</para>
<para id="p34"><emph type="i">The mechanism of the diplomacy of the ancient Greek city-states to 338 B.C.</emph> D.J. Mosley. Cambridge Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<para id="p35"><emph type="i">The history of Miletus down to the <emph type="i">anabasis</emph> of Alexander.</emph> Adelaide G. Dunham. London M.A. 1913.</para>
<para id="p36"><emph type="i">The history of Thessaly.</emph> R. Williams. Wales M.A. 1903.</para>
<para id="p37"><emph type="i">The history of Thessaly up to 323 B.C.</emph> E.J. Lloyd. Wales M.A. 1914.</para>
<para id="p38"><emph type="i">The commercial law of ancient Athens to 323 B.C.</emph> E.S.F. Ridout. London Ph.D. 1935.</para>
<para id="p39"><emph type="i">Early Greek ships.</emph> R.T. Williams. Wales M.A. 1958.</para>
<para id="p40"><emph type="i">Moral and religious education at Athens in the 5th century B.C.</emph> T.W. Herry. Liverpool M.A. 1915.</para>
<para id="p41"><emph type="i">The campaign of Xerxes from the Persian side.</emph> J.A. Dodd. London M.A. 1913.</para>
<para id="p42"><emph type="i">A study of the building inscriptions at Epidauros.</emph> Alison M. Burford. Cambridge Ph.D. 1963.</para>
<para id="p43"><emph type="i">The political parties in Athens during the Peloponnesian War.</emph> R.A.E. Prosser. Bristol M.A. 1926.</para>
<para id="p44"><emph type="i">The Four Hundred and the Thirty.</emph> A.J. Barnett. Birmingham M.A. 1901.</para>
<para id="p45"><emph type="i">Social organisation in Xenophon's <emph type="i">anabasis</emph>: the communal or political organisation of the Army of the Ten Thousand.</emph> G.B. Nussbaum. Birmingham M.A. 1955.</para>
<page start="007"/>
<para id="p46"><emph type="i">Greek medicine in the 5th and 4th centuries B.C.</emph> W.C. Wake. London M.Sc. (Ext.) 1946.</para>
<para id="p47"><emph type="i">Athenian foreign trade in the 5th and 4th centuries B.C.</emph> R.J. Hopper. Cambridge Ph.D. 1935/6.</para>
<para id="p48"><emph type="i">Tyrants and dynasts in the Greek cities of Asia Minor in the 5th and 4th centuries B.C.</emph> A.J. Earp. Cambridge M.Litt. 1954.</para>
<para id="p49"><emph type="i">A study of the family in Athens in the 5th and 4th centuries B.C.</emph> Dorothy M. Burgmann. Oxford B.Litt. 1951.</para>
<para id="p50"><emph type="i">Stasis in the Greek world (excluding Magna Graecia), from the end of the Peloponnesian War to the death of Alexander the Great (404&ndash;324 B.C.).</emph> J.C. Octon. Cambridge Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p51"><emph type="i">Piraeus and the sea-people of Athens in the 4th and 5th centuries B.C.</emph> M. Amit. London Ph.D. 1958.</para>
<para id="p52"><emph type="i">The coinages of Illyria and Paeonia, from the early 4th century B.C. until the establishment of Roman provinces in those countries.</emph> J.M.F. May. Oxford B.Litt. 1937.</para>
<para id="p53"><emph type="i">Studies in the history of Arcadia in the classical and Hellenistic periods.</emph> J. Roy. Cambridge Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p54"><emph type="i">The idea of a common peace in ancient Greece in the 4th century B.C.</emph> T.T.B. Ryder. Cambridge Ph.D. 1956.</para>
<para id="p55"><emph type="i">Military and naval administration in Athens in the 4th century B.C., including finance.</emph> L.M.A.W. Yehya. London Ph.D. 1953.</para>
<para id="p56"><emph type="i">Antigonus the One-eyed.</emph> R.H. Simpson. Durham Ph.D. 1952.</para>
<para id="p57"><emph type="i">The Third Sacred War.</emph> C.T.H.R. Ehrhardt. Oxford B.Litt. 1961.</para>
<para id="p58"><emph type="i">The Aetolian League 323&ndash;189 B.C.</emph> P.H. Agrell. Oxford D.Phil. 1970.</para>
<para id="p59"><emph type="i">The distribution of power between the federal government and constituent states in Greek federations.</emph> E.S.F. Ridout. London M.A. 1926.</para>
<para id="p60"><emph type="i">Studies in the history and epigraphy of Hellenistic Rhodes.</emph> P.M. Fraser. Oxford D.Phil. 1951.</para>
<para id="p61"><emph type="i">The battle elephant in the Hellenistic period.</emph> C.E. Thompson. Belfast M.A. 1970.</para>
<para id="p62"><emph type="i">The rival claims of Sparta and Macedon to the leadership of Greece in the late 3rd century B.C.</emph> Eleanor M. Green. London M.A. 1924.</para>
<para id="p63"><emph type="i">Demetrius Poliorcetes, with special reference to Plutarch's Life.</emph> L.C. Smith. Liverpool Ph.D. 1957.</para>
<para id="p64"><emph type="i">The life and times of Hiero II, king of Syracuse.</emph> W.H. Davies. Wales M.A. 1935.</para>
<para id="p65"><emph type="i">Philopoemen: a study in Hellenistic history.</emph> R.M. Errington. Durham Ph.D. 1965/6.</para>
<para id="p66"><emph type="i">The early coinage of Neapolis Campaniae and its relationship to the coinage of Hyria and Nola.</emph> N.K. Rutter. London Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p67"><emph type="i">City-state and church.</emph> A.A.T. Ehrhardt. Cambridge Ph.D. 1943.</para>
</section>
<section id="s4">
<head>ROME AND THE ROMAN EMPIRE</head>
<section id="s5">
<head>General and Political History</head>
<para id="p68"><emph type="i">The types of political relation established between Rome and other communities in Italy from the earliest recorded times to the close of the Republic, and their contribution to the conception of citizenship adopted by the Roman empire during the first three centuries A.D.</emph> A.N. Sherwin-White. Oxford D.Phil. 1937.</para>
<para id="p69"><emph type="i">Roman policies in Etruria and Umbria from the Conquest to the early empire.</emph> W.V. Harris. Oxford D.Phil. 1968.</para>
<page start="008"/>
<para id="p70"><emph type="i">The Etruscan and Roman town of Sutrim (Sutri), in the light of the archaeological remains in and around it.</emph> G.C. Duncan. Cambridge Ph.D. 1963.</para>
<para id="p71"><emph type="i">The history of the governing class at Rome from the beginning of the Republic to 100 B.C., with special reference to the accessibility of that class to those born outside it.</emph> E.S. Staveley. Oxford D.Phil. 1951.</para>
<para id="p72"><emph type="i">Kinship and political organisation in regal and republican Rome.</emph> Diana M. Evans. Manchester M.A. 1961.</para>
<para id="p73"><emph type="i">The development of the <emph type="i">ius municipii</emph> and the <emph type="i">ius Latii</emph> to 90 B.C.</emph> J. Pinsent. Oxford D.Phil. 1957.</para>
<para id="p74"><emph type="i">The rise and fall of the Caecilii Metelli, 284&ndash;46 B.C.</emph> M.G. Morgan. Exeter Ph.D. 1961.</para>
<para id="p75"><emph type="i">The tribunate of the plebs, 287&ndash;133 B.C.</emph> Monica M. Morgan. Liverpool M.A. 1960.</para>
<para id="p76"><emph type="i">Foreign clientelae in Roman foreign policy and internal politics (264 B.C. &ndash; 70 B.C.).</emph> E. Badian. Oxford D.Phil. 1956.</para>
<para id="p77"><emph type="i">The history of Sardinia under the Roman Republic.</emph> Ellen M. Adams. London M.A. 1917.</para>
<para id="p78"><emph type="i">Family influence in Roman politics from Hannibal's invasion to the battle of Pydna.</emph> J.R. Cummings. Oxford B.Litt. 1935.</para>
<para id="p79"><emph type="i">'Vis'. Violence in the city in the last two centuries of the Roman Republic - its development in the light of the inadequacy of means of suppression and of the Roman attitude to the rule of law.</emph> A.W. Lintott. London Ph.D. 1963.</para>
<para id="p80"><emph type="i">Politics and policies at Rome, 187&ndash;167 B.C.</emph> Valerie M. Warrior. London Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p81"><emph type="i">Italian senators, 139 B.C. - A.D. 14.</emph> T.P. Wiseman. Oxford D.Phil. 1967.</para>
<para id="p82"><emph type="i">Studies in pre-Gracchan colonisation.</emph> E.T. Salmon. Cambridge Ph.D. 1932/3.</para>
<para id="p83"><emph type="i">The legislation of Caius Gracchus, considered especially in relation to the Order of the Equites.</emph> G.A. Le Chavetois. London M.A. 1912.</para>
<para id="p84"><emph type="i">Constitutional speculation in the antiquarians and annalists of the last century B.C., with special reference to the legends of Romulus and Servius Tullius in Livy, Cicero, and Dionysius of Halicarnassus.</emph> Mary L.M. Leavitt. Oxford B.Litt. 1966.</para>
<para id="p85"><emph type="i">The life and times of Marcus Licinius Crassus, triumvir.</emph> J. Thompson. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1941.</para>
<para id="p86"><emph type="i">A biography of Lucius Licinius Lucullus.</emph> W.H. Bennett. Oxford B.Litt. 1969.</para>
<para id="p87"><emph type="i">The political and administrative system of Sulla.</emph> J.E. Taylor. Oxford B.Litt. 1924.</para>
<para id="p88"><emph type="i">The political activity of Clodius, particularly in relation to the triumvirs.</emph> Muriel D. Whitehouse. London M.A. 1916.</para>
<para id="p89"><emph type="i">The political thought of Sallust.</emph> D.C. Earl. Cambridge Ph.D. 1957.</para>
<para id="p90"><emph type="i">Politics at Rome during the social and civil wars.</emph> C.M. Bulst. Oxford B.Litt. 1961.</para>
<para id="p91"><emph type="i">Political biography at Rome from its first appearance to Augustus.</emph> R.G. Lewis. Oxford B.Litt. 1966.</para>
<para id="p92"><emph type="i"><emph type="i">Libertas</emph> as a political idea at Rome during the late Republic and early Principate.</emph> C. Wirszubski. Cambridge Ph.D. 1946/7.</para>
<para id="p93"><emph type="i">The lost sources of Roman history, 44 B.C. - A.D. 68.</emph> J.B. Kenyon , <emph type="i">formerly</emph> Higginbottom. Liverpool M.A. 1968.</para>
<para id="p94"><emph type="i">A history of the relations between the princeps and the senate during the Julio-Claudian period, with special reference to Augustus and Tiberius.</emph> T.J. Cadoux. Oxford D.Phil. 1951.</para>
<para id="p95"><emph type="i">The senatorial opposition to the early Roman empire.</emph> Winifred Biggs. Manchester M.A. 1917.</para>
<page start="009"/>
<para id="p96"><emph type="i">The career of Marcus Antonius until the battle of Philippi.</emph> C.N. Frank. Leeds M.A. 1935.</para>
<para id="p97"><emph type="i">The administrative staff of the Roman emperors at Rome from Augustus to Alexander Severus.</emph> G.R.C. Davis. Oxford D.Phil. 1947.</para>
<para id="p98"><emph type="i">The Monumentum Ancyranum compared with other authorities for the life of Augustus.</emph> M.H. Davies. Wales M.A. 1912.</para>
<para id="p99"><emph type="i">The frontiers of the Roman empire under Augustus.</emph> C.M. Wells. Oxford D.Phil. 1965.</para>
<para id="p100"><emph type="i">Augustus and the Greek world.</emph> G.W. Bowersock. Oxford D.Phil. 1962.</para>
<para id="p101"><emph type="i">Augustus and the gods.</emph> S.O. Esan. London M.A. 1959.</para>
<para id="p102"><emph type="i">The Roman senate during the reigns of Claudius and Nero.</emph> D.A. McAlindon. Belfast M.A. 1953.</para>
<para id="p103"><emph type="i">The Roman senate, A.D. 69&ndash;193.</emph> J.R. Morris. London Ph.D. 1953.</para>
<para id="p104"><emph type="i">The philosophic and aristocratic opposition to the Flavian emperors.</emph> R.L. James. London Ph.D. 1938.</para>
<para id="p105"><emph type="i">The early career, accession and domestic policy of the Emperor Domitian.</emph> R.A. Gillespie. London M.A. 1937.</para>
<para id="p106"><emph type="i">Concepts of imperial government in the age of Trajan.</emph> J. Warmington. Southampton M.A. 1964/5.</para>
<para id="p107"><emph type="i">The emperor Lucius Septimius Severus.</emph> M. Platnauer. Oxford B.Litt. 1914.</para>
<para id="p108"><emph type="i">A prosopographical investigation into the politics of the reigns of Septimius Severus and Caracalla, 193&ndash;217.</emph> J.B. Leaning. Manchester M.A. 1968.</para>
<para id="p109"><emph type="i">The reign of Alexander Severus.</emph> I.H.C. Powell. Birmingham M.A. 1964.</para>
<para id="p110"><emph type="i">Public disorders in the late Roman empire, their causes and character.</emph> J.R. Martindale. Oxford B.Litt. 1961.</para>
<para id="p111"><emph type="i">The influence of the senatorial aristocracy on the imperial government in the late 3rd and 4th centuries A.D.</emph> M.T.W. Arnheim. Cambridge Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p112"><emph type="i">The chronology of the campaigns of the reign of Diocletian.</emph> J.V. Maitland. Manchester M.A. 1969.</para>
<para id="p113"><emph type="i">The political consequences of Maxentius's usurpation on the Tetrarchic system of Galerius.</emph> Nicola G. Tailby. Manchester M.A. 1970.</para>
<para id="p114"><emph type="i">The family and supporters of the emperor in western society in the age of Theodosius.</emph> J.F. Matthews. Oxford D.Phil. 1970.</para>
<para id="p115"><emph type="i">The imperial notarii of the late Roman empire from the accession of Constantine to the death of Honorius.</emph> Mrs. Carol H. Moulton. Birmingham M.A. 1970.</para>
<para id="p116"><emph type="i">Relations between the Roman and Persian empires from the death of Constantine (337) to the death of Theodosius (395).</emph> M.H. Dodgeon. Bristol M.Litt. 1968.</para>
<para id="p117"><emph type="i">A prosopographical study of the court of Theodosius II.</emph> Margaret Priest. London Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p118"><emph type="i">The evidence of Salvian for the causes of the fall of the Roman empire in the west.</emph> W.R. Davies. Wales M.A. 1941.</para>
<para id="p119"><emph type="i">The sea and the 5th-century west Roman empire.</emph> J.R. Moss. London Ph.D. 1970.</para>
</section>
<section id="s6">
<head>Economic and Social History</head>
<para id="p120"><emph type="i">The social and economic history of Ostia.</emph> F.H. Wilson. Oxford D.Phil. 1935.</para>
<para id="p121"><emph type="i">A study of the development of social and economic life at Pompeii, with a consideration of how far that development can be regarded as typical of the towns of Campania in general.</emph> R.C. Carrington. Oxford D.Phil. 1932/3.</para>
<para id="p122"><emph type="i">An epigraphic survey of costs in Italy and Africa from the Republic to the Tetrarchy.</emph> R.P. Duncan-Jones. Cambridge Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<page start="010"/>
<para id="p123"><emph type="i">Social status and legal privilege in the 2nd and 3rd centuries of the Roman empire, with special reference to the curial class.</emph> P.D.A. Garnsey. Oxford D.Phil. 1967.</para>
<para id="p124"><emph type="i">The state of Roman agriculture in the time of the Gracchi.</emph> Claire A.I. Moore. London M.A. 1914.</para>
<para id="p125"><emph type="i">The agrarian programme of the Democratic party, B.C. 78&ndash;59.</emph> Muriel Auld. Liverpool M.A. 1905.</para>
<para id="p126"><emph type="i">The condition of Roman agriculture in the time of Augustus.</emph> W.A. Rhodes. Leeds M.A. 1932.</para>
<para id="p127"><emph type="i">The social legislation of the Roman empire from Augustus to Constantine, and the policy of its authors.</emph> J.F. Leddy. Oxford D.Phil. 1938.</para>
<para id="p128"><emph type="i">The practice of medicine in ancient Rome.</emph> E.M. Bell. Sheffield M.A. 1969.</para>
<para id="p129"><emph type="i">Women in Roman history from 200 B.C. to A.D. 138.</emph> Gwynneth M.L. Jones. Wales M.A. 1964.</para>
<para id="p130"><emph type="i">The position of women among the Romans.</emph> Alice M. Holmes. London M.A. 1932.</para>
<para id="p131"><emph type="i">The slave's 'peculium' in Rome, and the protection afforded to it by Roman law before the year 180 A.D.</emph> Esm&eacute;e M. Thomas. Wales M.A. 1927.</para>
<para id="p132"><emph type="i"><emph type="i">Familia Caesaris</emph>: a social study of the slaves and freedmen of the Roman imperial administration.</emph> P.R.C. Weaver. Cambridge Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<para id="p133"><emph type="i">Roman freedmen during the late Republic.</emph> Mrs. Susan M. Treggiari, <emph type="i">n&eacute;e</emph> Franklin. Oxford B.Litt. 1967.</para>
<para id="p134"><emph type="i">Slavery in the first two centuries of the Roman empire.</emph> R.H. Barrow. Oxford B.Litt. 1926.</para>
<para id="p135"><emph type="i">Freedmen in the early Roman empire.</emph> A.M. Duff. Oxford B.Litt. 1926.</para>
<para id="p136"><emph type="i">Social mobility in the early Roman empire.</emph> H.H. Dalby. Leicester M.A. 1967.</para>
<para id="p137"><emph type="i">A comparative study of the fora of the Roman empire.</emph> Isabel Purchon. Wales M.A. 1933.</para>
<para id="p138"><emph type="i">Clothing and its manufacture in the northern Roman provinces (excluding leatherwork).</emph> J.P. Wild. Cambridge Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p139"><emph type="i">The development of the mining of lead in the Iberian peninsula and Britain under the Roman empire until the end of the 2nd century A.D.</emph> H.D.H. Elkington. Durham M.A. 1968.</para>
<para id="p140"><emph type="i">The design, structure and organisation of <emph type="i">Horrea</emph> under the Roman empire.</emph> G.E. Rickman. Oxford D.Phil. 1963.</para>
<para id="p141"><emph type="i">The medical profession in the Roman empire from Augustus to Justinian.</emph> V. Nutton. Cambridge Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p142"><emph type="i">Studies in Roman imperial numismatic art.</emph> C.C. Vermeule. London Ph.D. 1953.</para>
<para id="p143"><emph type="i">The <emph type="i">aes</emph> coinage of Rome and its subsidiary mints in the West, A.D. 68&ndash;81, with special reference to mint organisation, to the relative frequency of types and to their consequent interpretation.</emph> C.M. Kraay. Oxford D.Phil. 1953.</para>
<para id="p144"><emph type="i">A re-examination and analysis of the coinages of Nero, with special reference to the <emph type="i">aes</emph> - coined and current in Italy and the western provinces of the empire.</emph> D.W. Macdowall. Oxford D.Phil. 1959.</para>
<para id="p145"><emph type="i">The dating and arrangement of the undated coins from the mint of Rome, A.D. 98&ndash;148.</emph> P.V.B. Hill. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1969.</para>
<para id="p146"><emph type="i">Inland transport for civilian purposes in the Roman empire from the Ciceronian age to the principate of Trajan.</emph> G.P. McKenna. Manchester M.A. 1962.</para>
<para id="p147"><emph type="i">Urban development in the north-western Roman provinces in the first two centuries A.D.</emph> C.V. Walthew. Cambridge Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p148"><emph type="i">The spice trade under the Roman empire.</emph> J.I. Miller. Oxford D.Phil. 1964.</para>
<para id="p149"><emph type="i">Commerce in the time of the empire between Italy and other countries.</emph> W.W. Griffiths. Wales M.A. 1922.</para>
<page start="011"/>
<para id="p150"><emph type="i">Some 'voluntary' taxes of the Roman empire.</emph> Emily C. Wordsworth. Birmingham M.A. 1912.</para>
<para id="p151"><emph type="i">The Jews in the city of Rome during the first centuries B.C. and A.D., including a study of the references to them in Greek and Latin writers.</emph> J.H. Michael. Wales M.A. 1913.</para>
<para id="p152"><emph type="i">The Jewish community in Rome, from its foundation until A.D. 313.</emph> Mary E. Jacombs. Birmingham M.A. 1915.</para>
<para id="p153"><emph type="i">Social life in the Roman empire during the reigns of Constantius and Julian.</emph> A.R. Foster. Belfast M.A. 1929.</para>
</section>
<section id="s7">
<head>Religion, Art and Letters</head>
<para id="p154"><emph type="i">The interrelation of state religion and politics in Roman public life, from the end of the Second Punic War to the time of Sulla.</emph> J.A. North. Oxford D.Phil. 1967.</para>
<para id="p155"><emph type="i">Some aspects of the acting profession in Rome.</emph> E.J. Jory. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1967.</para>
<para id="p156"><emph type="i">The history of the schools of rhetoric in the Roman empire from Vespasian to the fall of the empire in the west.</emph> A.O. Gwynn. Oxford B.Litt. 1919.</para>
<para id="p157"><emph type="i">The chronology of the life and letters of the younger Pliny.</emph> R.H. Harte. Belfast Ph.D. 1937.</para>
<para id="p158"><emph type="i">The cult of Isis in Italy: an account of its external history.</emph> M.S. Salem. Liverpool Ph.D. 1937.</para>
<para id="p159"><emph type="i">The meaning and development of the cult of Mars at Rome.</emph> E. H. Clement. Oxford B.Litt. 1939.</para>
<para id="p160"><emph type="i">The cult of Mars in Britain and Gaul.</emph> K.J. Fairless. Newcastle M.A. 1967.</para>
<para id="p161"><emph type="i">The local cults of ancient Latium outside Rome, with the exception of Ostia.</emph> T.G. Thomas. Wales M.A. 1930.</para>
<para id="p162"><emph type="i">The policy of the Roman government towards non-Roman religions from Augustus to Trajan, with special reference to the treatment of such religions in Rome and Italy.</emph> Una C. Fitzhardinge. Oxford B.Litt. 1940.</para>
<para id="p163"><emph type="i">The fall of paganism.</emph> Elsie M.C. Hunt. Birmingham M.A. 1913.</para>
<para id="p164"><emph type="i">The fall of paganism.</emph> A.E. Wilson. Birmingham M.A. 1914.</para>
<para id="p165"><emph type="i">The attitude of the Roman government to Christianity from Nero to Marcus Aurelius.</emph> M.H. Evans. Wales M.A. 1909.</para>
<para id="p166"><emph type="i">The persecution under Diocletian.</emph> G.W. Richardson. London M.A. 1924.</para>
<para id="p167"><emph type="i">The cult of Apollo from the 4th to the 6th century A.D.</emph> Alice Weissbruth. London Ph.D. 1967.</para>
</section>
<section id="s8">
<head>Army</head>
<para id="p168"><emph type="i">The primipilares of the Roman army.</emph> B. Dobson. Durham Ph.D. 1955.</para>
<para id="p169"><emph type="i">The immunes and principales of the Roman army.</emph> D.J. Breeze. Durham Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p170"><emph type="i">Roman military book-keeping.</emph> G.R. Watson. Durham M.Litt. 1953.</para>
<para id="p171"><emph type="i">The recruitment of Roman legionaries from 146 B.C. to 30 B.C.</emph> P.J. Cuff. Oxford D.Phil. 1955.</para>
<para id="p172"><emph type="i">Peace-time routine in the Roman army.</emph> R.W. Davies. Durham Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p173"><emph type="i">Some aspects of the political influence of the Roman army as it developed from 133 B.C. to A.D. 14.</emph> F. Naylor. Liverpool M.A. 1963.</para>
<para id="p174"><emph type="i">Some neglected aspects of Scipio Africanus.</emph> H.H. Scullard. London Ph.D. 1930.</para>
<para id="p175"><emph type="i">The armies of the Triumviral period.</emph> W.C.G. Schmitthenner. Oxford D.Phil. 1958.</para>
<para id="p176"><emph type="i">Studies in the later Roman army.</emph> J.R. Hepworth. Durham Ph.D. 1963.</para>
<page start="012"/>
<para id="p177"><emph type="i">A study of the Roman cavalry arm, with special reference to the deployment and use of cavalry in the 2nd century A.D.</emph> S.H. Bartle. Durham Ph.D. 1962.</para>
<para id="p178"><emph type="i">The Roman high command from the death of Hadrian to the death of Caracalla, with particular attention to the Danubian wars of Marcus Aurelius and Commodus.</emph> A.R. Birley. Oxford D.Phil. 1966.</para>
<para id="p179"><emph type="i">The 3rd-century origins of the 'New' Roman army.</emph> P.K. Cooper. Oxford D.Phil. 1968.</para>
<para id="p180"><emph type="i">The settlement of veterans in the Roman empire.</emph> J.C. Mann. London Ph.D. 1956.</para>
<para id="p181"><emph type="i">The development of the Roman fleets under the empire.</emph> L.F. Fitzhardinge. Oxford B.Litt. 1933.</para>
<para id="p182"><emph type="i">Late Roman military architecture in Britain and northern Gaul, with special reference to the coastal defence system.</emph> R.M. Butler. Cambridge Ph.D. 1954.</para>
</section>
<section id="s9">
<head>Provinces</head>
<section id="s10">
<head><emph type="i">Greece and the East</emph></head>
<para id="p183"><emph type="i">Roman relations with the Greek East, from the earliest contacts to 146 B.C., and their relation to internal political struggles.</emph> J. Briscoe. Oxford D.Phil. 1965.</para>
<para id="p184"><emph type="i">The development of trade to the end of the 2nd century A.D. between the eastern provinces of the Roman empire and the countries lying further east.</emph> J. Thorley. Durham M.A. 1965.</para>
<para id="p185"><emph type="i">Immigration and settlement in the province of Dalmatia from the first Roman contacts to the death of Commodus.</emph> A.J.N. Wilson. Oxford D.Phil. 1949.</para>
<para id="p186"><emph type="i">Studies in the Roman province of Dalmatia.</emph> J.J. Wilkes. Durham Ph.D. 1962.</para>
<para id="p187"><emph type="i">Proconsular administration of justice in Asia Minor in the late Republic, with special reference to Cicero in Cilicia.</emph> A.J. Marshall. Oxford B.Litt. 1962.</para>
<para id="p188"><emph type="i">Cicero's provincial governorship of Cilicia.</emph> J.K. Wilkinson. Birmingham M.A. 1959.</para>
<para id="p189"><emph type="i">Social and economic conditions of the province Achaia from Augustus to Caracalla.</emph> A.J. Gossage. London Ph.D. 1951.</para>
<para id="p190"><emph type="i">The trade gilds of the eastern provinces of the Roman empire (exclusive of Egypt) during the first three centuries A.D.</emph> Esm&eacute;e M. Thomas. Oxford B.Litt. 1934.</para>
<para id="p191"><emph type="i">The anti-Roman reaction in Sicily and the eastern provinces, 133 B.C. - 85 B.C.</emph> Marianne E. Henderson. Sheffield M.A. 1955.</para>
<para id="p192"><emph type="i">Lycia and Pamphylia under the Roman empire from Augustus to Diocletian.</emph> Shelagh A. Jameson. Oxford D.Phil. 1965.</para>
<para id="p193"><emph type="i">Roman colonies in southern Asia Minor with special reference to Antioch - towards Pisidia.</emph> Barbara M. Levick. Oxford D.Phil. 1958.</para>
<para id="p194"><emph type="i">Rome and Parthia, 70&ndash;29 B.C.</emph> A. Sandys-Wood. Oxford B. Litt. 1949.</para>
<para id="p195"><emph type="i">Parthia and her relations with Rome from B.C. 27 to A.D. 228.</emph> A.T. Owen. Wales M.A. 1920.</para>
<para id="p196"><emph type="i">The relation between the Jews and the Roman government from 66 B.C. to the foundation of the Christian empire.</emph> Edith M. Smallwood. Cambridge Ph.D. 1951.</para>
<para id="p197"><emph type="i">A study of Jewish history from the death of Herod the Great to the destruction of Jerusalem, 4 B.C. - 70 A.D.</emph> S.G.F. Brandon. Leeds M.A. 1932.</para>
<para id="p198"><emph type="i">Judaea under the procurators.</emph> L. Robinson. Cambridge M.Litt. 1926/7.</para>
<para id="p199"><emph type="i">The Roman province of Judea before A.D. 70.</emph> Dorothy D. Fielding. Manchester M.A. 1933.</para>
<para id="p200"><emph type="i">Palestine under Roman administration, 6&ndash;66 A.D.</emph> M. Aberbach. Leeds M.A. 1947.</para>
<page start="013"/>
<para id="p201"><emph type="i">Palestinian coins of the centuries immediately preceding and following the Christian era.</emph> A. Mallinson. Oxford B.Litt. 1923/4.</para>
<para id="p202"><emph type="i">Currencies and prices in 3rd- and 4th-century Palestine and their implications for Roman economic history.</emph> D. Sperber. London Ph.D. 1968.</para>
</section>
<section id="s11">
<head><emph type="i">Africa</emph></head>
<para id="p203"><emph type="i">Social life in Roman Africa.</emph> Mary A. Gardiner. Belfast M.A. 1931.</para>
<para id="p204"><emph type="i">History of Numidia under the Roman Republic.</emph> Sybil M. Gates. London M.A. 1917.</para>
<para id="p205"><emph type="i">A study of the municipal aristocracies of the Roman empire in the west, with special reference to North Africa.</emph> M.G. Jarrett. Durham Ph.D. 1958.</para>
<para id="p206"><emph type="i">The composition and functions of the local councils of the cities of the province of Africa under the early Roman empire - up to Constantine.</emph> C.V.M. Lucas. London Ph.D. 1937.</para>
<para id="p207"><emph type="i">Studies in the Roman province of Mauretania Tingitana.</emph> J.E.H. Spaul. Durham M.Litt. 1958.</para>
<para id="p208"><emph type="i">Mauretania Caesariensis: an archaeological and geographical survey.</emph> R.I. Lawless. Durham Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p209"><emph type="i">Studies in the mosaic pavements of Roman North Africa.</emph> Katherine M.D. Dunbabin. Oxford D.Phil. 1970.</para>
<para id="p210"><emph type="i">The agriculture of Cyrenaica in classical antiquity, with special reference to the Jewish Revolt under Trajan.</emph> S.E. Applebaum. Oxford B.Litt. 1948.</para>
</section>
<section id="s12">
<head><emph type="i">Gaul</emph></head>
<para id="p211"><emph type="i">The political and economic organisation of Gaul from 27 B.C. to A.D. 68.</emph> Bernardine M. Humphrey. Liverpool M.A. 1961.</para>
<para id="p212"><emph type="i">The Gallic empire.</emph> C.D. Bishop. Durham M.A. 1965.</para>
<para id="p213"><emph type="i">The political and social organisation of Gaul under the Roman empire.</emph> E.J. Rowland. Wales M.A. 1910.</para>
<para id="p214"><emph type="i">The political and social organisation of Gaul under the Roman empire.</emph> J. Hooson. Wales M.A. 1912.</para>
<para id="p215"><emph type="i">Roman civilisation in the three Gauls during the first three centuries of Roman rule.</emph> H.W. Lawton. Wales M.A. 1923.</para>
<para id="p216"><emph type="i">Roman agricultural organisation in western Europe, with special reference to the Tres Galliae.</emph> J. Percival. Oxford D.Phil. 1967.</para>
<para id="p217"><emph type="i">The organisation and administration of the 'Tres Galliae', 49 B.C. to A.D. 284.</emph> Mary A.J.P. Kerr. Manchester M.A. 1924.</para>
<para id="p218"><emph type="i">The social and economic history of Cisalpine Gaul under the early empire to the death of Trajan.</emph> G.E.F. Chilver. Oxford D.Phil. 1936.</para>
<para id="p219"><emph type="i">Some historical problems arising from the martyrdom of the Christians of Lyons and Vienne in 177 A.D.</emph> G. McConville. Belfast M.A. 1958.</para>
<para id="p220"><emph type="i">Education in Gaul in the last century of the western empire (350&ndash;450 A.D.).</emph> T.J. Haarhoff. Oxford B.Litt. 1918.</para>
<para id="p221"><emph type="i">The Celtic personal names in the Celtic inscriptions of Gaul, the <emph type="i">Commentaries on the Gallic War</emph> and La Graufesenque graffiti.</emph> D.E. Evans. Oxford D.Phil. 1962.</para>
</section>
<section id="s13">
<head><emph type="i">Germania</emph></head>
<para id="p222"><emph type="i">A historical and cultural survey of the Roman Limes of Germania Superior and Raetia.</emph> Olwen P.F. Kendall. London M.A. 1931.</para>
<para id="p223"><emph type="i">The <emph type="i">honestiores</emph> of the Rhine and Danube provinces of the Roman empire, with particular reference to Noricum.</emph> B.L. Cooke. Durham Ph.D. 1964.</para>
<page start="014"/>
<para id="p224"><emph type="i">Roman Trier and the Treveri.</emph> Edith M. Wightman. Oxford D.Phil. 1968.</para>
<para id="p225"><emph type="i">The Romans in W&uuml;rttemberg: a study of colonial development.</emph> J. Rogan. Durham M.A. 1951.</para>
</section>
<section id="s14">
<head><emph type="i">Britain</emph></head>
<para id="p226"><emph type="i">The geography of Roman Britain and its human relationships.</emph> C. Midgley. Sheffield M.Sc. 1927.</para>
<para id="p227"><emph type="i">Some aspects of the Romano-British rural system of the lowland zone.</emph> S.E. Applebaum. Oxford D.Phil. 1952.</para>
<para id="p228"><emph type="i">A reassessment of the economic basis of Roman Britain.</emph> Ilid E. Anthony. London M.A. 1951.</para>
<para id="p229"><emph type="i">The siting and layout of native settlements in the north of England.</emph> P.R. Middleton. Durham M.A. 1967.</para>
<para id="p230"><emph type="i">The coin hoards of Roman Britain.</emph> Annie S. Robertson. London M.A. 1936.</para>
<para id="p231"><emph type="i">Municipal and military water supply and drainage in Roman Britain.</emph> Julie C. Hanson. London Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p232"><emph type="i">Stone building materials in Roman Britain.</emph> J.H. Williams. Manchester M.A. 1968.</para>
<para id="p233"><emph type="i">Roman villas in Britain.</emph> Joan E.A. Liversidge. Cambridge M.Litt. 1949.</para>
<para id="p234"><emph type="i">The villas of Roman Britain, and their place in the life of the province.</emph> C.A.F. Berry. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1949.</para>
<para id="p235"><emph type="i">Roman villas in Britain: their nature and distribution.</emph> Mabel G.A. Webster. Liverpool M.A. 1920.</para>
<para id="p236"><emph type="i">Romano-British villa bath-suites and bath-houses.</emph> J.M.T.H. Younge. Leeds M.A. 1960.</para>
<para id="p237"><emph type="i">The development and affinities of mosaic decoration in Roman Britain.</emph> D.J. Smith. Durham Ph.D. 1952.</para>
<para id="p238"><emph type="i">The crafts of Roman Britain, with special reference to the metal remains at Corstopitum.</emph> R.A. Peel. Durham M.A. 1965.</para>
<para id="p239"><emph type="i">Non-military ironwork in Roman Britain.</emph> W.H. Manning. London Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p240"><emph type="i">Objects of jet in Roman Britain.</emph> C.E.P. Rosser. Manchester M.A. 1961.</para>
<para id="p241"><emph type="i">The religions of Roman Britain.</emph> Judith A.P. Angles. London M.A. 1956.</para>
<para id="p242"><emph type="i">The religions of Roman Britain.</emph> Bridgett E.A. Jones. London M.A. 1955.</para>
<para id="p243"><emph type="i">A survey of the indigenous, Celtic and Teutonic cults of Roman Britain.</emph> J. Herbert. Wales M.A. 1954.</para>
<para id="p244"><emph type="i">Temples and shrines in Roman Britain: their architecture, chronology and distribution.</emph> M.J.T. Lewis. Cambridge Ph.D. 1963.</para>
<para id="p245"><emph type="i">The sculptured decoration on Roman votive altars and pedestals from northern Britain.</emph> J. Kewley. Durham Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p246"><emph type="i">Christian evidence (archaeological and documentary) in Roman and sub-Roman north Britain.</emph> J. Wall. Bristol M.A. 1966.</para>
<para id="p247"><emph type="i">The ethnic connections and status of civilians of non-British origin in the Roman province of Britain.</emph> A.W. Lingard. Sheffield M.A. 1954.</para>
<para id="p248"><emph type="i">Roman civilians and the frontier region of Roman Britain.</emph> P. Salway. Cambridge Ph.D. 1958.</para>
<para id="p249"><emph type="i">The milestones and turrets of Hadrian's Wall and their allocation to legionary construction teams.</emph> Mrs. Joyce Moss, <emph type="i">n&eacute;e</emph> Hooley. Durham M.A. 1969.</para>
<para id="p250"><emph type="i">Pottery from the milecastles and turrets on Hadrian's Wall.</emph> J.D. Dockerill. Durham M.A. 1969.</para>
<para id="p251"><emph type="i">Romanisation in south-west Scotland.</emph> A. Wilson. Durham M.A. 1966.</para>
<para id="p252"><emph type="i">The archaeology of Roman Durham.</emph> K.A. Steer. Durham Ph.D. 1938.</para>
<page start="015"/>
<para id="p253"><emph type="i">Roman military dispositions west of the Pennines, with some observations on the native population of that area.</emph> E. Jones. Liverpool M.A. 1962.</para>
<para id="p254"><emph type="i">The Roman occupation of west Cumberland.</emph> A.H.N. Williams. Wales M.A. 1927.</para>
<para id="p255"><emph type="i">The Roman occupation of north Lancashire and south Westmorland.</emph> J.P. Newsome. Durham M.A. 1958.</para>
<para id="p256"><emph type="i">The Romano-British settlements of Westmorland: a study in cultural ecology.</emph> R.A. Webster. Reading Ph.D. 1968/9.</para>
<para id="p257"><emph type="i">Roman Britain and its defence measures against Irish incursions.</emph> Ann M. Dornier. Durham M.A. 1969.</para>
<para id="p258"><emph type="i">The non-military aspects of the Roman occupation of Wales.</emph> B. Jones. Wales M.A. 1935.</para>
<para id="p259"><emph type="i">The Roman occupation of North Wales and Chester.</emph> W.E. Griffiths. Wales M.A. 1947.</para>
<para id="p260"><emph type="i">Roman Chester - a reconsideration.</emph> T.F. Wright. Durham M.A. 1955.</para>
<para id="p261"><emph type="i">The defences and intra-mural buildings of the Roman legionary fortress at Chester.</emph> G.A. Webster. Manchester M.A. 1951.</para>
<para id="p262"><emph type="i">Caerwent and the Roman occupation of South Wales.</emph> V.E.N. Williams. Wales M.A. 1924.</para>
<para id="p263"><emph type="i">Castle Lyons, the works-depot of the 20th Legion at Holt, Denbighshire. (A description and history of the site, with a catalogue of the pottery and other objects found, its place in the history of the Roman occupation of North Wales, together with a study of the Romano-British pottery industry.)</emph> W.F. Grimes. Wales M.A. 1930.</para>
<para id="p264"><emph type="i">The history and archaeology of Roman Chichester.</emph> Jane G. Pilmer. Durham M.Litt. 1954.</para>
<para id="p265"><emph type="i">Roman Chichester: a survey of its investigation.</emph> K.V. Pagan. Durham M.A. 1965.</para>
<para id="p266"><emph type="i">The Brigantes.</emph> R. Pedley. Durham Ph.D. 1939.</para>
<para id="p267"><emph type="i">The territory of the Cornovii from the time of Septimius Severus to the end of Roman rule.</emph> R.A. Rutland. Keele M.A. 1965.</para>
<para id="p268"><emph type="i">Pre-Flavian military activity in Roman Britain.</emph> A.M. French. Bristol M.Litt. 1966.</para>
<para id="p269"><emph type="i">The organisation and disposition of the Roman army in Britain in the 2nd and 3rd centuries.</emph> J. Maiden. Manchester M.A. 1954.</para>
<para id="p270"><emph type="i">A Roman military problem: a reassessment of Wales and the southern Pennines in the 2nd century A.D.</emph> Mary G. Simpson. Oxford D.Phil. 1960.</para>
<para id="p271"><emph type="i">The representation of the mints in operation under Constantine I in coinage found in south-east England.</emph> Dorothy F. Bushell. London M.A. 1956.</para>
<para id="p272"><emph type="i">Roman coinage of the 4th century in Britain.</emph> Mrs. Alison Ravetz. Leeds Ph.D. 1963.</para>
<para id="p273"><emph type="i">Magnus Maximus and the end of Roman Britain.</emph> D.A. Gillett. Durham M.A. 1960.</para>
<para id="p274"><emph type="i">The Vallum reconsidered.</emph> Brenda Swinbank. Durham Ph.D. 1954.</para>
</section>
</section>
</section>
</section>
</report>
