<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="154864" pubid="1512" publish="true">
<title>Britain: 19th and 20th Centuries</title>
<subtitle></subtitle>
<page start="171"/>
<section id="s1">
<head>BRITAIN: 19TH AND 20TH CENTURIES</head>
<para id="p1"><emph type="i">For items covering the period 1800&ndash;32 see above under 1600&ndash;1832</emph></para>
<section id="s2">
<head>POPULATION AND MIGRATION</head>
<para id="p2"><emph type="i">The rural population of England and Wales, 1801&ndash;1951.</emph> S.W.E. Vince. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1955.</para>
<para id="p3"><emph type="i">Changes in the distribution of the population since 1800.</emph> Winifred R. Luke. London M.A. (Ext.) 1939.</para>
<para id="p4"><emph type="i">Cleveland and Teesside: a geographical study of population and occupational changes since 1800.</emph> Ida Bowes. London M.A. 1948.</para>
<para id="p5"><emph type="i">Some aspects of the population growth and structure in the Warwickshire coalfield since 1800.</emph> R.C. Bunker. Birmingham M.A. 1952.</para>
<para id="p6"><emph type="i">Berkshire: some studies based on the census returns.</emph> G.R. Lucas. Reading M.A. 1954.</para>
<para id="p7"><emph type="i">Population and urban growth in east Bristol, 1800&ndash;1914.</emph> F. Hewitt. Bristol Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p8"><emph type="i">Some aspects of the growth and distribution of population in Hertfordshire since 1801.</emph> D.J.M. Hooson. London Ph.D. 1955.</para>
<para id="p9"><emph type="i">A study of planned urban and rural industrial settlements and communities in the United Kingdom during the 19th century.</emph> P. Taylor. Durham Ph.D. 1960/1.</para>
<para id="p10"><emph type="i">Population change and population structure 1801&ndash;61 in the Peak district of Derbyshire.</emph> Ray Gurney. Liverpool Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p11"><emph type="i">The population of Northamptonshire, 1801&ndash;1951.</emph> C.D. Morley. Birmingham M.A. 1957.</para>
<para id="p12"><emph type="i">The changes in population distribution in the Tern 'basin' of north-east Shropshire, with special reference to the Wellington-Oakengates conurbation, 1801&ndash;1951.</emph> K.C. Riley. London M.A. 1958.</para>
<para id="p13"><emph type="i">The economic significance of the present population distribution in Gloucestershire and its relationship to economic developments during the past 150 years in the county.</emph> H.C. Andrews. London M.Sc. (Ext.) 1956.</para>
<para id="p14"><emph type="i">Urban change in East Anglia in the 19th century.</emph> Lucy Caroe. Cambridge Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p15"><emph type="i">Stages in the growth of urban settlement in central Cornwall.</emph> M.E. Witherick. Birmingham Ph.D. 1963.</para>
<para id="p16"><emph type="i">A study of the development of urban spheres of influence in Leicestershire.</emph> P.R. Odell. Birmingham Ph.D. 1954.</para>
<para id="p17"><emph type="i">Leicester's rural-urban fringe: a study of industry and settlement.</emph> Gladys Starmer. Nottingham M.A. 1959.</para>
<para id="p18"><emph type="i">Population in the dales of north-east England.</emph> A.E. Smailes. London M.A. 1933.</para>
<para id="p19"><emph type="i">Aspects of the social geography of Nidderdale, Wensleydale and the northern part of the vale of York.</emph> R.J. Johnston. Manchester M.A. 1964.</para>
<para id="p20"><emph type="i">The geographical significance of population changes in Carmarthenshire since 1802.</emph> F.G. Hannell. Bristol Ph.D. 1952.</para>
<para id="p21"><emph type="i">A demographic study of central Snowdonia and its coastlands in the 19th century.</emph> Kathleen M. O'Kelly. Manchester M.A. 1961.</para>
<para id="p22"><emph type="i">Population in central Wales: changes in number and distribution, 1801&ndash;1931.</emph> J.E.C. Jenkins. London M.A. 1939.</para>
<para id="p23"><emph type="i">The geographical reasons for the growth of the population of south Staffordshire, east Warwickshire and Leicestershire from 1801 to 1931.</emph> Gladys M. Sarson. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1937.</para>
<page start="172"/>
<para id="p24"><emph type="i">Nineteenth-century changes in the distribution of population in the south Staffordshire coalfield.</emph> R.D. Bramwell. Birmingham M.A. 1935.</para>
<para id="p25"><emph type="i">A sociological and statistical study of the population of the vale of Glamorgan during the first half of the 19th century.</emph> M.I. Williams. Wales M.A. 1939.</para>
<para id="p26"><emph type="i">The migration of the wage-earning classes in England in the early part of the 19th century.</emph> A. Redford. Manchester Ph.D. 1922.</para>
<para id="p27"><emph type="i">The geographical variation of rural population change in eastern Nottinghamshire, 1811&ndash;1911, with particular reference to the correlative effect on this variation of changes in agriculture, rural industry and transport.</emph> M.J. Croft. Leeds M.A. 1961.</para>
<para id="p28"><emph type="i">A study of emigration from Great Britain, 1802&ndash;60.</emph> Monica G. Page. London Ph.D. 1931.</para>
<para id="p29"><emph type="i">Emigration from the British Isles, 1815&ndash;1921.</emph> W.A. Carrothers. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1921.</para>
<para id="p30"><emph type="i">The role of the United Kingdom in the transatlantic emigrant trade, 1815&ndash;75.</emph> M.A. Jones. Oxford D.Phil. 1956.</para>
<para id="p31"><emph type="i">An inquiry into the changing distribution of population in the Chilterns since 1821.</emph> R.S.G. Brocklebank. London Ph.D. 1937.</para>
<para id="p32"><emph type="i">An investigation of changes in population density and distribution, together with changes in agricultural practice in Pembrokeshire during the period 1831&ndash;1931.</emph> G.I. Lewis. Birmingham M.A. 1937.</para>
<para id="p33"><emph type="i">Some geographical aspects of the depopulation of rural Wales since 1841.</emph> V.C. Davies. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1955.</para>
<para id="p34"><emph type="i">A study of the changes in the distribution and density of population in Worcestershire during the period 1841&ndash;1931, and of the geographical factors involved.</emph> E.R.G. Wood. Birmingham M.A. 1950.</para>
<para id="p35"><emph type="i">Population changes in Worcestershire (south of the Birmingham conurbation) and Gloucestershire, 1851&ndash;1951.</emph> A.T. Allen. Wales M.Sc. 1961.</para>
<para id="p36"><emph type="i">Population migration into and from Staffordshire and Warwickshire, 1841&ndash;1901.</emph> R. Lawton. Liverpool M.A. 1950.</para>
<para id="p37"><emph type="i">The upper Calder basin, Yorkshire, in the mid 19th century: a study in historical geography.</emph> B. Barnes. Manchester M.A. 1961.</para>
<para id="p38"><emph type="i">Changes in industry, population and settlement on the exposed coalfield of south Yorkshire, 1840&ndash;1908.</emph> M. Jones. Nottingham M.A. 1967.</para>
<para id="p39"><emph type="i">Population and settlement growth in the south Yorkshire coalfield.</emph> R. Blackledge. Birmingham M.A. 1951.</para>
<para id="p40"><emph type="i">Aspects of the population and settlement geography of the South Wales coalfield, 1850&ndash;1926.</emph> P.N. Jones. Birmingham Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<para id="p41"><emph type="i">The urban geography of the north-eastern rim of the Glamorgan coalfield.</emph> L.H. Bolwell. Wales M.A. 1961.</para>
<para id="p42"><emph type="i">A study of socio-geographic change in the central Welsh marchland since the mid 19th century.</emph> G.J. Lewis. Leicester Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p43"><emph type="i">The distribution of population in England and Wales in 1851.</emph> T.E. Hilton. Manchester M.A. 1938.</para>
<para id="p44"><emph type="i">The internal migration of population in England and Wales, 1851&ndash;1911.</emph> J. Heads. Cambridge M.Sc. 1956.</para>
<para id="p45"><emph type="i">Rural depopulation in Wales, 1881&ndash;1901: an enquiry into its extent, nature, causes, and consequences, with a brief discussion of some of the more important remedies.</emph> R. Jones. Belfast M.A. 1911.</para>
<para id="p46"><emph type="i">The structure and classification of settlement in the Oxfordshire Cotswolds.</emph> J.M. Griffiths. Reading M.A. 1955.</para>
<para id="p47"><emph type="i">A study of the changes in the geographical distribution of industry and population in England and Wales during the 20th century.</emph> J.E.S. Orrin. Wales M.A. 1932.</para>
<page start="173"/>
<para id="p48"><emph type="i">A study of statistics of population and occupations in the counties, urban and rural districts of Wales, 1901&ndash;31.</emph> Mary A. Richards. Wales M.Sc. 1942.</para>
<para id="p49"><emph type="i">Migration from the United Kingdom to the Dominions in the inter-war period, with special reference to the Empire Settlement Act of 1922.</emph> S. Wertimer. London Ph.D. 1952.</para>
</section>
<section id="s3">
<head>POLITICAL HISTORY</head>
<section id="s4">
<head>General</head>
<para id="p50"><emph type="i">The geographic distribution of political opinion in the county of Glamorgan for the parliamentary elections 1820&ndash;1950.</emph> H.M. Williams. Wales M.A. 1951.</para>
<para id="p51"><emph type="i">Political and electioneering activity in south-east Wales, 1820&ndash;52.</emph> I.W.R. David. Wales M.A. 1959.</para>
<para id="p52"><emph type="i">Politics in Anglesey and Caernarvonshire 1826&ndash;52, with special reference to the Caernarvon boroughs.</emph> R.G. Thomas. Wales M.A. 1970.</para>
<para id="p53"><emph type="i">Politics in the borough of Colchester, 1812&ndash;47.</emph> M.E. Speight. London Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p54"><emph type="i">Political issues in the county of Kent, 1820&ndash;46.</emph> Julia H. Andrews. London M.Phil. 1967.</para>
<para id="p55"><emph type="i">Sir James Graham as politician and Home Secretary, 1818&ndash;46.</emph> D.W.J. Johnson. Oxford B.Litt. 1948.</para>
<para id="p56"><emph type="i">The political career of Sir John Bowring (1792&ndash;1872), between 1820 and 1849.</emph> G.F. Bartle. London M.A. 1959.</para>
<para id="p57"><emph type="i">Sir Richard Vyvyan and Tory politics, with special reference to the period 1825&ndash;46.</emph> B.T. Bradfield. London Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<para id="p58"><emph type="i">The political career of Henry, 3rd Earl Grey, 1826&ndash;52.</emph> R. Job. Durham M.Litt. 1959.</para>
<para id="p59"><emph type="i">The relief of the Jewish disabilities in England, 1829&ndash;58.</emph> I. Shapira. London M.A. 1934.</para>
<para id="p60"><emph type="i">Daniel O'Connell and Catholic emancipation.</emph> N.E.L. Guest. Birmingham M.A. 1931.</para>
<para id="p61"><emph type="i">Daniel O'Connell and the Irish parliamentary party, 1830&ndash;47.</emph> A.D. Macintyre. Oxford D.Phil. 1963.</para>
<para id="p62"><emph type="i">The development of a railway interest, and its relation to parliament, 1830&ndash;68.</emph> G.K. Roberts. London Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p63"><emph type="i">Party politics in the county of Staffordshire during the years 1830&ndash;47.</emph> G.B. Kent. Birmingham M.A. 1959.</para>
<para id="p64"><emph type="i">Politics in Leeds, 1830&ndash;52.</emph> D. Fraser. Leeds Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p65"><emph type="i">Life and times of the Rt. Hon. Charles Buller.</emph> E. Sweetman. London Ph.D. 1952.</para>
<para id="p66"><emph type="i">The early career and correspondence of Richard Wood, 1830&ndash;41.</emph> A.B. Cunningham. London Ph.D. 1956.</para>
<para id="p67"><emph type="i">The life and work of H.S. Tremenheere.</emph> C. Holmes. Nottingham M.A. 1964.</para>
<para id="p68"><emph type="i">James Silk Buckingham (1786&ndash;1855) - social and political reformer.</emph> S.T. King. London M.A. 1933.</para>
<para id="p69"><emph type="i">The political career of Henry Goulburn, 1784&ndash;1856.</emph> W.J. Stranz. Durham M.Litt. 1949.</para>
<para id="p70"><emph type="i">A consideration of the use of non-ministerial organisation in the administrative and executive work of the central government, with special reference to the period 1832&ndash;1919.</emph> B.B. Schaffer. London Ph.D. 1956.</para>
<para id="p71"><emph type="i">A consideration of the experience, in Britain, of administrative commissions represented in parliament by non-ministerial commissioners, with special reference to the Ecclesiastical Commission, the Charity Commission and the Forestry Commission.</emph> F.M.G. Willson. Oxford D.Phil. 1953.</para>
<page start="174"/>
<para id="p72"><emph type="i">An enquiry into the change in the character of the house of commons, 1832&ndash;1901.</emph> J.A. Thomas. London Ph.D. 1926.</para>
<para id="p73"><emph type="i">Public opinion and parliament since 1832.</emph> Dorothy C. Johnson. Oxford B.Litt. 1922.</para>
<para id="p74"><emph type="i">The elimination of corrupt practices at British elections.</emph> C. O'Leary. Oxford D.Phil. 1959.</para>
<para id="p75"><emph type="i">The comparative study of parliamentary representation in the new borough constituencies created in 1832.</emph> S.F. Woolley. London M.A. (Ext.) 1937.</para>
<para id="p76"><emph type="i">The effects of the Reform Bill of 1832 on the Lancashire constituencies, especially Liverpool.</emph> W.K. Hunt. Manchester M.A. 1924.</para>
<para id="p77"><emph type="i">Politics and party organisation in Oldham, 1832&ndash;1914.</emph> D. Bickerstaffe. Durham M.A. 1964.</para>
<para id="p78"><emph type="i">Lincolnshire politics, 1832&ndash;85.</emph> R.J. Olney. Oxford D.Phil. 1970.</para>
<para id="p79"><emph type="i">Politics and opinion in 19th-century Bradford, 1832&ndash;80, with special reference to parliamentary elections.</emph> D.G. Wright. Leeds Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p80"><emph type="i">Elections and political behaviour in Durham and Newcastle, 1832&ndash;74.</emph> T.J. Nossiter. Oxford D.Phil. 1968.</para>
<para id="p81"><emph type="i">The parliamentary representation of Wales and Monmouthshire during the 19th century - but mainly till 1870.</emph> O. Parry. Wales M.A. 1924.</para>
<para id="p82"><emph type="i">The party politics of the Black Country and neighbourhood, 1832&ndash;67.</emph> V. Tunsiri. Birmingham M.A. 1964.</para>
<para id="p83"><emph type="i">Parliamentary elections in Derby and Derbyshire, 1832&ndash;65.</emph> C.E. Hogarth. Manchester M.A. 1957.</para>
<para id="p84"><emph type="i">The private member of parliament, 1833&ndash;68.</emph> J.K. Glynn. London Ph.D. 1949.</para>
<para id="p85"><emph type="i">Financial aspects of a parliamentary career in aristocratic and democratic Britain: a study of the expense of membership in the house of commons, with special reference to the 19th century.</emph> W.B. Gwyn. London Ph.D. 1956.</para>
<para id="p86"><emph type="i">The transition from Whiggism to Liberalism.</emph> D.G. Southgate. Oxford D.Phil. 1949.</para>
<para id="p87"><emph type="i">Lord John Russell and the development of relations between parliament, cabinet and parties, 1832&ndash;52.</emph> Mildred E. Gibbs. Manchester Ph.D. 1928.</para>
<para id="p88"><emph type="i">Lord John Russell and the leadership of the house of commons, 1835&ndash;41.</emph> V.B.P. Jones. Wales M.A. 1970.</para>
<para id="p89"><emph type="i">The general elections of 1835 and 1837 in England and Wales.</emph> D.H. Close. Oxford D.Phil. 1967.</para>
<para id="p90"><emph type="i">The idea of political representation in the United States and Great Britain, 1836&ndash;56.</emph> J.L. Moore. Oxford B.Litt. 1953.</para>
<para id="p91"><emph type="i">Lord Melbourne's second administration and the opposition, 1837&ndash;41.</emph> R.H. Cameron. London Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p92"><emph type="i">The relations of Sir Robert Peel with the Crown, 1837&ndash;46.</emph> J.W. Horton. Oxford B.Litt. 1950.</para>
<para id="p93"><emph type="i">The opposition to Sir Robert Peel in the Conservative party, 1841&ndash;6.</emph> D.R. Fisher. Cambridge Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p94"><emph type="i">The Victorian house of lords.</emph> A.L. Sachar. Cambridge Ph.D. 1923.</para>
<para id="p95"><emph type="i">The Russell administration, 1846&ndash;52.</emph> F.A. Dreyer. St. Andrews Ph.D. 1962.</para>
<para id="p96"><emph type="i">John Bright and the representation of Manchester in the house of commons, 1847&ndash;57.</emph> J. Skinner. Wales M.A. 1965.</para>
<para id="p97"><emph type="i">The development of English socialism from 1848 to 1884.</emph> Muriel John. London M.A. 1934.</para>
<para id="p98"><emph type="i">Administrative legislation and adjudication in Great Britain and the United States.</emph> E.R. Baltzell. Oxford D.Phil. 1923.</para>
<para id="p99"><emph type="i">Public opinion and administrative reform in Britain between 1848 and 1854.</emph> A.D. Gidlow-Jackson. London M.A. 1958.</para>
<page start="175"/>
<para id="p100"><emph type="i">The concept of parliamentary representation in Great Britain, 1850&ndash;1918: a history of its development.</emph> A.P. Dean. Oxford B.Litt. 1951.</para>
<para id="p101"><emph type="i">Francis Pulszky's political activities in England, 1849&ndash;60.</emph> T.G. Kabdebo. London M.Phil. 1969.</para>
<para id="p102"><emph type="i">The Liberal party and nationalism, 1850&ndash;1914.</emph> G.E.H. Griffith. Wales M.A. 1957.</para>
<para id="p103"><emph type="i">Cardiff politics, 1850&ndash;75.</emph> I. Humphreys. Wales M.A. 1970.</para>
<para id="p104"><emph type="i">The political influence of the Prince Consort.</emph> U.F.J. Eyck. Oxford B.Litt. 1958.</para>
<para id="p105"><emph type="i">Three Northumberland constituencies in the general election of 1852: North and South Northumberland and Tynemouth.</emph> Anne E. Carnick. Durham M.A. 1966.</para>
<para id="p106"><emph type="i">The relations of statutory and voluntary authorities in public administration in England and Wales.</emph> Muriel McKie. Oxford B.Litt. 1930.</para>
<para id="p107"><emph type="i">The changing role of the administrative class of the British home civil service, 1853&ndash;1965.</emph> G.K. Fry. London Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p108"><emph type="i">Treasury control of civil establishments, 1856&ndash;74.</emph> M.W. Wright. Oxford D.Phil. 1963.</para>
<para id="p109"><emph type="i">Specialist policy in government growth: aspects of state activity, 1860&ndash;1900.</emph> R.M. MacLeod. Cambridge Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p110"><emph type="i">The social and political ideas of Frederic Harrison in relation to English thought and politics, 1855&ndash;86.</emph> P. Adelman. London Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p111"><emph type="i">Aspects of academic radicalism in mid-Victorian England: a study in the politics of thought and action, with special reference to Frederic Harrison and John Morley.</emph> C.A. Kent. Sussex D.Phil. 1968.</para>
<para id="p112"><emph type="i">Some aspects of the radical and democratic career of the 1st marquess of Ripon (1827&ndash;1909).</emph> A.F. Denholm. Wales M.A. 1966.</para>
<para id="p113"><emph type="i">The life and career of Sir William Christopher Leng, 1825&ndash;1902: a prominent Victorian journalist.</emph> K.G. March. Sheffield M.A. 1966.</para>
<para id="p114"><emph type="i">The early life and political development of James Keir Hardie, 1856&ndash;92.</emph> F. Reid. Oxford D.Phil. 1969.</para>
<para id="p115"><emph type="i">The formation of the Liberal party, 1857&ndash;68.</emph> J.R. Vincent. Cambridge Ph.D. 1962.</para>
<para id="p116"><emph type="i">The Liberal party on Merseyside in the 19th century.</emph> C.D. Watkinson. Liverpool Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p117"><emph type="i">The growth of Liberal organisation in Manchester from the eighteen-sixties to 1903.</emph> P. Whitaker. Manchester Ph.D. 1956.</para>
<para id="p118"><emph type="i">Disraeli.</emph> Dorothy I. Hart. Birmingham M.A. 1921.</para>
<para id="p119"><emph type="i">Sir James Fitzjames Stephen: a study of his thought and life.</emph> J.P.C. Roach. Cambridge Ph.D. 1953.</para>
<para id="p120"><emph type="i">The political career of Sir Edward Baines, 1800&ndash;90.</emph> J.R. Lowerson. Leeds M.A. 1965.</para>
<para id="p121"><emph type="i">The career of Arthur Hamilton Gordon, 1st Lord Stanmore, to 1875.</emph> J.K. Chapman. London Ph.D. 1954.</para>
<para id="p122"><emph type="i">Parliamentary elections in Blackburn and the Blackburn hundred, 1865&ndash;80.</emph> J.C. Lowe. Lancaster M.Litt. 1970.</para>
<para id="p123"><emph type="i">The Reform Bill of 1867.</emph> P. Carter. Wales M.A. 1952.</para>
<para id="p124"><emph type="i">The making of the Second Reform Bill.</emph> F.B. Smith. Cambridge Ph.D. 1962.</para>
<para id="p125"><emph type="i">The debate on democracy at the time of the Second Reform Act, 1867.</emph> M.W. Davies. Wales M.A. 1969.</para>
<para id="p126"><emph type="i">The evolution of the franchise in England, with special reference to the Reform Act of 1867 and to the political influence of organised Christianity.</emph> W.G.H. Cook. London M.Sc. 1922.</para>
<para id="p127"><emph type="i">Central organisation and leadership in the Conservative party under the conditions created by the Reform Bill of 1867.</emph> E.J. Feuchtwanger. Southampton Ph.D. 1958.</para>
<page start="176"/>
<para id="p128"><emph type="i">British labour and parliament, 1867&ndash;93.</emph> W.K. Lamb. London Ph.D. 1933.</para>
<para id="p129"><emph type="i">The cabinet in the late 19th century.</emph> S. Gale. Leeds M.A. 1956.</para>
<para id="p130"><emph type="i">The English cabinet, 1868&ndash;1917.</emph> W. Yu. London Ph.D. 1937.</para>
<para id="p131"><emph type="i">A geographical study of the results of British parliamentary elections from 1868 to 1910.</emph> D.J. Morrish. London M.Sc. (Ext.) 1955.</para>
<para id="p132"><emph type="i">The general election of 1868: a study in the bases of mid-Victorian politics.</emph> H.J. Hanham. Cambridge Ph.D. 1954.</para>
<para id="p133"><emph type="i">Mr. Gladstone's leadership of the parliamentary Liberal party, 1868&ndash;74.</emph> J.D. Clayton. Oxford D.Phil. 1961.</para>
<para id="p134"><emph type="i">The political significance of R.A. Cross.</emph> T.O. Hughes. Wales M.A. 1954.</para>
<para id="p135"><emph type="i">The rise of Richard Assheton Cross and his work at the Home Office, 1868&ndash;80.</emph> F.J. Dwyer. Oxford B.Litt. 1955.</para>
<para id="p136"><emph type="i">The career of A.J. Mundella, with special reference to his Sheffield connections.</emph> Margaret Higginbotham. Sheffield M.A. 1941.</para>
<para id="p137"><emph type="i">The radical attitude towards the monarchy and the house of lords, 1868&ndash;85.</emph> E.G. Collieu. Oxford B.Litt. 1936.</para>
<para id="p138"><emph type="i">Social and political aspects of the British monarchy, 1870&ndash;87.</emph> E.T. Galpin. Cambridge M.Litt. 1952.</para>
<para id="p139"><emph type="i">A study of the attitude and policies of the British political parties towards Welsh affairs, disestablishment of the church, education and governmental devolution, in the period 1870&ndash;1920.</emph> K.O. Morgan. Oxford D.Phil. 1958.</para>
<para id="p140"><emph type="i">The history of the Co-operative party in Manchester and Salford.</emph> Cynthia I. Arditti. Manchester M.A. 1953.</para>
<para id="p141"><emph type="i">John Morley: a political study, with special emphasis on the relationship between his political thought and practice.</emph> D.A. Hamer. Oxford D.Phil. 1965.</para>
<para id="p142"><emph type="i">The political ideas of Sir Alfred Comyn Lyall, 1873&ndash;1903.</emph> Mrs. Parveen Hassan. Durham M.Litt. 1962.</para>
<para id="p143"><emph type="i">The railway interest, 1873&ndash;1913.</emph> G. Alderman. Oxford D.Phil. 1969.</para>
<para id="p144"><emph type="i">The history of civil procedure in the Supreme Court of Judicature since 1873.</emph> J.A. Burnes. Oxford D.Phil. 1958.</para>
<para id="p145"><emph type="i">The influence of public opinion on the development of English law, 1880&ndash;1914.</emph> S.D. Temkin. Liverpool M.A. 1938.</para>
<para id="p146"><emph type="i">The political career of Lord Randolph Churchill.</emph> Mary Dempsey. Liverpool M.A. 1949.</para>
<para id="p147"><emph type="i">The origins of the revolt of the British labour movement from Liberalism, 1875&ndash;1906.</emph> D.W. Crowley. London Ph.D. 1952.</para>
<para id="p148"><emph type="i">Henry George and British socialism, 1879&ndash;1924.</emph> P.d'A. Jones. Manchester M.A. 1953.</para>
<para id="p149"><emph type="i">H.M. Hyndman and British socialism, 1881&ndash;1921.</emph> C. Tsuzuki. Oxford D.Phil. 1959.</para>
<para id="p150"><emph type="i">The influence of socialist ideas on English prose writing and political thinking, 1880&ndash;95.</emph> Mrs. Mira S. Wilkins. Cambridge Ph.D. 1957.</para>
<para id="p151"><emph type="i">Origins and early history of the Independent Labour Party, 1880&ndash;1900.</emph> H.M. Pelling. Cambridge Ph.D. 1951.</para>
<para id="p152"><emph type="i">The nature of propaganda and its function in democratic government: an examination of the principal theories of propaganda since 1880.</emph> T.H. Qualter. London Ph.D. 1956.</para>
<para id="p153"><emph type="i">Liberalism in England, 1880&ndash;1914.</emph> W.G.K. Duncan. London Ph.D. 1930.</para>
<para id="p154"><emph type="i">The decline of the Liberal party, 1880&ndash;1900.</emph> B.D. Rubinstein. London Ph.D. 1956.</para>
<para id="p155"><emph type="i">The Liberal party and the house of lords, 1880&ndash;95.</emph> J.E. Williams. Wales M.A. 1961.</para>
<para id="p156"><emph type="i">The general election of 1880 in England, Scotland and Wales.</emph> T.O. Lloyd. Oxford D.Phil. 1959.</para>
<page start="177"/>
<para id="p157"><emph type="i">T.P. O'Connor and Liverpool politics, 1880&ndash;1929.</emph> L.W. Brady. Liverpool Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p158"><emph type="i">Fabian doctrine and its influence in English politics.</emph> A.M. McBriar. Oxford D.Phil. 1949.</para>
<para id="p159"><emph type="i">Fabianism and the Fabians, 1884&ndash;1914.</emph> E.J.E. Hobsbawm. Cambridge Ph.D. 1950.</para>
<para id="p160"><emph type="i">Fabian thought and social change in England from 1884 to 1914.</emph> R.D. Howland. London Ph.D. 1942.</para>
<para id="p161"><emph type="i">The Webbs: a study of the influence of intellectuals in politics (largely between 1889 and 1918).</emph> M. Warner. Cambridge Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p162"><emph type="i">The origin and development of the standing committees of the house of commons, with special reference to their procedure, 1882&ndash;1951.</emph> G.M. Higgins. Oxford B.Litt. 1953.</para>
<para id="p163"><emph type="i">Geographical aspects of parliamentary constituencies in the United Kingdom, with special reference to the period 1885 to 1948.</emph> G.E. Daniels. London M.A. 1963.</para>
<para id="p164"><emph type="i">Economic and political origins of the Labour party from 1884 to 1906.</emph> Dorothy Good. London Ph.D. 1936.</para>
<para id="p165"><emph type="i">London working-class politics and the formation of the London Labour party, 1885&ndash;1914.</emph> P.R. Thompson. Oxford D.Phil. 1964.</para>
<para id="p166"><emph type="i">The Reform Bills of 1884 and 1885.</emph> R.C. Reed. Wales M.A. 1949.</para>
<para id="p167"><emph type="i">The Third Reform Bill, 1884&ndash;5.</emph> G.A. Jones. Cambridge Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p168"><emph type="i">Joseph Chamberlain and the Unauthorised Programme.</emph> A. Simon. Oxford D.Phil. 1970.</para>
<para id="p169"><emph type="i">A study of the social origins and character of British political leaders, 1886&ndash;1936.</emph> W.L. Guttsman. London M.Sc. 1950.</para>
<para id="p170"><emph type="i">The Liberal party and collectivism, 1886&ndash;1906.</emph> L.A. Clark. Cambridge M.Litt. 1957.</para>
<para id="p171"><emph type="i">The Irish nationalist movement in Great Britain, 1886&ndash;1908.</emph> E.P.M. Wollaston. London M.A. 1958.</para>
<para id="p172"><emph type="i">The earlier history of the Home Rule movement.</emph> Dorothy Freeling. Birmingham M.A. 1927.</para>
<para id="p173"><emph type="i">The Salisbury administration and Ireland 1885&ndash;92.</emph> L.P. Curtis. Oxford D.Phil. 1959.</para>
<para id="p174"><emph type="i">An analysis and criticism of the rhetoric of the debates on the Irish Home Rule Bill of 1886.</emph> R.A. Hufford. Durham M.Litt. 1959.</para>
<para id="p175"><emph type="i">The genesis and significance of the 1886 'Home Rule' split in the Liberal party.</emph> D.G. Hoskin. Cambridge Ph.D. 1964.</para>
<para id="p176"><emph type="i">The Liberal Unionist party until December 1887.</emph> J.K. Lindsay. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1955.</para>
<para id="p177"><emph type="i">The general election of 1886 in Great Britain and Ireland.</emph> D.C. Savage. London Ph.D. 1958.</para>
<para id="p178"><emph type="i">The great debate, 1893&ndash;4.</emph> J.F. Finn. Warwick M.A. 1968/9.</para>
<para id="p179"><emph type="i">The educational and political work of the countess of Warwick, 1861&ndash;1938.</emph> Mrs. Margaret A. Blunden, <emph type="i">n&eacute;e</emph> Haigh. Exeter M.A. 1966.</para>
<para id="p180"><emph type="i">The Independent Labour Party, 1893&ndash;1918.</emph> C.T. Solberg. Oxford B.Litt. 1939.</para>
<para id="p181"><emph type="i">An examination of the Labour party during its formative years, 1900&ndash;20.</emph> R.T. Spooner. Birmingham M.A. 1949.</para>
<para id="p182"><emph type="i">Socialism in Gwynedd, 1900&ndash;20.</emph> C. Parry. Wales Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p183"><emph type="i">The history of the Socialist Labour Party of Great Britain from 1902 until 1921, with special reference to the development of its ideas.</emph> D.M. Chewter. Oxford B.Litt. 1965.</para>
<para id="p184"><emph type="i">The Socialist Labour Party and the working-class movement on the Clyde, 1903&ndash;21.</emph> Helen R. Vernon. Leeds M.Phil. 1967.</para>
<para id="p185"><emph type="i">The press and parliamentary privilege in Britain during the 20th century.</emph> C.K. Seymour-Ure. Oxford D.Phil. 1968.</para>
<page start="178"/>
<para id="p186"><emph type="i">The development of the concept of 'national efficiency' and its relation to politics and government, 1900&ndash;10.</emph> G.R. Searle. Cambridge Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p187"><emph type="i">Elections and the electorate in north-west England: an enquiry into the course of political change, 1900&ndash;14.</emph> P.F. Clarke. Cambridge Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p188"><emph type="i">Parliamentary elections and party organisation in Walsall constituency, 1906&ndash;45.</emph> K.J. Dean. Birmingham M.A. 1969.</para>
<para id="p189"><emph type="i">The general election of 1906.</emph> A.K. Russell. Oxford D.Phil. 1962.</para>
<para id="p190"><emph type="i">Some aspects of the history of the Liberal party in Britain between 1906 and 1914.</emph> A.S. King. Oxford D.Phil. 1962.</para>
<para id="p191"><emph type="i">Liberal policies and nationalist politics in Ireland, 1905&ndash;10.</emph> A.C. Hepburn. Kent Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p192"><emph type="i">The development of parliamentary opposition in Britain, 1906&ndash;45, with special reference to the leader of the opposition.</emph> M.A. Mills. London Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p193"><emph type="i">The Conservative party 1906&ndash;11: a study of the internal difficulties of the party.</emph> R.B. Jones. Oxford B.Litt. 1960.</para>
<para id="p194"><emph type="i">Arthur Balfour and the leadership of the Unionist party in opposition, 1906&ndash;11: a study of the origins of Unionist policy towards the Third Home Rule Bill.</emph> J.R. Fanning. Cambridge Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p195"><emph type="i">National and local issues in politics: a study of east Sussex and the Lancashire spinning towns, 1906&ndash;10.</emph> Grace A. Jones. Sussex D.Phil. 1964/5.</para>
<para id="p196"><emph type="i">The political theory of the British Guild Socialists.</emph> S.T. Glass. Oxford B.Litt. 1963.</para>
<para id="p197"><emph type="i">The British general elections of 1910.</emph> N. Blewett. Oxford D.Phil. 1967.</para>
<para id="p198"><emph type="i">Evolution of a national party: Labour's political organisation, 1910&ndash;24.</emph> R.I. McKibbin. Oxford D.Phil. 1970.</para>
<para id="p199"><emph type="i">The Parliamentary Labour party and its relations with the Liberals, 1910&ndash;14.</emph> S.E. Hassam. Aberdeen M.Litt. 1967.</para>
<para id="p200"><emph type="i">The rise of the Labour party in Leicester.</emph> D. Cox. Leicester M.A. 1959.</para>
<para id="p201"><emph type="i">The outsider: aspects of the political career of Sir Alfred Mond, 1st Lord Melchett (1868&ndash;1930).</emph> G.M. Bayliss. Wales Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p202"><emph type="i">The deviations of the parliamentary system of the United Kingdom since 1911.</emph> P.H. Siriex. Oxford B.Litt. 1934.</para>
<para id="p203"><emph type="i">The development of British socialist thought, 1912&ndash;18.</emph> J.M. Winter. Cambridge Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p204"><emph type="i">The Unionists and Ireland.</emph> P.J. Buckland. Birmingham M.A. 1966.</para>
<para id="p205"><emph type="i">The Ulster crisis: opposition to the Third Home Rule Bill, 1912&ndash;14.</emph> A.T.Q. Stewart. Belfast Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p206"><emph type="i">Southern Unionism, 1885&ndash;1922, with special reference to the period after 1914.</emph> P.J. Buckland. Belfast Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p207"><emph type="i">Unionist and Conservative members of parliament, 1914&ndash;39.</emph> J.M. McEwen. London Ph.D. 1959.</para>
<para id="p208"><emph type="i">The decline of the Liberal party in the United Kingdom, 1914&ndash;26.</emph> J.M. McEwen. Manchester M.A. 1953.</para>
<para id="p209"><emph type="i">The Liberal party during the First World War, with special reference to the split of 1916.</emph> E.I. David. Cambridge M.Litt. 1968.</para>
<para id="p210"><emph type="i">The Liberal party: division and decline, 1916&ndash;29.</emph> N.C. Edsall. London M.A. 1960.</para>
<para id="p211"><emph type="i">The Parliamentary Liberal party in Britain 1918&ndash;24.</emph> T.G. Wilson. Oxford D.Phil. 1959.</para>
<para id="p212"><emph type="i">The political influence of organised ex-service men in England and Wales, 1917&ndash;57.</emph> J.G.G. Wotton. London Ph.D. 1960.</para>
<para id="p213"><emph type="i">The 1918 election, with particular reference to the elections in South Wales, Somerset and Bristol.</emph> S.E. Hughes. Wales M.A. 1969.</para>
<page start="179"/>
<para id="p214"><emph type="i">The Independent Labour Party, 1918&ndash;32.</emph> A.J.B. Marwick. Oxford B.Litt. 1960.</para>
<para id="p215"><emph type="i">The Independent Labour Party, 1918&ndash;32, with special reference to its relationship with the Labour party.</emph> R.E. Dowse. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1962.</para>
<para id="p216"><emph type="i">The Liverpool Labour party, 1918&ndash;63.</emph> R.J. Baxter. Oxford D.Phil. 1969.</para>
<para id="p217"><emph type="i">The evolution and working of the British electoral system, 1918&ndash;50.</emph> D.H.E. Butler. Oxford D.Phil. 1951.</para>
<para id="p218"><emph type="i">The political life of Viscount Swinton, 1918&ndash;38.</emph> A. Earl. Manchester M.A. 1961.</para>
<para id="p219"><emph type="i">British public opinion and government policy in Ireland, 1918&ndash;22.</emph> D.G. Boyce. Belfast Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p220"><emph type="i">The economic and social policy of the Conservative party during the period 1919&ndash;39.</emph> S.G. Lees. Manchester M.A. 1953.</para>
<para id="p221"><emph type="i">Unemployed labour as a pressure group in Great Britain, 1919&ndash;39.</emph> R.J. Irvine. Oxford B.Litt. 1951.</para>
<para id="p222"><emph type="i">The formation of the Communist party of Great Britain, 1918&ndash;21.</emph> W.F.H. Kendall. Oxford B.Litt. 1966.</para>
<para id="p223"><emph type="i">The origins of the Communist party of Great Britain and its early history, 1920&ndash;7.</emph> L.J. Macfarlane. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1962.</para>
<para id="p224"><emph type="i">Some aspects of the politics of decontrol in Great Britain and the United States, 1919&ndash;21.</emph> Mrs. Susan M.H. Armitage. London Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p225"><emph type="i">The 'shadow cabinet' in British politics, with particular reference to its development since 1922.</emph> D.R. Turner. Wales M.A. 1966.</para>
<para id="p226"><emph type="i">The general election of 1922.</emph> M.S.R. Kinnear. Oxford D.Phil, 1965.</para>
<para id="p227"><emph type="i">The British general election of 1929.</emph> E.A. Rowe. Oxford B.Litt. 1959.</para>
<para id="p228"><emph type="i">The Labour government and the unemployment question, 1929&ndash;31.</emph> R.J.A. Skidelsky. Oxford D.Phil. 1967.</para>
<para id="p229"><emph type="i">The British Fascist movement, 1932&ndash;40: its development and significance.</emph> R.J. Benewick. Manchester Ph.D. 1963.</para>
<para id="p230"><emph type="i">The Commonwealth party, 1942&ndash;5.</emph> A.L.R. Calder. Sussex D.Phil. 1968.</para>
</section>
<section id="s5">
<head>Foreign and Colonial Relations</head>
<para id="p231"><emph type="i">The origin and growth of the protectorate system, with special study of the system as developed in British colonial history (1800&ndash;48).</emph> W.E. Philpott. London M.A. 1934.</para>
<para id="p232"><emph type="i">Aspects of British colonial policy 1825&ndash;37, with particular reference to the administrations of Major General Sir Richard Bourke in Cape Colony and New South Wales.</emph> Alice H.K. King. Oxford D.Phil. 1960.</para>
<para id="p233"><emph type="i">Attitudes within the Colonial Office towards imperial control of colonial legislation, 1826&ndash;65, with particular reference to the South Australian crisis, which led to the passing of the Colonial Laws Validity Act.</emph> D.B. Swinfen. Oxford D.Phil. 1965.</para>
<para id="p234"><emph type="i">The influence of the Wakefield School on British colonial policy.</emph> K.L.P. Martin. Manchester M.A. 1920.</para>
<para id="p235"><emph type="i">The house of commons and foreign policy between the First and Second Reform Acts.</emph> A.C. Turner. Oxford B.Litt. 1948.</para>
<para id="p236"><emph type="i">The exercise of the judicial function of the privy council, 1833&ndash;1954.</emph> F.O. Akinrele. Hull LL.M. 1955.</para>
<para id="p237"><emph type="i">The problem of the Indian immigrant in British colonial policy after 1834.</emph> I. Mary Cumpston. Oxford D.Phil. 1950.</para>
<para id="p238"><emph type="i">India, Britain, Russia: a study in British opinion, 1838&ndash;78.</emph> V.K. Chavda. Leeds Ph.D. 1961.</para>
<page start="180"/>
<para id="p239"><emph type="i">James Stephen, the development of the Colonial Office and the administration of three Crown colonies, Trinidad, Sierra Leone and Ceylon.</emph> T.J. Barron. London Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p240"><emph type="i">Anti-slavery sentiment in Great Britain, 1841&ndash;54; its nature and its decline, with special reference to its influence upon British policy towards the former slave colonies.</emph> Elsie I. Pilgrim. Cambridge Ph.D. 1953.</para>
<para id="p241"><emph type="i">British colonial administration, 1841&ndash;52.</emph> W.P. Morrell. Oxford D.Phil. 1927.</para>
<para id="p242"><emph type="i">The character of the foreign policy of the earl of Aberdeen, 1841&ndash;6.</emph> Muriel E. Chamberlain. Oxford D.Phil. 1961.</para>
<para id="p243"><emph type="i">The life of Sir Edmund Walker Head, Bart.</emph> J.A. Gibson. Oxford D.Phil. 1938.</para>
<para id="p244"><emph type="i">Attitudes to peace and war in the eighteen-forties and the eighteen-nineties: a comparison of the two decades.</emph> Mrs. Mary A. McCollester. Cambridge M.Litt. 1965.</para>
<para id="p245"><emph type="i">The ideas and activities of John Bright in relation to the empire, 1843&ndash;89.</emph> J.L. Sturgis. London M.A. 1963.</para>
<para id="p246"><emph type="i">John Bright as a critic of foreign policy.</emph> Joyce E. Sanderson. Birmingham M.A. 1923.</para>
<para id="p247"><emph type="i">The administration of the British diplomatic service and Foreign Office, 1848&ndash;1906.</emph> R.A. Jones. London Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p248"><emph type="i">British foreign policy, 1850&ndash;71.</emph> J.C. Kite. Birmingham M.A. 1916.</para>
<para id="p249"><emph type="i">The role of the British parliament in colonial affairs, 1850&ndash;60.</emph> Margaret W. Kerr. Oxford B.Litt. 1952.</para>
<para id="p250"><emph type="i">Edmund Hammond, permanent under-secretary of state for foreign affairs, 1854&ndash;73.</emph> Mary A. Anderson. London Ph.D. 1956.</para>
<para id="p251"><emph type="i">The attitude of the Colonial Office towards the working of responsible government, 1854&ndash;68.</emph> Dorothy P. Clarke. London Ph.D. 1953.</para>
<para id="p252"><emph type="i">Great Britain and belligerent maritime rights from the Declaration of Paris, 1856, to the Declaration of London, 1909.</emph> M.R. Pitt. London Ph.D. 1964.</para>
<para id="p253"><emph type="i">English policy and the execution of the treaty of Paris.</emph> W.E.E. Mosse. Cambridge Ph.D. 1950.</para>
<para id="p254"><emph type="i">Sir Edward Hertslet and his work as librarian and keeper of the papers of the Foreign Office from 1857 to 1896.</emph> Shirley Hall. London M.A. 1958.</para>
<para id="p255"><emph type="i">The formation of policy in the India Office, 1858&ndash;66; with special reference to the Political, Judicial, Revenue, Public and Public Works Departments.</emph> D. Williams. Oxford D.Phil. 1962.</para>
<para id="p256"><emph type="i">The foreign policy of Lord Malmesbury, 1858&ndash;9.</emph> H. Hearder. London Ph.D. 1954.</para>
<para id="p257"><emph type="i">The role of free trade treaties in British foreign policy, 1859&ndash;71.</emph> A. Iliasu. London Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<para id="p258"><emph type="i">The colonial policy of the 5th duke of Newcastle, 1859&ndash;64.</emph> C.C. Eldridge. Nottingham Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p259"><emph type="i">Idealism and foreign policy: a study of the relations of Great Britain with Germany and France, 1860&ndash;78.</emph> Anna A.W. Ramsay. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1925.</para>
<para id="p260"><emph type="i">The select committee of 1861 on colonial military expenditure, and its antecedents.</emph> Marjorie G. Chappell. London M.A. 1933.</para>
<para id="p261"><emph type="i">From status to contract: a biographical study of Sir Henry Maine, 1822&ndash;88.</emph> G.A. Feaver. London Ph.D. 1962.</para>
<para id="p262"><emph type="i">Edward Cardwell at the Colonial Office, 1864&ndash;6 - some aspects of his policy and ideas.</emph> Gabrielle J. Sellers. Oxford B.Litt. 1958.</para>
<para id="p263"><emph type="i">The foreign secretaryship of Lord Stanley, July 1866 to December 1868.</emph> K. Bourne. London Ph.D. 1955.</para>
<para id="p264"><emph type="i">The Judicial Committee of the Privy Council and the distribution of legislative powers in the British North America Act, 1867.</emph> G.P. Browne. Oxford D.Phil. 1963.</para>
<page start="181"/>
<para id="p265"><emph type="i">The place of foreign affairs in British party politics during the period 1868&ndash;92.</emph> T.M. Moloney. London M.A. 1957.</para>
<para id="p266"><emph type="i">Imperial defence, 1868&ndash;87: a study in decisive impulses behind the change from 'colonial' to 'imperial' defence.</emph> D.M. Schurman. Cambridge Ph.D. 1955.</para>
<para id="p267"><emph type="i">The discussion of imperial affairs in the British parliament, 1868&ndash;80.</emph> P.J. Durrans. Oxford D.Phil. 1970.</para>
<para id="p268"><emph type="i">The influence of the treasury on the making of British colonial policy, 1868&ndash;80.</emph> Ann M. Burton. Oxford D.Phil. 1960.</para>
<para id="p269"><emph type="i">The influence of parliament upon the foreign policy of the Gladstone government, 1868&ndash;74.</emph> Sheila Lambert. London M.A. 1949.</para>
<para id="p270"><emph type="i">British policy in West Africa, the Malay peninsula and the South Pacific during the colonial secretaryships of Lord Kimberley and Lord Carnarvon, 1870 to 1876.</emph> W.D. McIntyre. London Ph.D. 1959.</para>
<para id="p271"><emph type="i">A.J. Balfour and the evolution and problems of the British empire, 1874&ndash;1906.</emph> D.O'N. Judd. London Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p272"><emph type="i">John Morley and the empire before 1886.</emph> D.J.B. Trotter. Manchester M.A. 1967.</para>
<para id="p273"><emph type="i">British imperial policy, 1874&ndash;80.</emph> R.L. Kirkpatrick. Oxford D.Phil. 1953.</para>
<para id="p274"><emph type="i">Evelyn Baring's liberal policies in Egypt and India, 1877&ndash;85.</emph> L.P. Burns. Cambridge Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p275"><emph type="i">British public opinion and the rise of imperialist sentiment in relation to expansion in Africa, 1880&ndash;1900.</emph> Patricia F. Knight. Warwick Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p276"><emph type="i">The views on imperial affairs of Henry Labouchere and his activities in this connexion, 1880&ndash;6.</emph> R.J. Hind. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1967.</para>
<para id="p277"><emph type="i">Liberal imperialism, 1885&ndash;1906.</emph> R.W. Edwards. Wales M.A. 1957.</para>
<para id="p278"><emph type="i">Factors and variations in Liberal and radical opinion on foreign policy, 1885&ndash;99.</emph> R.H. Gross. Oxford D.Phil. 1950.</para>
<para id="p279"><emph type="i">Public opinion and the movement for disarmament, 1888&ndash;98.</emph> Merze Tate. Oxford B.Litt. 1935.</para>
<para id="p280"><emph type="i">The colonial and imperial conferences, 1887&ndash;1911: a study in imperial organisation and politics.</emph> J.E. Kendle. London Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<para id="p281"><emph type="i">The invasion of the United Kingdom: public controversy and official planning, 1888&ndash;1918.</emph> H.R. Moon. London Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p282"><emph type="i">The internationalism in the work and thought of William Ewart Gladstone, with reference to present-day theory and practice of internationalism.</emph> J.D. Evans. Wales M.A. 1938.</para>
<para id="p283"><emph type="i">The foreign policy of the Gladstone and Rosebery administrations, 1892&ndash;5.</emph> T.B. Miller. London Ph.D. 1954.</para>
<para id="p284"><emph type="i">The imperial idea in English fiction: a study in the literary expression of the idea, with special reference to the works of Kipling, Conrad and Buchan.</emph> A.G. Sandison. Cambridge Ph.D. 1963.</para>
<para id="p285"><emph type="i">The role of empire in English letters after Kipling.</emph> C. Conybeare. London M.Phil. 1968.</para>
<para id="p286"><emph type="i">British opinion on the development of the Commonwealth of Nations, 1895&ndash;1926.</emph> F.S. Morley. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1931/2.</para>
<para id="p287"><emph type="i">The Liberal party and foreign affairs, 1895&ndash;1905.</emph> T. Boyle. London M.Phil. 1969.</para>
<para id="p288"><emph type="i">Liberal imperialists, 1895&ndash;1905.</emph> H.C.G. Matthew. Oxford D.Phil. 1970.</para>
<para id="p289"><emph type="i">The Liberal party and South Africa 1895&ndash;1902.</emph> J.E. Butler. Oxford D.Phil. 1963.</para>
<para id="p290"><emph type="i">Radical and Labour attitudes to empire, 1896&ndash;1914.</emph> B.J. Porter. Cambridge Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p291"><emph type="i">Sir Wilfrid Laurier and the imperial problem, 1896&ndash;1906.</emph> J.A. Colvin. London Ph.D. 1955.</para>
<page start="182"/>
<para id="p292"><emph type="i">The attitude and policy of the main sections of the British labour movement to imperial issues, 1899&ndash;1924.</emph> I. Henderson. Oxford B.Litt. 1965.</para>
<para id="p293"><emph type="i">The Boer War and the British working class, 1899&ndash;1902: a study in working-class attitudes and reactions to imperialism.</emph> R.N. Price. Sussex D.Phil. 1968.</para>
<para id="p294"><emph type="i">The effects of the Boer War on British diplomatic relations, 1899 - April 1904.</emph> R. Hughes. Wales M.A. 1941.</para>
<para id="p295"><emph type="i">British foreign policy, 1899&ndash;1902.</emph> J.A.S. Grenville. London Ph.D. 1954.</para>
<para id="p296"><emph type="i">A history of the Pan-African movement in Britain, 1900&ndash;48.</emph> P.O. Esedebe. London Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p297"><emph type="i">Aspects of defence policy, 1900&ndash;14, with particular reference to naval-military co-operation.</emph> J. Bertie. Manchester M.A. 1967.</para>
<para id="p298"><emph type="i">The end of isolation: British foreign policy, 1900&ndash;5.</emph> G.W. Monger. Cambridge Ph.D. 1962.</para>
<para id="p299"><emph type="i">Youth and empire: a study of the propagation of imperialism to the young in Edwardian Britain.</emph> J.O. Springhall. Sussex D.Phil. 1968.</para>
<para id="p300"><emph type="i">British policy towards American-Japanese relations, 1901&ndash;7.</emph> R.W. Davies. London M.Sc. 1958.</para>
<para id="p301"><emph type="i">The idea of economic imperialism, with special reference to the life and works of E.D. Morel.</emph> R. Wuliger. London Ph.D. 1953.</para>
<para id="p302"><emph type="i">British pacifism, 1906&ndash;16: a study in the ideology and activities of the British peace movement during the early years of the 20th century.</emph> H.S. Weinroth. Cambridge Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p303"><emph type="i">The elimination of war: an examination of the work of Sir Norman Angell.</emph> R.J. Feilding. Sussex M.Phil. 1966/7.</para>
<para id="p304"><emph type="i">The elimination of war: a study of the writings of Sir Norman Angell on international affairs from 1903 to 1939.</emph> R. Goldstein. Wales M.A. 1966.</para>
<para id="p305"><emph type="i">The Dominions Department of the Colonial Office: origins and early years, 1905&ndash;14.</emph> J.A. Cross. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1965.</para>
<para id="p306"><emph type="i">The African policy of the Liberal government, 1905&ndash;9.</emph> R. Hyam. Cambridge Ph.D. 1963.</para>
<para id="p307"><emph type="i">Opposition to Grey's foreign policy and its connection with the demand for open diplomacy.</emph> E.C. Sterne. Leeds M.A. 1957.</para>
<para id="p308"><emph type="i">Radical Liberal criticism of British foreign policy, 1906&ndash;14.</emph> A.J. Dorey. Oxford D.Phil. 1965.</para>
<para id="p309"><emph type="i">The Colonial Office and political problems in Ceylon and Mauritius, 1907&ndash;21.</emph> L.B.L. Crook. London Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p310"><emph type="i">British defence strategy, 1906&ndash;14.</emph> D.W. Dawson. Manchester M.A. 1966.</para>
<para id="p311"><emph type="i">The formulation of a continental foreign policy by Great Britain, 1908&ndash;12.</emph> M.L. Dockrill. London Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p312"><emph type="i">The formation of British Labour's foreign policy, 1914&ndash;20.</emph> C.D. Armistead. St. Andrews M.Litt. 1970.</para>
<para id="p313"><emph type="i">Attitudes to the war and to the conduct of the war on the western front, 1914&ndash;18.</emph> A.E. Brown. Wales M.A. 1967.</para>
<para id="p314"><emph type="i">Politicians at war, July 1914 to May 1915: a study, with special reference to the emergence of David Lloyd George as a war leader.</emph> G.C.L. Hazlehurst. Oxford D.Phil. 1969.</para>
<para id="p315"><emph type="i">The shell crisis of 1915.</emph> T. Holder. Liverpool M.A. 1967.</para>
<para id="p316"><emph type="i">The development of British war aims, August 1914 - March 1915.</emph> M.G. Ekstein-Frankl. London Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p317"><emph type="i">The abolition of war: a study in the ideology and organisation of the peace movement, 1914&ndash;19.</emph> K.G. Robbins. Oxford D.Phil. 1965.</para>
<para id="p318"><emph type="i">A study of the ideology of pacifism and its background, with special reference to Britain, 1915&ndash;45.</emph> D.A. Martin. London Ph.D. 1964.</para>
<page start="183"/>
<para id="p319"><emph type="i">War aims, peace moves and strategy in British policy, 1916&ndash;18.</emph> V.H. Rothwell. Leeds Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p320"><emph type="i">Lord Robert Cecil and the League of Nations.</emph> P.S. Raffo. Liverpool Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p321"><emph type="i">The Dominions and British foreign policy, 1919&ndash;23: a study in intergovernmental co-operation.</emph> M.D. Henderson. London Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p322"><emph type="i">Labour's foreign policy, 1919&ndash;24.</emph> T.Z. Winnicki. Cambridge M.Litt. 1950.</para>
<para id="p323"><emph type="i">The theory and practice of internationalism in the British Labour party, with special reference to the interwar period.</emph> G.W. Shepherd. London Ph.D. 1952.</para>
<para id="p324"><emph type="i">British public opinion and British naval policy, 1919&ndash;22.</emph> J.W. Sears. Oxford B.Litt. 1957.</para>
<para id="p325"><emph type="i">Great Britain and the Locarno treaties (December 1924 - October 1925).</emph> C.E. Moreton. London M.Phil. 1969.</para>
<para id="p326"><emph type="i">The foreign policy of the second Labour administration, 1929&ndash;31, with special reference to disarmament, foreign trade and the German situation.</emph> D. Carlton. London Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p327"><emph type="i">British attitudes towards disarmament and rearmament, 1932&ndash;5.</emph> J.P. Kyba. London Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p328"><emph type="i">The influence of the Dominions on British foreign policy, 1933&ndash;9.</emph> K.H. Boothroyd. Sheffield M.A. 1966.</para>
<para id="p329"><emph type="i">The Spanish Civil War and British opinion.</emph> K.W. Watkins. London Ph.D. 1961.</para>
<para id="p330"><emph type="i">British left-wing attitudes to the Spanish Civil War.</emph> D.P.F. Lancien. Oxford B.Litt. 1965.</para>
<para id="p331"><emph type="i">British policy in Europe from the Munich Agreement to the Polish Guarantee, 29 September 1938 to 31 March 1939.</emph> R.J. Richards. Durham M.A. 1967.</para>
</section>
<section id="s6">
<head>Reform Movements and Labour Movement</head>
<para id="p332"><emph type="i">The economic ideas of the urban industrial working class of England during the years 1800&ndash;50.</emph> W.H. Warburton. Birmingham M.Com. 1939.</para>
<para id="p333"><emph type="i">Economic conditions and working-class movements in the city of Bath, 1800&ndash;50.</emph> R.S. Neale. Bristol M.A. 1962.</para>
<para id="p334"><emph type="i">The working-class movement in the Black Country, 1815&ndash;67.</emph> G.J. Barnsby. Birmingham M.A. 1965.</para>
<para id="p335"><emph type="i">History of the labour movement in England, 1825&ndash;52: the problem of leadership and the articulation of demands.</emph> D.C. Morris. London Ph.D. 1952.</para>
<para id="p336"><emph type="i">London working-class movements, 1825&ndash;48.</emph> I.J. Prothero. Cambridge Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p337"><emph type="i">London radicalism, 1829&ndash;41, with special reference to the relationship of its middle- and working-class components.</emph> D.J. Rowe. Southampton Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<para id="p338"><emph type="i">A study in London radicalism: the Democratic Association, 1837&ndash;41.</emph> Jennifer A. Bennett. Sussex M.A. 1967/8.</para>
<para id="p339"><emph type="i">Some aspects of Sheffield radicalism.</emph> Mrs. Betty Culcheth. Durham M.A. 1960.</para>
<para id="p340"><emph type="i">Joseph Parkes of Birmingham and the part which he played in radical reform movements from 1825 to 1845.</emph> Jessie K. Buckley. London M.A. 1924.</para>
<para id="p341"><emph type="i">The reform movement in Birmingham, 1830&ndash;48.</emph> H.G. Smith. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1929.</para>
<para id="p342"><emph type="i">English radicalism, 1832&ndash;52.</emph> S. Maccoby. London Ph.D. 1934.</para>
<para id="p343"><emph type="i">Welsh anti-slavery sentiments, 1795&ndash;1865: a survey of public opinion.</emph> G.E. Owen. Wales M.A. 1964.</para>
<para id="p344"><emph type="i">Relations between British and American abolitionists from British emancipation to the American Civil War.</emph> D.M. Turley. Cambridge Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p345"><emph type="i">Some connections between British and American reform movements, 1830&ndash;60, with special reference to the antislavery movement.</emph> L. Billington. Bristol M.Litt. 1966.</para>
<page start="184"/>
<para id="p346"><emph type="i">Some American reformers and their influence on reform movements in Great Britain from 1830 to 1860.</emph> Gloria C. Taylor. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1960.</para>
<para id="p347"><emph type="i">Social aspects of the Chartist movement.</emph> H.J.R. Bennett. Birmingham M.A. 1927.</para>
<para id="p348"><emph type="i">Chartism and the churches, with special reference to Lancashire.</emph> N.J. McLellan. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1947.</para>
<para id="p349"><emph type="i">Chartism in Suffolk.</emph> H. Fearn. Sheffield M.A. 1952.</para>
<para id="p350"><emph type="i">The Chartist movement in Wales.</emph> Myfanwy Williams. Wales M.A. 1919.</para>
<para id="p351"><emph type="i">Chartism in Brighton.</emph> T.M. Kemnitz. Sussex D.Phil. 1969.</para>
<para id="p352"><emph type="i">The life of James Bronterre O'Brien.</emph> A. Plummer. Oxford B.Litt. 1928.</para>
<para id="p353"><emph type="i">George Julian Harney.</emph> A. Schoyen. London Ph.D. 1951.</para>
<para id="p354"><emph type="i">Feargus O'Connor, Irishman and Chartist: a study of his life and work.</emph> E.L.H. Glasgow. Manchester Ph.D. 1951.</para>
<para id="p355"><emph type="i">The teachings of Karl Marx: their influence on English labour organisations, 1850&ndash;1900.</emph> H. Morgans. Wales M.A. 1936.</para>
<para id="p356"><emph type="i">The Northern Reform Union, 1858&ndash;62.</emph> C. Muris. Durham M.A. 1953.</para>
<para id="p357"><emph type="i">George Howell and working-class politics, 1859&ndash;95.</emph> R.G.G. Wheeler. London M.Phil. 1969.</para>
<para id="p358"><emph type="i">The Reform League, from its origins to the passing into law of the Reform Act of 1867.</emph> A.D. Bell. Oxford D.Phil. 1961.</para>
<para id="p359"><emph type="i">The working classes, the Reform League and the reform movement in Lancashire and Yorkshire.</emph> M.R. Dunsmore. Sheffield M.A. 1961.</para>
<para id="p360"><emph type="i">The reform movement in Northumberland.</emph> Florence M. Iddon. Liverpool M.A. 1923.</para>
<para id="p361"><emph type="i">The activity and influence of the English positivists on labour movements, 1859&ndash;85.</emph> R.J. Harrison. Oxford D.Phil. 1955.</para>
<para id="p362"><emph type="i">George Odger and the English working-class movement, 1860&ndash;77.</emph> D.R. Moberg. London Ph.D. 1954.</para>
<para id="p363"><emph type="i">The women's suffrage movement in Britain, 1866&ndash;1914.</emph> Mrs. Constance M. Rover. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1966.</para>
<para id="p364"><emph type="i">The politics of women's suffrage in Britain and the United States of America, 1906&ndash;20.</emph> D.R. Morgan. Cambridge Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p365"><emph type="i">The British labour movement, 1868&ndash;1906.</emph> B.J. Atkinson. Oxford D.Phil. 1970.</para>
<para id="p366"><emph type="i">The labour movement in Wigan, 1874&ndash;1967.</emph> D. Brown. Liverpool M.A. 1968/9.</para>
<para id="p367"><emph type="i">The movement for direct labour representation in Wales, 1893&ndash;1906.</emph> K.O. Fox. Wales M.A. 1965.</para>
<para id="p368"><emph type="i">The miners and politics in England and Wales, 1906&ndash;14.</emph> R.G. Gregory. Oxford D.Phil. 1963.</para>
<para id="p369"><emph type="i">The impact of the labour unrest, 1910&ndash;14, on the British labour movement.</emph> J.D. Fraser. Leicester Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p370"><emph type="i">The new liberalism in Great Britain and the United States - a study in reform thought, with special reference to the problem of industrial concentration.</emph> M.R. Wilson. Manchester M.A. 1967.</para>
<para id="p371"><emph type="i">The labour movement in Birmingham, 1927&ndash;45.</emph> R.P. Hastings. Birmingham M.A. 1959.</para>
<para id="p372"><emph type="i">Left-wing pressure groups in the British labour movement, 1930&ndash;40: some aspects of the relations between the Labour Left and the official leadership, with special reference to the experience of the I.L.P. and the Socialist League.</emph> S. Hornby. Liverpool M.A. 1965/6.</para>
<para id="p373"><emph type="i">The Left in Britain, 1931&ndash;41.</emph> J. Jupp. London M.Sc. 1956.</para>
<page start="185"/>
</section>
</section>
<section id="s7">
<head>ARMY, NAVY AND AIR FORCE</head>
<para id="p374"><emph type="i">The development of English admiralty jurisdiction and practice since 1800.</emph> F.L. Wiswall. Cambridge Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p375"><emph type="i">The army 1815&ndash;54 as an institution: to be considered as regards the administration, organisation, composition, and its relations to the political and social conditions of the country.</emph> M.F. Cunliffe. Oxford B.Litt. 1947.</para>
<para id="p376"><emph type="i">Development of British naval gunnery, 1815&ndash;53.</emph> D.F. MacMillan. London Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p377"><emph type="i">The introduction of the screw propellor into the navy, 1830&ndash;60.</emph> W.M. Petty. London M.Phil. 1969.</para>
<para id="p378"><emph type="i">A history of the royal dockyard schools, with particular reference to the Portsmouth school.</emph> D.R. Jack. London M.A. (Ext.) 1969.</para>
<para id="p379"><emph type="i">Manning the Royal Navy: the reform of the recruiting system, 1847&ndash;61.</emph> R. Taylor. London M.A. 1954.</para>
<para id="p380"><emph type="i">The history of the introduction of the percussion breech-loading rifle into British military service, 1850&ndash;70.</emph> C.H. Roads. Cambridge Ph.D. 1961.</para>
<para id="p381"><emph type="i">The army and public opinion from 1854 to the end of 1873.</emph> H.S. Wilson. Oxford B.Litt. 1955.</para>
<para id="p382"><emph type="i">The naval defence of British sea-borne trade, 1860&ndash;1905.</emph> B.McL. Ranft. Oxford D.Phil. 1967.</para>
<para id="p383"><emph type="i">The emergence of the modern British capital ship, 1863&ndash;70.</emph> S.L. Sandler. London Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<para id="p384"><emph type="i">The introduction and operation of short service and localisation in the British army, 1868&ndash;92.</emph> B.J. Bond. London M.A. 1962.</para>
<para id="p385"><emph type="i">The effect and impact of the administrative reform movement upon the army in the mid Victorian period.</emph> J. Wheaton. Manchester Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p386"><emph type="i">Edward Cardwell's abolition of the purchase system in the British army, 1868&ndash;74: a study in the administrative and legislative processes.</emph> N.H. Moses. London Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p387"><emph type="i">The origin and development of the British and Imperial General Staffs to 1916.</emph> J. Gooch. London Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p388"><emph type="i">The origins and recruitment of the British army &eacute;lite, 1870&ndash;1959.</emph> C.B. Otley. Hull Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<para id="p389"><emph type="i">The Barracks Act of 1890: its motives and consequences, with special reference to Shorncliffe camp.</emph> R. Brook. Wales M.A. 1962.</para>
<para id="p390"><emph type="i">The development of the British army, 1899&ndash;1914.</emph> J.K. Dunlop. London Ph.D. 1936.</para>
<para id="p391"><emph type="i">The military departments and the Committee of Imperial Defence, 1902&ndash;14: a study in the structural problems of defence organisation.</emph> N.J. d'Ombrain. Oxford D.Phil. 1969.</para>
<para id="p392"><emph type="i">The labour movement in Great Britain and compulsory military service, 1914&ndash;16.</emph> M.I. Thomis. London M.A. 1959.</para>
<para id="p393"><emph type="i">The development of official treatment of conscientious objectors to military service, 1916&ndash;45.</emph> J.M. Rae. London Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<para id="p394"><emph type="i">History of the development of the doctrine of strategic bombing, 1914&ndash;26.</emph> R.A. Leonard. London M.Phil. 1969.</para>
<para id="p395"><emph type="i">The theory of strategic air power in the Royal Air Force, 1918&ndash;39: concepts and capabilities.</emph> N.H. Jones. London M.A. (Ext.) 1968.</para>
<para id="p396"><emph type="i">The R.F.C. and R.A.F. in Macedonia: 1916&ndash;18.</emph> T.S.D. Neilon. Glasgow B.Litt. 1969.</para>
</section>
<section id="s8">
<head>ECONOMIC AND SOCIAL HISTORY</head>
<section id="s9">
<head>Finance</head>
<para id="p397"><emph type="i">Capital investment in north-eastern England, 1800&ndash;1913.</emph> A.G. Kenwood. London Ph.D. 1962.</para>
<page start="186"/>
<para id="p398"><emph type="i">The growth of government expenditure in the United Kingdom in the 19th century.</emph> J. Veverka. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1961/2.</para>
<para id="p399"><emph type="i">The origins and early history of savings banks in Great Britain.</emph> S.M. Procter. Liverpool M.A. 1929.</para>
<para id="p400"><emph type="i">Fiscal policy and the silk industry, 1800&ndash;50.</emph> Z. Majid-Hamid. Leicester M.A. 1967.</para>
<para id="p401"><emph type="i">The history of the public debts of the United Kingdom from 1815 to 1939, and the economic doctrine relating thereto.</emph> R.O. Roberts. Wales M.A. 1942.</para>
<para id="p402"><emph type="i">Wales and the corn laws, 1815&ndash;46.</emph> T.H. Williams. Wales M.A. 1952.</para>
<para id="p403"><emph type="i">Opinion on the operation of the bank rate, 1822&ndash;60.</emph> A.B. Cramp. London Ph.D. 1960.</para>
<para id="p404"><emph type="i">The rise and growth of English joint stock banking.</emph> S.E. Thomas. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1934.</para>
<para id="p405"><emph type="i">British sugar taxation since the Napoleonic Wars.</emph> J.L. Mackie. London Ph.D. 1939.</para>
<para id="p406"><emph type="i">Some theoretical views on bank note circulation in England between 1827 and 1913.</emph> E.L.X. Coppieters. London M.Sc. 1953.</para>
<para id="p407"><emph type="i">Ebenezer Elliott: a study, including an edition of his works.</emph> E.R. Seary. Sheffield Ph.D. 1933.</para>
<para id="p408"><emph type="i">The history of slave compensation, 1833&ndash;45.</emph> R.E.P. Wastell. London M.A. 1933.</para>
<para id="p409"><emph type="i">Manchester and the Manchester school, 1830&ndash;57.</emph> J.A. Williams. Leeds M.A. 1966.</para>
<para id="p410"><emph type="i">The activities and organisation of the Anti-Corn-Law League, 1838&ndash;46.</emph> N. McCord. Cambridge Ph.D. 1956.</para>
<para id="p411"><emph type="i">The free traders, 1840&ndash;6.</emph> Sarah J. Caldwell. Leeds M.A. 1911.</para>
<para id="p412"><emph type="i">Sir Robert Peel and the free trade movement in the first half of the 19th century, especially during the years 1842&ndash;7.</emph> W.W. Rollinson. Birmingham M.A. 1930.</para>
<para id="p413"><emph type="i">The history of the Imperial Continental Gas Association, 1824&ndash;1900: a study in British economic enterprise on the continent of Europe in the 19th century.</emph> N.K. Hill. London Ph.D. 1951.</para>
<para id="p414"><emph type="i">The development of banking in the south-western counties in the 19th century, with particular reference to Devon and Cornwall in the period 1840&ndash;90.</emph> N.L. Armstrong. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1937.</para>
<para id="p415"><emph type="i">Mr. Gladstone's fiscal and financial policy, 1841&ndash;5.</emph> F.E. Hyde. London Ph.D. 1931.</para>
<para id="p416"><emph type="i">Lord Derby and the Protectionist party, 1845&ndash;52.</emph> R.M. Stewart. Oxford D.Phil. 1967.</para>
<para id="p417"><emph type="i">Trends in business organisation in Great Britain since 1856, with special reference to the financial structure of companies, the mechanism of investment, and the relations between the shareholder and the company.</emph> J.B. Jefferys. London Ph.D. 1938.</para>
<para id="p418"><emph type="i">Auditors in Britain: patterns of role continuity and change: a study in economic and accounting history.</emph> N. Aranya. London Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p419"><emph type="i">A study of the British economy in the crisis of 1857.</emph> J.R.T. Hughes. Oxford D.Phil. 1955.</para>
<para id="p420"><emph type="i">Joint stock company failures, 1862&ndash;1914.</emph> G.F. Todd. Oxford B.Litt. 1932.</para>
<para id="p421"><emph type="i">Investment trusts and investment companies in the United States and Great Britain since 1868.</emph> S.L. Baskin. London Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p422"><emph type="i">Joint stock companies in Great Britain, 1890&ndash;1930.</emph> A. Essex-Crosby. London M.Com. 1937.</para>
<para id="p423"><emph type="i">The role of the state in British economics from 1870 to 1914.</emph> D.E. Bland. Durham M.Litt. 1968.</para>
<para id="p424"><emph type="i">Home and foreign investment in Great Britain, 1870&ndash;1913.</emph> A.K. Cairncross. Cambridge Ph.D. 1935/6.</para>
<page start="187"/>
<para id="p425"><emph type="i">Home and foreign investment: some aspects of capital formation, finance and income in the United Kingdom, 1870&ndash;1913.</emph> C.H. Feinstein. Cambridge Ph.D. 1959.</para>
<para id="p426"><emph type="i">British overseas investment in iron ore mining, 1870&ndash;1914.</emph> M.W. Flinn. Manchester M.A. 1952.</para>
<para id="p427"><emph type="i">British investment in overseas mining, 1880&ndash;1914.</emph> J.W. McCarty. Cambridge Ph.D. 1961.</para>
<para id="p428"><emph type="i">Sir Stafford Northcote's Sinking Fund and the redemption of debt between 1874 and 1914.</emph> P.C. Gordon Walker. Oxford B.Litt. 1930.</para>
<para id="p429"><emph type="i">Aspects of taxation and expenditure in the United Kingdom, 1890&ndash;1914, with special reference to the growth of the social services.</emph> E.M. Bowen. Wales M.A. 1934.</para>
<para id="p430"><emph type="i">Tariff reform and the Conservative party, 1895&ndash;1906.</emph> B.H.P. Turner. London Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p431"><emph type="i">The origins of the tariff reform movement.</emph> B.H. Smith. Birmingham M.A. 1938.</para>
<para id="p432"><emph type="i">The tariff reform movement, 1903&ndash;14.</emph> Mrs. Jean Wright. Oxford B.Litt. 1960.</para>
<para id="p433"><emph type="i">The Unionist free traders, 1903&ndash;10.</emph> R.A. Rempel. Oxford D.Phil. 1967.</para>
<para id="p434"><emph type="i">Fluctuations in new capital issues on the London money market, 1899 to 1913.</emph> G.L. Ayres. London M.Sc. 1934.</para>
<para id="p435"><emph type="i">The British income tax since 1900.</emph> A.H.F. Dolley. Oxford B.Litt. 1929.</para>
<para id="p436"><emph type="i">British overseas investment in the British empire, 1900&ndash;39.</emph> H.W. Richardson. Manchester M.A. 1961.</para>
<para id="p437"><emph type="i">British capital export, 1900&ndash;13.</emph> J.H.A.M. Lenfant. London Ph.D. 1949.</para>
<para id="p438"><emph type="i">The technique of government borrowing - a study of the methods employed by the British treasury in its borrowing operations, 1914&ndash;39.</emph> Y.-C. Ma. London Ph.D. 1942.</para>
<para id="p439"><emph type="i">British financial policy and the trade cycle, 1918&ndash;39.</emph> G.D. Garton. Liverpool M.A. 1951/2.</para>
<para id="p440"><emph type="i">British overseas investment, 1918&ndash;31.</emph> J.M. Atkin. London Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p441"><emph type="i">Birmingham public opinion in relation to the economic development of the count y, and the achievement of the policies of protection and imperial preference in the period 1919&ndash;32.</emph> J.R.S. Marsh. Birmingham M.A. 1961.</para>
<para id="p442"><emph type="i">Some aspects of British international monetary policy, 1924&ndash;31.</emph> D.E. Moggridge. Cambridge Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p443"><emph type="i">Studies in the abolition of economic controls in Great Britain after the two world wars.</emph> D.H. Aldcroft. Manchester Ph.D. 1962.</para>
</section>
<section id="s10">
<head>Industry and Employment</head>
<section id="s11">
<head><emph type="i">General</emph></head>
<para id="p444"><emph type="i">The development of the industrial landscape of western South Wales during the 19th and 20th centuries.</emph> H.W.E. Davies. London M.Sc. 1955.</para>
<para id="p445"><emph type="i">Economic development of Lonsdale in the 19th century.</emph> D.M. Clark. Liverpool M.A. 1968.</para>
<para id="p446"><emph type="i">An economic geography of Montgomeryshire in the 19th century.</emph> J.M. Powell. Liverpool M.A. 1962.</para>
<para id="p447"><emph type="i">The industrial history of Flintshire in the 19th century.</emph> P.T. Williams. Liverpool M.A. 1933.</para>
<para id="p448"><emph type="i">The industrialisation of Flintshire in the 19th century, being an examination of the changes and developments in the principal industries from 1815 to 1914.</emph> C.R. Williams. Wales M.A. 1950.</para>
<para id="p449"><emph type="i">Historical geography of manufacturing industry in the south-east of England in the 19th century.</emph> A.H. Shorter. Manchester M.A. 1948.</para>
<page start="188"/>
<para id="p450"><emph type="i">The organisation of industrial employment in England in the early 19th century.</emph> Marie Jones. Manchester M.A. 1933.</para>
<para id="p451"><emph type="i">The factory system and the Factory Acts, 1802&ndash;50.</emph> Gertrude Baylis. Birmingham M.A. 1930.</para>
<para id="p452"><emph type="i">Unemployment in British industries, 1815&ndash;50.</emph> A.D. Gayer. Oxford D.Phil. 1930/1.</para>
<para id="p453"><emph type="i">The life and times of Thomas Attwood.</emph> K.E. Richardson. Nottingham Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<para id="p454"><emph type="i">Co-operation and the Owenite-Socialist communities in Britain, 1825&ndash;45.</emph> R.G. Garnett. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1970.</para>
<para id="p455"><emph type="i">The factory controversy, 1830&ndash;53.</emph> Mrs. Ann P.W. Robson. London Ph.D. 1958.</para>
<para id="p456"><emph type="i">The factory movement, <emph type="i">c</emph>.1830&ndash;1850.</emph> J.T. Ward. Cambridge Ph.D. 1957.</para>
<para id="p457"><emph type="i">The development of factory legislation from 1833 to 1847: a study of legislative and administrative evolution.</emph> M.W. Thomas. London Ph.D. 1948.</para>
<para id="p458"><emph type="i">The attitude of the Tory party to labour questions, 1832&ndash;46.</emph> R.L. Hill. Oxford B.Litt. 1928.</para>
<para id="p459"><emph type="i">The movements for shorter hours, 1840 to 1875.</emph> J.S. Hodgson. Oxford D.Phil. 1940.</para>
<para id="p460"><emph type="i">Industrial organisation in Leicester, 1844&ndash;1914: a study in changing technology, innovation and conditions of employment.</emph> P. Head. Leicester Ph.D. 1960.</para>
<para id="p461"><emph type="i">The location of industry in metropolitan Essex.</emph> May Greenfield. London M.A. 1950.</para>
<para id="p462"><emph type="i">The location of industry in London, 1851&ndash;1939.</emph> P.G. Hall. Cambridge Ph.D. 1959.</para>
<para id="p463"><emph type="i">The location of industry in inner north-east London: a study in industrial geography.</emph> J.E. Martin. London Ph.D. 1961.</para>
<para id="p464"><emph type="i">Industry in south-east London (Bermondsey and Southwark).</emph> M.D. Avery. London M.A. 1963.</para>
<para id="p465"><emph type="i">A geographical analysis of the growth of industrial activity in the north-west London area.</emph> Mildred Gascoigne. Durham M.A. 1936.</para>
<para id="p466"><emph type="i">The employment of married women in England, 1850&ndash;1950.</emph> Mrs. Leonore Lockwood. London M.A. 1956.</para>
<para id="p467"><emph type="i">The employment of women in Great Britain, 1891&ndash;1921.</emph> Mrs. Sallie Hogg. Oxford D.Phil. 1968.</para>
<para id="p468"><emph type="i">The industrial development of Birmingham and the Black Country, 1860&ndash;1914.</emph> G.C. Allen. Birmingham Ph.D. 1928.</para>
<para id="p469"><emph type="i">The development of consumers' co-operation in the northeast coast area.</emph> N.S. Ross. Durham Ph.D. 1939.</para>
<para id="p470"><emph type="i">Some social consequences of the casual labour problem in London, 1860&ndash;90, with particular reference to the East End.</emph> G. Stedman Jones. Oxford D.Phil. 1970.</para>
<para id="p471"><emph type="i">The course of public opinion and legal decision, including legislation relating to economic combination and monopoly mainly in Great Britain, in the period 1880&ndash;1914.</emph> Leonora D.F. Peck. Wales M.A. 1929.</para>
<para id="p472"><emph type="i">Factory legislation and its administration, 1891&ndash;1924.</emph> H.A. Mess. London Ph.D. 1926.</para>
<para id="p473"><emph type="i">Trends in capital, employment and output in the British manufacturing industry, 1900&ndash;62.</emph> I. Aristidou. London Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p474"><emph type="i">Industrial change and its effects upon labour, 1900&ndash;14.</emph> A.L. Levine. London Ph.D. 1954.</para>
<para id="p475"><emph type="i">Labour and unemployment, 1900&ndash;14.</emph> K.D. Brown. Kent Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p476"><emph type="i">The growth of manufacturing in the Brighton conurbation, 1901&ndash;63.</emph> B. Thompson. Sussex M.Phil. 1966/7.</para>
<para id="p477"><emph type="i">Public ownership in Great Britain: a study in the origin and development of socialist ideas concerning the control and administration of publicly owned industries and services.</emph> G.N. Ostergaard. Oxford D.Phil. 1953.</para>
<page start="189"/>
<para id="p478"><emph type="i">New growth industries in an era of stagnation and depression, 1919&ndash;39.</emph> J. Harrop. Liverpool M.A. 1966.</para>
<para id="p479"><emph type="i">The problem of unemployment in the United Kingdom, 1919&ndash;29.</emph> K.J. Hancock. London Ph.D. 1959.</para>
<para id="p480"><emph type="i">The social and economic effects of unemployment in Manchester, 1919&ndash;26.</emph> F.J. Rosamond. Manchester M.A. 1970.</para>
<para id="p481"><emph type="i">The social and economic effects of unemployment in the coal and steel industries of Sheffield between 1925 and 1935.</emph> B.J. Elliott. Sheffield M.A. 1969.</para>
<para id="p482"><emph type="i">Changes in the economic geography of the vale of Gloucester since the First World War.</emph> K.J. Noyes. Manchester M.A. 1958.</para>
<para id="p483"><emph type="i">Changes in the industrial geography of west Cumberland, 1928&ndash;57.</emph> Mary R. Hall. Manchester M.A. 1962.</para>
</section>
<section id="s12">
<head><emph type="i">Industrial Relations</emph></head>
<para id="p484"><emph type="i">The history of trade unions in the Yorkshire woollen and worsted industries during the 19th and 20th centuries.</emph> J.F. Weatherhead. Oxford B.Litt. 1924.</para>
<para id="p485"><emph type="i">The progress of labour organisation in the pottery industry of Great Britain.</emph> W.H. Warburton. Oxford B.Litt. 1928.</para>
<para id="p486"><emph type="i">A history of trade unionism in Leicester to the end of the 19th century.</emph> J. Walton. Sheffield M.A. 1952.</para>
<para id="p487"><emph type="i">The history of the miner's bond in Northumberland and Durham: with special reference to its influence on industrial disputes.</emph> H. Scott. Manchester M.A. 1946.</para>
<para id="p488"><emph type="i">The general strike during 100 years.</emph> A. Plummer. London M.Sc. 1927.</para>
<para id="p489"><emph type="i">English trade unions and the problem of emigration, 1840&ndash;80.</emph> R.V. Clements. Oxford B.Litt. 1954.</para>
<para id="p490"><emph type="i">Trade unions and public opinion, 1850&ndash;75.</emph> R.A. Buchanan. Cambridge Ph.D. 1957.</para>
<para id="p491"><emph type="i">A history of trade unionism in the provincial printing industry during the 19th century.</emph> A.E. Musson. Manchester M.A. 1950.</para>
<para id="p492"><emph type="i">History of industrial relations in the British printing industry.</emph> J. Child. Oxford D.Phil. 1953.</para>
<para id="p493"><emph type="i">A hundred years of progress: the record of the Scottish Typographical Association, 1853&ndash;1952.</emph> Sarah C. Gillespie. Glasgow Ph.D. 1954.</para>
<para id="p494"><emph type="i">Social and economic aspects of combination in the printing trade before 1875.</emph> J.H. Richards. Liverpool M.A. 1957.</para>
<para id="p495"><emph type="i">The antecedents and beginnings of the Amalgamated Society of Engineers.</emph> T.H. Robinson. Oxford B.Litt. 1928.</para>
<para id="p496"><emph type="i">Labour relationships in engineering and shipbuilding on the north-east coast in the second half of the 19th century.</emph> J.F. Clarke. Newcastle M.A. 1966.</para>
<para id="p497"><emph type="i">Labour in the merchant service, 1850&ndash;1920.</emph> A. McGeogh. Birmingham M.Com. 1921.</para>
<para id="p498"><emph type="i">British commercial travellers and their organisations, 1850&ndash;1914.</emph> B.J. Avari. Manchester M.A. 1970.</para>
<para id="p499"><emph type="i">Trades councils in England and Scotland, 1858&ndash;97.</emph> W.H. Fraser. Sussex D.Phil. 1968.</para>
<para id="p500"><emph type="i">Industrial conciliation and arbitration, 1860&ndash;1914.</emph> J.H. Porter. Leeds Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p501"><emph type="i">Labour organisation of miners of south Yorkshire from 1858 to 1914.</emph> F. Machin. Oxford B.Litt. 1930.</para>
<para id="p502"><emph type="i">Industrial relations in Birmingham and the Black Country, 1860&ndash;1914.</emph> A. Fox. Oxford B.Litt. 1952.</para>
<para id="p503"><emph type="i">Wages and labour organisation in the brass trades of Birmingham and district.</emph> T.H. Kelly. Birmingham Ph.D. 1930.</para>
<para id="p504"><emph type="i">Railway labour, 1830&ndash;70.</emph> P.W. Kingsford. London Ph.D. 1951.</para>
<page start="190"/>
<para id="p505"><emph type="i">Development of labour relations in the British railways since 1860.</emph> G.C. Halverson. London Ph.D. 1952.</para>
<para id="p506"><emph type="i">The history of the Amalgamated Society of Railway Servants, 1871&ndash;1913.</emph> P.S. Gupta. Oxford D.Phil. 1960.</para>
<para id="p507"><emph type="i">Labour relations in the baking industry in England and Wales since 1860, with special reference to the impact of technical and economic change on union administration and bargaining procedure.</emph> R.F. Banks. London Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<para id="p508"><emph type="i">Agricultural labourers' trade unionism in four midland counties, 1860&ndash;1900.</emph> P.L.R. Horn. Leicester Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p509"><emph type="i">Bradford women in organisation, 1867&ndash;1914.</emph> Mrs. J.C. Scott. Bradford M.A. 1970.</para>
<para id="p510"><emph type="i">The growth of trade unionism in England from 1867 to 1906 in its political aspects.</emph> A.E.P. Duffy. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1956.</para>
<para id="p511"><emph type="i">Aspects of trade union interest in judicial reform, 1867&ndash;82.</emph> D.C. Stainton. Southampton M.Phil. 1968.</para>
<para id="p512"><emph type="i">The National Union of Teachers: a study of the political process within an association of professional workers.</emph> W. Roy. London Ph.D. 1963.</para>
<para id="p513"><emph type="i">The status, functions and policy of the trade union official, 1870&ndash;1930.</emph> P.J. Head. Cambridge M.Litt. 1956.</para>
<para id="p514"><emph type="i">Trade unionism in the Port of London, 1870&ndash;1914.</emph> J.C. Lovell. London Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p515"><emph type="i">The origins and development of new unionism, 1870&ndash;1910.</emph> E.L. Taplin. Liverpool M.A. 1966/7.</para>
<para id="p516"><emph type="i">The labour movement in Hull, 1870&ndash;1900, with special references to new unionism.</emph> R. Brown. Hull M.Sc. 1966.</para>
<para id="p517"><emph type="i">A history of the trade disputes and the formation and operation of the several sliding scale agreements in the South Wales coal trade, 1870&ndash;1903, with special reference to the work of Sir William Thomas Lewis, 1st Baron Merthyr of Senghenydd.</emph> B. Evans. Wales M.A. 1944.</para>
<para id="p518"><emph type="i">A study of industrial relations in the British tinplate industry, 1874&ndash;1939.</emph> E.H. Jones. Wales M.A. 1941.</para>
<para id="p519"><emph type="i">The life and work of William John Parry, Bethesda, with particular reference to his trade union activities among the slate quarrymen of North Wales.</emph> J.R. Williams. Wales M.A. 1953.</para>
<para id="p520"><emph type="i">The Liverpool Trades Council and politics, 1878&ndash;1918.</emph> S. Maddock. Liverpool M.A. 1958/9.</para>
<para id="p521"><emph type="i">The history of the Manchester and Salford Trades Council.</emph> L. Bather. Manchester Ph.D. 1956.</para>
<para id="p522"><emph type="i">The development of industrial relations in the Nottinghamshire coalfield.</emph> A.R. Griffin. Nottingham Ph.D. 1963.</para>
<para id="p523"><emph type="i">Trade unionism in the coal industry until 1900, with particular reference to Lancashire.</emph> R.C. Challinor. Lancaster Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p524"><emph type="i">A history of industrial relations in the South Wales coal industry to 1912.</emph> E.W. Evans. Wales Ph.D. 1955.</para>
<para id="p525"><emph type="i">The political, social and economic factors influencing the growth of trade unionism among the Derbyshire coal miners, 1880&ndash;1944.</emph> J.E. Williams. Sheffield Ph.D. 1959.</para>
<para id="p526"><emph type="i">Industrial relations and the social structure: a case study of the Bolton cotton-mule spinners, 1880&ndash;1910.</emph> E. Thorpe. Salford M.Sc. 1969/70.</para>
<para id="p527"><emph type="i">Unskilled labour unions in South Wales, 1889&ndash;1914.</emph> P.W. Donovan. London M.Phil. 1969.</para>
<para id="p528"><emph type="i">A study of the development of labour relations in the British furniture trade.</emph> N. Robertson. Oxford B.Litt. 1955.</para>
<para id="p529"><emph type="i">The National Union of Agricultural Workers.</emph> M. Madden. Oxford B.Litt. 1957.</para>
<para id="p530"><emph type="i">British newspaper journalism, 1900&ndash;56: a study in industrial relations.</emph> H.C. Strick. London Ph.D. 1957.</para>
<para id="p531"><emph type="i">The Electrical Trades Union and the growth of the electrical industry to 1926.</emph> D.R. Lewis. Oxford D.Phil. 1970.</para>
<page start="191"/>
<para id="p532"><emph type="i">The National Transport Workers' Federation, 1910&ndash;27.</emph> G.A. Phillips. Oxford D.Phil. 1969.</para>
<para id="p533"><emph type="i">The Workers' Union, 1898&ndash;1929.</emph> R. Hyman. Oxford D.Phil. 1968.</para>
<para id="p534"><emph type="i">Methodism and syndicalism in the Rhondda valley, 1906 to 1926.</emph> C.E. Gwyther. Sheffield Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p535"><emph type="i">Syndicalism and industrial unionism in England until 1918.</emph> E.L. Burdick. Oxford D.Phil. 1950.</para>
<para id="p536"><emph type="i">The demand for 'Workers' Control' in the coal mining, engineering and railway industries, 1910&ndash;22.</emph> B. Pribi&cacute;evi&cacute;. Oxford D.Phil. 1957.</para>
<para id="p537"><emph type="i">Rank-and-file movements amongst the miners of South Wales, 1910&ndash;26.</emph> M.G. Woodhouse. Oxford D.Phil. 1970.</para>
<para id="p538"><emph type="i">Rank and file militancy in the British engineering industry, 1914&ndash;18.</emph> J.S. Hinton. London Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p539"><emph type="i">National consultation and co-operation between trade unionists and employers in Britain, 1911&ndash;39.</emph> R.F. Charles. Oxford D.Phil. 1970.</para>
<para id="p540"><emph type="i">The National Minority movement: a study in the organisation of trade union militancy in the inter-war period.</emph> R. Martin. Oxford D.Phil. 1965.</para>
<para id="p541"><emph type="i">The Durham Miners' Association, 1919&ndash;47.</emph> W.R. Garside. Leeds Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p542"><emph type="i">A.J. Cook: miners' leader in the General Strike.</emph> W.G. Quine. Manchester M.A. 1964.</para>
<para id="p543"><emph type="i">The miners' unions of Northumberland and Durham, 1918&ndash;31, with special reference to the General Strike of 1926.</emph> A. Mason. Hull Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p544"><emph type="i">The relations between government and the trade unions in the General Strike of May 1926.</emph> L.D. Thomson. London Ph.D. 1952.</para>
<para id="p545"><emph type="i">Labour relations in the South Wales coal mining industry, 1926&ndash;39.</emph> W.J. Anthony-Jones. Wales Ph.D. 1959.</para>
</section>
<section id="s13">
<head><emph type="i">Specific Industries</emph></head>
<para id="p546"><emph type="i">The Forest of Dean and Bristol-Somerset coalfields: a comparative study in industrial geography during the 19th and 20th centuries.</emph> J.F. Davis. London Ph.D. 1959.</para>
<para id="p547"><emph type="i">Development and location of the clay brickmaking industry in the south-east Midlands of England since 1800.</emph> L.J. Collier. London Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p548"><emph type="i">The location and development of London's leather manufacturing industry since the early 19th century.</emph> J. Statham. London M.A. 1965.</para>
<para id="p549"><emph type="i">The Northampton boot and shoe industry and its significance for social change in the borough from 1800 to 1914.</emph> W.C. Griffin. Wales M.A. 1968.</para>
<para id="p550"><emph type="i">Shoemakers of Somerset: a history of C. &amp; J. Clark, 1833&ndash;1903.</emph> G.B. Sutton. Nottingham M.A. 1959.</para>
<para id="p551"><emph type="i">An historical geography of the Cotswold woollen industry in the 19th and early 20th centuries.</emph> Irene Ellis. Wales M.A. 1946.</para>
<para id="p552"><emph type="i">The credit structure of the West Riding wool textile industry in the 19th century.</emph> A.J. Topham. Leeds M.A. 1955.</para>
<para id="p553"><emph type="i">Dewsbury Mills: a history of Messrs. Wormalds and Walker Ltd., blanket manufacturers of Dewsbury, with an economic survey of the Yorkshire woollen cloth industry in the 19th century.</emph> F.J. Glover. Leeds Ph.D. 1959.</para>
<para id="p554"><emph type="i">A history of Messrs. John Foster &amp; Son, Ltd., 1819&ndash;91. (With an outline history of the worsted industry during the 19th century.)</emph> E.M. Sigsworth. Leeds Ph.D. 1954.</para>
<para id="p555"><emph type="i">The Yorkshire woollen and worsted industries, 1800&ndash;50.</emph> R.M. Hartwell. Oxford D.Phil. 1955.</para>
<para id="p556"><emph type="i">Growth, decline and locational change in the English silk industry of the 19th century: a study in historical geography.</emph> P.D. Wilde. Keele Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<page start="192"/>
<para id="p557"><emph type="i">A history of the slate quarrymen in Caernarvonshire in the 19th century.</emph> Gweirydd Ellis. Wales M.A. 1931.</para>
<para id="p558"><emph type="i">The historical geography of the copper mining industry in Devon and Cornwall from 1800 to 1900.</emph> J.C. Goodridge. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1967.</para>
<para id="p559"><emph type="i">The silversmithing trade in London and the provinces in the first half of the 19th century.</emph> Shirley Bury. Reading M.A. 1959/60.</para>
<para id="p560"><emph type="i">Industrial and social conditions in the Wrexham coalfield (1800&ndash;60).</emph> D.T. Morgan. Liverpool M.A. 1927.</para>
<para id="p561"><emph type="i">The pitmen of Tyneside and Weardale: conditions of their life and work in the first half of the 19th century: with some reference to the keelmen and sailors engaged in the coal trade.</emph> Bessie B.F. Allan. Liverpool M.A. 1920.</para>
<para id="p562"><emph type="i">Hours of work in the coal-mining industry of Great Britain since the early part of the 19th century, with special reference to Northumberland and Durham and with an account of certain movements connected therewith.</emph> N.H. Booth. Oxford B.Litt. 1930.</para>
<para id="p563"><emph type="i">The history of the development of the steam engine to the year 1850, with special reference to the work of west-country engineers.</emph> W.R.M. Caff. London M.Sc. (Ext.) 1937.</para>
<para id="p564"><emph type="i">The development and organisation of the British iron industry, 1815&ndash;67.</emph> A. Birch. Manchester M.A. 1951.</para>
<para id="p565"><emph type="i">The career of Richard Smith (1783&ndash;1868), manager of Lord Dudley's mines and ironworks.</emph> R.P. Fereday. Keele M.A. 1966.</para>
<para id="p566"><emph type="i">The Birmingham steel pen trade.</emph> F.L. Timings. Birmingham M.Com. 1926.</para>
<para id="p567"><emph type="i">William Felkin, 1795&ndash;1874.</emph> S.D. Chapman. Nottingham M.A. 1960.</para>
<para id="p568"><emph type="i">The development of the London brewing industry, 1830&ndash;1914, with special reference to Whitbread and Company.</emph> Diana M. Knox. Oxford B.Litt. 1956.</para>
<para id="p569"><emph type="i">The rise of the British rubber industry.</emph> W. Woodruff. Nottingham Ph.D. 1953.</para>
<para id="p570"><emph type="i">Regional functions of the mineral transport system in the South Wales coalfield, 1830&ndash;1951.</emph> E. Brooks. Cambridge Ph.D. 1958.</para>
<para id="p571"><emph type="i">Changes in the location of the British glass industry since about 1833.</emph> C.M. Brown. London Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p572"><emph type="i">The telegraph industry, 1837&ndash;90.</emph> J.L. Kieve. London M.Phil. 1970.</para>
<para id="p573"><emph type="i">The Ashworth cotton factories and the life of Henry Ashworth, 1794&ndash;1880.</emph> R. Boyson. London Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p574"><emph type="i">The history of John Bowes and Partners up to 1914.</emph> O.E. Mountford. Durham M.A. 1967.</para>
<para id="p575"><emph type="i">Legislation relating to mining in the 19th century (1840&ndash;67).</emph> A.T. Flight. London Ph.D. 1937.</para>
<para id="p576"><emph type="i">An examination of education and training in the coalmining industry from 1840 to 1947, with special reference to the work and influence of the mines inspectorate.</emph> R.H.B. Calvert. Nottingham M.Phil. 1970.</para>
<para id="p577"><emph type="i">Her Majesty's inspectors of mines, 1843&ndash;62.</emph> A.J. Cassell. Southampton M.Sc. 1962.</para>
<para id="p578"><emph type="i">History of tinplate manufacture in Llanelly.</emph> H. Hancocks. Wales M.A. 1965.</para>
<para id="p579"><emph type="i">The history of the catering industry, with special reference to the development of J. Lyons &amp; Co. Ltd. to 1939.</emph> D.J. Richardson. Kent Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p580"><emph type="i">The metal-working machine tool industry in England, 1850&ndash;1914, with special reference to Greenwood and Batley Ltd.</emph> R.C. Floud. Oxford D.Phil. 1970.</para>
<para id="p581"><emph type="i">The London letterpress printing industry, 1850&ndash;1941.</emph> B.W.E. Alford. London Ph.D. 1962.</para>
<para id="p582"><emph type="i">The English cotton industry, 1850&ndash;96.</emph> D.A. Farnie. Manchester M.A. 1953.</para>
<page start="193"/>
<para id="p583"><emph type="i">The house of Spencer, 1853&ndash;91: a study in business history.</emph> P.L. Payne. Nottingham Ph.D. 1954.</para>
<para id="p584"><emph type="i">The Sun Mill Co. Ltd.: a study in democratic investment, 1858&ndash;1959.</emph> R.E. Tyson. Manchester M.A. 1962.</para>
<para id="p585"><emph type="i">A geography of the paper-making industry in England and Wales from 1860.</emph> P.W. Lewis. Hull Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p586"><emph type="i">The Lancashire cotton famine, 1861&ndash;4.</emph> W.O. Henderson. London Ph.D. 1932.</para>
<para id="p587"><emph type="i">A study of the location and migration of the furniture industry in metropolitan England.</emph> J.L. Oliver. London Ph.D. 1963.</para>
<para id="p588"><emph type="i">The development of the engineering industries, with special reference to machinery production since 1870.</emph> J.M. Jackson. Manchester Ph.D. 1953.</para>
<para id="p589"><emph type="i">The development and location of the specialist agricultural engineering industry, with special reference to East Anglia.</emph> C.J. Lines. London M.Sc. 1961.</para>
<para id="p590"><emph type="i">The economic history of British shipbuilding, 1870&ndash;1914.</emph> S. Pollard. London Ph.D. 1951.</para>
<para id="p591"><emph type="i">The economic development of the inland coal-fields, 1870&ndash;1914.</emph> B.R. Mitchell. Cambridge Ph.D. 1955.</para>
<para id="p592"><emph type="i">The heavy iron and steel industry in South Wales and Monmouthshire, 1870&ndash;1950.</emph> J.P. Addis. Wales Ph.D. 1957.</para>
<para id="p593"><emph type="i">The Monmouthshire and South Wales Coal Owners' Association, 1873&ndash;1914.</emph> L.J. Williams. Wales M.A. 1957.</para>
<para id="p594"><emph type="i">The effect of the growth of an industrial concern (Brunner, Mond &amp; Co.) on local politics and affairs in the Weaver valley, 1873&ndash;98.</emph> Hilda M. Rooke. Manchester M.A. 1965.</para>
<para id="p595"><emph type="i">A history of the Lancashire cotton industry between the years 1875 and 1896.</emph> R. Smith. Birmingham Ph.D. 1954.</para>
<para id="p596"><emph type="i">The location of the British car industry, 1888&ndash;1940.</emph> D.R. Littlewood. Leicester M.A. 1962.</para>
<para id="p597"><emph type="i">Rolls Royce: the growth of a firm.</emph> I.S. Lloyd. Cambridge M.Sc. 1951.</para>
<para id="p598"><emph type="i">Some aspects of the British motor manufacturing industry during the years 1919&ndash;30.</emph> A. Holme. Sheffield M.A. 1964.</para>
<para id="p599"><emph type="i">The economic geography of the development and present position of Lowestoft as a port and holiday resort.</emph> A.H. Woolner. London M.Sc. (Ext.) 1956.</para>
<para id="p600"><emph type="i">The development of settlement on the Isle of Thanet in its geographical setting, with special reference to the growth of the holiday industry.</emph> W.T.W. Morgan. London M.Sc. 1950.</para>
<para id="p601"><emph type="i">The seaside resort towns of England and Wales.</emph> J.A. Barrett. London Ph.D. 1958.</para>
<para id="p602"><emph type="i">The Lincolnshire coast holiday region.</emph> R.E. Pearson. Nottingham M.A. 1965.</para>
<para id="p603"><emph type="i">The history and development of the iron and steel welded tube trade, with particular reference to the rise and eventual decline of the trade in the town of Wednesbury, Staffordshire.</emph> S.J. Langley. Birmingham M.Com. 1948.</para>
<para id="p604"><emph type="i">The British electrical industry, 1875&ndash;1914.</emph> I.C.R. Byatt. Oxford D.Phil. 1962.</para>
<para id="p605"><emph type="i">'The technological challenge': some aspects of the early development of the electrical lighting industry, with special reference to England and the U.S.A., 1882&ndash;1919.</emph> J.P. Brown. Sheffield M.A. 1964.</para>
<para id="p606"><emph type="i">The development of the electricity supply industry in Great Britain.</emph> S. Judek. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1946/7.</para>
<para id="p607"><emph type="i">The growth and progress of electrical manufacturing industry in Great Britain.</emph> Elsie Yates. Manchester M.A. 1936.</para>
<para id="p608"><emph type="i">The development and organisation of the artificial silk industry in Great Britain.</emph> E. Jones. Wales M.A. 1940.</para>
<para id="p609"><emph type="i">Mechanisation in British and American bituminous coal mines, 1890&ndash;1939.</emph> C.A. Pauli. London M.Phil. 1968.</para>
<page start="194"/>
<para id="p610"><emph type="i">The cotton spinning industry in the Oldham district, 1896&ndash;1914.</emph> F. Jones. Manchester M.A. 1959.</para>
<para id="p611"><emph type="i">The tobacco manufacturing industry of Great Britain in the 20th century.</emph> W.C. Woolley. Wales M.A. 1953.</para>
<para id="p612"><emph type="i">The sugar beet and sugar refining industry in the United Kingdom, 1900&ndash;52.</emph> E.D. Altschuler. Manchester M.A. 1953.</para>
<para id="p613"><emph type="i">The development and location of the aluminium industry in the United Kingdom.</emph> T.G.L. Hopkins. Oxford B.Litt. 1958.</para>
<para id="p614"><emph type="i">An economic history of the British aircraft industry, 1908&ndash;48.</emph> R.F. Ryder. Southampton M.Sc. 1957/8.</para>
<para id="p615"><emph type="i">Developments in the British film industry before 1918.</emph> Rachel Low. London Ph.D. 1951.</para>
<para id="p616"><emph type="i">The positions of the skilled and less skilled workman in the engineering and building trades (1914&ndash;25).</emph> J.R. Hicks. Oxford B.Litt. 1927.</para>
<para id="p617"><emph type="i">The South Wales coalfield during government control, 1914&ndash;21.</emph> J. Thomas. Wales M.A. 1925.</para>
<para id="p618"><emph type="i">The development of the road (motor) haulage industry in Great Britain, with special reference to the years 1918&ndash;46.</emph> S.M.B. Green. Oxford B.Litt. 1948.</para>
<para id="p619"><emph type="i">The development of the South Wales tinplate industry, with special reference to 1919&ndash;39.</emph> E.E. Watkin. Wales M.A. 1949.</para>
<para id="p620"><emph type="i">The British shipbuilding industry, with special reference to the period 1919&ndash;39.</emph> L. Jones. Wales M.A. 1952.</para>
<para id="p621"><emph type="i">The British iron and steel trades since 1920.</emph> E. Davies. Wales M.A. 1937.</para>
<para id="p622"><emph type="i">The United Kingdom meat market, 1920&ndash;59.</emph> R.H. Tuckwell. Cambridge M.Sc. 1963/4.</para>
</section>
</section>
<section id="s14">
<head>Trade</head>
<para id="p623"><emph type="i">English foreign trade in the first half of the 19th century, together with some observations on the war period of 1793&ndash;1814.</emph> J.S. Jones. London M.Sc. 1928.</para>
<para id="p624"><emph type="i">Retail trade in Great Britain, 1800&ndash;50.</emph> D.G. Alexander. London Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p625"><emph type="i">The function of the merchant in specific Liverpool import trades, 1820&ndash;50.</emph> D.M. Williams. Liverpool M.A. 1964.</para>
<para id="p626"><emph type="i">The policy of the Board of Trade in relation to British tariffs and foreign trade, 1830&ndash;42.</emph> Lucy M. Brown. London Ph.D. 1955.</para>
<para id="p627"><emph type="i">Business in two continents, 1845&ndash;73. [Rathbones of Liverpool in America and Asia.]</emph> Sheila Marriner. Liverpool Ph.D. 1957/8.</para>
<para id="p628"><emph type="i">The influence of the coal trade upon the development of the mercantile marine and the foreign trade of Great Britain during the second half of the 19th century.</emph> E. Pritchard. Oxford B.Litt. 1924.</para>
<para id="p629"><emph type="i">Changes in the pattern of the British export trade (with special reference to the continent) between 1851 and 1873.</emph> Jean Cheetham. Manchester M.A. 1955.</para>
<para id="p630"><emph type="i">British trade fluctuations, 1868&ndash;86: a chronicle and a commentary.</emph> W.W. Rostow. Oxford B.Litt. 1938.</para>
<para id="p631"><emph type="i">The development of the overseas trade of the British empire, with particular reference to the period 1870&ndash;1939.</emph> K. Evans. Manchester M.A. 1956.</para>
<para id="p632"><emph type="i">British overseas trade, 1870&ndash;1914.</emph> S.B. Saul. Birmingham Ph.D. 1953.</para>
<para id="p633"><emph type="i">The British economy and the trade cycle, 1886&ndash;96.</emph> W.A. Sinclair. Oxford D.Phil. 1958.</para>
<para id="p634"><emph type="i">The geographical basis, character and organisation of the import trade of London from the East Indies, with special reference to the 20th century.</emph> L. Brettle. Oxford B.Litt. 1930.</para>
<page start="195"/>
</section>
<section id="s15">
<head>Transport and Communications</head>
<para id="p635"><emph type="i">The dock companies in London, 1796&ndash;1864: a history of the agitation for, and provision of, wet docks in the Port of London.</emph> R.A.H. Page. Sheffield M.A. 1959.</para>
<para id="p636"><emph type="i">A study of the function of Ipswich as a centre in East Anglia and its development as a port since 1805.</emph> A.J. Starr. London M.Sc. 1939.</para>
<para id="p637"><emph type="i">The major provincial seaports of England, 1800&ndash;50, excluding their coastwise trade.</emph> D.F. King. Manchester M.A. 1959.</para>
<para id="p638"><emph type="i">History of the port of Cardiff in relation to its hinterland with special reference to the years 1830&ndash;1914.</emph> T.M. Hodges. London M.Sc. (Ext.) 1946.</para>
<para id="p639"><emph type="i">A geographical study of the trade of the Dorset ports, 1815&ndash;1914.</emph> P.J. Perry. Cambridge Ph.D. 1963.</para>
<para id="p640"><emph type="i">The Holyhead road, 1810&ndash;42: a study in highway administration.</emph> M. Hughes. Wales M.A. 1963.</para>
<para id="p641"><emph type="i">The development of road transport in Cumberland, Westmorland and the Furness district of Lancashire, 1800&ndash;85.</emph> L.A. Williams. Leicester Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p642"><emph type="i">British railway management in the 19th century, with special reference to the career of Captain Mark Huish (1808&ndash;67).</emph> T.R. Gourvish. London Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p643"><emph type="i">The origins and development of four constituent lines of the North-Eastern Railway, 1824&ndash;54.</emph> D. Brooke. Hull M.A. 1961.</para>
<para id="p644"><emph type="i">The history of the Barry Dock and Railways Company in relation to the development of the South Wales coalfield.</emph> L.N.A. Davies. Wales M.A. 1938.</para>
<para id="p645"><emph type="i">A railway geography of the east Midlands, 1830&ndash;1905.</emph> N. Cossons. Liverpool M.A. 1969.</para>
<para id="p646"><emph type="i">The railway as a factor in the location of manufacturing industry in the east Midlands.</emph> G.E. Bell. Nottingham Ph.D. 1958.</para>
<para id="p647"><emph type="i">A study of the transport facilities of the Nottinghamshire-Derbyshire coalfield.</emph> S.R. Shaw. London M.A. (Ext.) 1956.</para>
<para id="p648"><emph type="i">Port developments and commerce of Newport, Monmouthshire, 1835&ndash;1935.</emph> Edith M.E. Davies. Wales M.A. 1938.</para>
<para id="p649"><emph type="i">Geographical aspects of the railway industry.</emph> B.J. Turton. Nottingham Ph.D. 1960.</para>
<para id="p650"><emph type="i">The evolution of the railway network of south-east England.</emph> E.A. Course. London Ph.D. 1958.</para>
<para id="p651"><emph type="i">The growth of south-east London, 1836&ndash;1914, with special reference to the development of communications.</emph> Mrs. Eileen M. Rolfe, <emph type="i">n&eacute;e</emph> Pierce. London Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p652"><emph type="i">A century's extension of passenger transport facilities (1830&ndash;1930), within the present London Transport Board's area and its relation to population spread.</emph> Minnie L. Moore. London Ph.D. 1948.</para>
<para id="p653"><emph type="i">The historical geography of the Newcastle and Carlisle railway system up to 1914.</emph> G. Whittle. Belfast M.A. 1969.</para>
<para id="p654"><emph type="i">The history of employment in the British Post Office.</emph> L.S. Martinuzzi. Oxford B.Litt. 1952.</para>
<para id="p655"><emph type="i">The development of public passenger transport services in Wales.</emph> E. Roberts. Wales M.Sc. 1960.</para>
<para id="p656"><emph type="i">The historical geography of railways in Yorkshire.</emph> J.H. Appleton. Durham M.Sc. 1958.</para>
<para id="p657"><emph type="i">The finances of the Lancashire and Yorkshire Railway, 1835&ndash;73.</emph> S.A. Broadbridge. London Ph.D. 1957.</para>
<para id="p658"><emph type="i">Railways in the northern Pennines to 1880.</emph> H.W. Parris. Leeds M.A. 1954.</para>
<para id="p659"><emph type="i">The regulation of railways by the government in Great Britain: the work of the Board of Trade and the Railway Commissioners, 1840&ndash;67.</emph> H.W. Parris. Leicester Ph.D. 1959.</para>
<page start="196"/>
<para id="p660"><emph type="i">Some geographical aspects of the construction of the London and Birmingham Railway and its influence on the growth of towns along the route.</emph> P.S. Richards. London M.A. 1957.</para>
<para id="p661"><emph type="i">Studies in the railway geography of the Birmingham region.</emph> P.L. Clark. Birmingham M.A. 1952.</para>
<para id="p662"><emph type="i">The East Anglian Railways Company: a study in railway and financial history.</emph> D.I. Gordon. Nottingham Ph.D. 1964.</para>
<para id="p663"><emph type="i">The effect of the railways on the growth of the economy of England and Wales, 1840&ndash;70.</emph> G.R. Hawke. Oxford D.Phil. 1968.</para>
<para id="p664"><emph type="i">History of the Eastern Counties railway in relation to contemporary economic development.</emph> Evelyn Doble. London Ph.D. 1939.</para>
<para id="p665"><emph type="i">Sir William Mackinnon, shipowner, 1823&ndash;93.</emph> I.K. Orchardson. London Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p666"><emph type="i">An examination of the factors which link Bristol dock policy with the development of the tramp shipping of the port, 1840&ndash;90.</emph> J.R. Stevens. Bristol M.A. 1940.</para>
<para id="p667"><emph type="i">The changing industrial geography of the port and city of Bristol since 1851: a study in port function.</emph> D.J. Webb. London M.Phil. 1967.</para>
<para id="p668"><emph type="i">A British ship-owning company in the late 19th and early 20th centuries: an analysis of the voyage accounts of William Thomson &amp; Co.</emph> T.E. Milne. Glasgow B.Litt. 1966.</para>
<para id="p669"><emph type="i">The development and decline of public transport services in mid Wales, 1861&ndash;1966, and the effects thereof.</emph> G.W. Jones. London M.A. 1968.</para>
<para id="p670"><emph type="i">The tramways of Kingston-upon-Hull, 1871&ndash;1945.</emph> G.A. Lee. Sheffield Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p671"><emph type="i">The streets and street traffic of Manchester, 1890&ndash;1914: a case study of the traffic problem.</emph> B.W. Beacroft. Leicester M.A. 1963.</para>
<para id="p672"><emph type="i">An analysis of public passenger transport services in West Yorkshire, 1896&ndash;1963.</emph> D. Scrafton. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1968.</para>
<para id="p673"><emph type="i">Government intervention in the British merchant service in the 19th century.</emph> R.G. Newey. Exeter M.A. 1970.</para>
<para id="p674"><emph type="i">State subsidies to the British merchant marine, 1900&ndash;50.</emph> L. Saletan. London M.Sc. 1952.</para>
<para id="p675"><emph type="i">The railway rates problem and combination amongst the railway companies of Great Britain, 1893&ndash;1913.</emph> P.J. Cain. Oxford B.Litt. 1968.</para>
<para id="p676"><emph type="i">The economic development of the port of Bristol, 1900&ndash;45.</emph> F.E. Cooke. London M.Sc. (Ext.) 1953.</para>
<para id="p677"><emph type="i">The beginnings of British civil air transport, 1919&ndash;24.</emph> E. Birkhead. Leicester M.A. 1959.</para>
<para id="p678"><emph type="i">A political and economic history of the development of internal civil aviation in Great Britain from 1919 to 1939.</emph> H.C.L. Leech. Manchester M.A. 1950.</para>
<para id="p679"><emph type="i">A geographical study of the evolution of civil air transport, 1918&ndash;57.</emph> A.F. Williams. Bristol Ph.D. 1960.</para>
</section>
<section id="s16">
<head>Agrarian History</head>
<para id="p680"><emph type="i">The history of the agricultural geography of Great Britain since 1800.</emph> J. McDermott. London M.Sc. (Ext.) 1943.</para>
<para id="p681"><emph type="i">A study of a rural and maritime community in the 19th century, with special reference to the relation between agriculture and shipping.</emph> D. Thomas. Liverpool M.A. 1928.</para>
<para id="p682"><emph type="i">The response of agriculture in Staffordshire to the price changes of the 19th century.</emph> R.W. Sturgess. Manchester Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<para id="p683"><emph type="i">Harvest technology and labour supply in Britain, 1790&ndash;1870.</emph> E.J.T. Collins. Nottingham Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p684"><emph type="i">Aspects of agricultural and rural change in Kent, 1800&ndash;1900.</emph> D.W. Harvey. Cambridge Ph.D. 1961.</para>
<page start="197"/>
<para id="p685"><emph type="i">Some aspects of the economic geography of the Sussex South Downs and contiguous land in the 19th century.</emph> Aileen E. Swanwick. Cambridge M.Sc. 1952/3.</para>
<para id="p686"><emph type="i">Economic and social aspects of landownership in the 19th century.</emph> F.M. Reid. Oxford B.Litt. 1957.</para>
<para id="p687"><emph type="i">The draining of the marshlands of east Yorkshire.</emph> June A. Sheppard. London Ph.D. 1956.</para>
<para id="p688"><emph type="i">Welsh agriculture, 1815&ndash;1914.</emph> D.W. Howell. London Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p689"><emph type="i">The evolution of high farming, 1815&ndash;65, with reference to Herefordshire.</emph> E.L. Jones. Oxford D.Phil. 1962.</para>
<para id="p690"><emph type="i">The agricultural labourer in west Oxfordshire: an account of some aspects of the life of west Oxfordshire agricultural labourers and the economic background in the 19th century.</emph> D.N. Bates. Birmingham M.A. 1955.</para>
<para id="p691"><emph type="i">The Norfolk agricultural labourer, 1834&ndash;84.</emph> Lillie M. Springall. London Ph.D. 1935.</para>
<para id="p692"><emph type="i">Changing attitudes to the employment of women and children on the land between the eighteen-thirties and the eighteen-seventies, with particular reference to the county of Sussex.</emph> Mrs. Ena M. Ainsworth. Sussex M.A. 1969/70.</para>
<para id="p693"><emph type="i">Land use changes in West Gower, 1840&ndash;1950.</emph> J.C. Grove. Wales M.A. 1956.</para>
<para id="p694"><emph type="i">Changes in land utilisation in the south-east of Denbighshire, 1840&ndash;1938.</emph> J.B. Jarvis. Wales M.A. 1940.</para>
<para id="p695"><emph type="i">The land utilisation of the London basin: a study of the existing conditions and historical changes, 1840&ndash;1935.</emph> E.C. Willatts. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1937.</para>
<para id="p696"><emph type="i">Changes in the agricultural geography of the parishes of Bockleton, Kyre Magna, Tenbury Township and Foreign (Worcs.) and Hampton Charles (Herefs.) from 1841 to <emph type="i">c</emph>.1958.</emph> Mrs. Constance Pritchard. Birmingham M.A. 1965.</para>
<para id="p697"><emph type="i">The changes in the numbers of agricultural labourers and in their wages and efficiency during the past fifty years, and the causes of these changes, with special reference to Wales.</emph> E. Hughes. Wales M.A. 1909.</para>
<para id="p698"><emph type="i">The treatment of 'land' in English social and political theory, 1840&ndash;85.</emph> Mrs. Joyce Macaskill. Oxford B.Litt. 1959.</para>
<para id="p699"><emph type="i">The economic and social background of the English landed interest, 1840&ndash;70, with particular reference to the estates of the dukes of Northumberland.</emph> F.M.L. Thompson. Oxford D.Phil. 1956.</para>
<para id="p700"><emph type="i">The rural landscape of the Blackmore vale, <emph type="i">c</emph>.1840.</emph> R.F.J. Chiplen. Exeter M.A. 1969.</para>
<para id="p701"><emph type="i">An agricultural geography of Essex, <emph type="i">c</emph>.1840.</emph> E.A. Cox. London M.A. 1963.</para>
<para id="p702"><emph type="i">The agricultural geography of the Chilterns, <emph type="i">c</emph>.1840.</emph> F.D. Hartley. London M.A. 1953.</para>
<para id="p703"><emph type="i">The development of market gardening in England, 1850&ndash;1914.</emph> R.J. Battersby. London Ph.D. 1960.</para>
<para id="p704"><emph type="i">Market gardening in eastern and central Bedfordshire.</emph> F. Beavington. London Ph.D. 1961.</para>
<para id="p705"><emph type="i">A historical and economic study of the development and organisation of the market gardening industry in the vale of Evesham.</emph> H.J. Meredith. Oxford B.Litt. 1929.</para>
<para id="p706"><emph type="i">Changes in land utilisation in the East Anglian Breckland during the past 100 years.</emph> E.H. Griffith. Wales M.A. 1955.</para>
<para id="p707"><emph type="i">The influence of legislation and economic conditions on the rent of agricultural land since 1850, with special reference to East Anglia and with a statistical analysis of some East Anglian farm rents.</emph> Carleen O'Loughlin. Cambridge M.Sc. 1953.</para>
<para id="p708"><emph type="i">A study of capital and rental values of agricultural land in England and Wales between 1858 and 1958.</emph> J.T. Ward. London Ph.D. 1960.</para>
<page start="198"/>
<para id="p709"><emph type="i">Landownership and rural population, with special reference to Leicestershire in the mid 19th century.</emph> D.R. Mills. Leicester Ph.D. 1963.</para>
<para id="p710"><emph type="i">The history of the earl of Scarbrough's estate, 1860&ndash;1900.</emph> T.W. Beastall. Manchester M.A. 1954.</para>
<para id="p711"><emph type="i">An examination of some factors influencing population changes in rural communities in an area of the north-east Midlands of England, 1861&ndash;1911, with special reference to the impact of agricultural depression.</emph> M.F. Bunce. Sheffield Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p712"><emph type="i">The agricultural geography of the Chilterns, 1870&ndash;1951.</emph> J.T. Coppock. London Ph.D. 1960.</para>
<para id="p713"><emph type="i">Agricultural co-operation in Hampshire.</emph> H. Newman. Cambridge M.Litt. 1949.</para>
<para id="p714"><emph type="i">A portion of west Sussex: a study of agriculture and population.</emph> E. Cook. Liverpool M.A. 1939.</para>
<para id="p715"><emph type="i">The history of landownership since 1870, with special reference to conditions in Cambridgeshire.</emph> J.J. Macgregor. Oxford B.Litt. 1938.</para>
<para id="p716"><emph type="i">The economic development of agriculture in east Lancashire, 1870&ndash;1939.</emph> T.W. Fletcher. Leeds M.Sc. 1954.</para>
<para id="p717"><emph type="i">English agriculture and the labourer, 1840&ndash;85, with special reference to the depression of the 'seventies'.</emph> Norah Yates. Birmingham M.A. 1930.</para>
<para id="p718"><emph type="i">The effects of agricultural depression on the English estates of the dukes of Sutherland, 1870&ndash;1900.</emph> R. Perren. Nottingham Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p719"><emph type="i">The making of a landed &eacute;lite: social mobility in Lancashire society.</emph> R.O. Knapp. Lancaster Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p720"><emph type="i">The draining of the Somerset Levels.</emph> M. Williams. Wales Ph.D. 1960.</para>
<para id="p721"><emph type="i">Land reform, 1880&ndash;1919: a study of the activities of the English Land Restoration League and the Land Nationalisation Society.</emph> A.J. Peacock. Southampton M.A. 1962.</para>
<para id="p722"><emph type="i">Jesse Collings and the back to the land movement.</emph> W.I. Wilks. Birmingham M.A. 1964.</para>
<para id="p723"><emph type="i">The migration of farmers in relation to the economic development of agriculture in Great Britain since 1880.</emph> E. Lorrain-Smith. Oxford B.Litt. 1931.</para>
<para id="p724"><emph type="i">A study of the changes that have taken place in farm size in Carmarthenshire since the end of the 19th century.</emph> J.W.G. Jasper. Wales M.Sc. 1959.</para>
<para id="p725"><emph type="i">The progress of land settlement in England since 1892, with a historical introduction.</emph> G.-L. von dem Knesebeck. Oxford B.Litt. 1935.</para>
<para id="p726"><emph type="i">An historical review of the development of British agricultural policies and programmes since 1900.</emph> A.V. Vickery. Oxford B.Litt. 1958.</para>
<para id="p727"><emph type="i">The derelict villages of Durham County.</emph> A. Temple. Durham M.Litt. 1940.</para>
<para id="p728"><emph type="i">British agricultural developments in the inter-war period 1919&ndash;39, with special reference to the contribution of interest groups.</emph> Priscilla J. Baines. Oxford B.Litt. 1969.</para>
<para id="p729"><emph type="i">Labour on the land since 1920.</emph> W.H. Pedley. Oxford B.Litt. 1940.</para>
<para id="p730"><emph type="i">A study of land-use changes in the period 1928&ndash;55 in part of south-west Yorkshire.</emph> R.M. Koerner. Sheffield M.A. 1961.</para>
</section>
<section id="s17">
<head>Social History</head>
<para id="p731"><emph type="i">The development of the law relating to children in the 19th and 20th centuries.</emph> T.E. James. London Ph.D. 1957.</para>
<para id="p732"><emph type="i">The reform of the law and administration of charities in the 19th century.</emph> B. Hargrove. London Ph.D. 1963.</para>
<page start="199"/>
<para id="p733"><emph type="i">Social conditions in the Black Country in the 19th century.</emph> G.J. Barnsby. Birmingham Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p734"><emph type="i">The social history of British coalminers, 1800&ndash;45.</emph> P.E.H. Hair. Oxford D.Phil. 1955.</para>
<para id="p735"><emph type="i">An historical study of the educational effects of the provision made for the social (as distinct from the scholastic) welfare of children and young persons in England since 1800.</emph> Christina L.H. Cowper. London M.A. 1930.</para>
<para id="p736"><emph type="i">Magazines for women: a sociological study of their character and function in the period 1800 to the present day.</emph> Cynthia L. White. London Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p737"><emph type="i">The Liverpool Corporate Estate: a study of the development of housing in the Moss Lake Fields area of Liverpool, 1800&ndash;75.</emph> P. Mathias. Liverpool M.A. 1956/7.</para>
<para id="p738"><emph type="i">The history of food adulteration in Great Britain in the 19th century, with special reference to bread, tea and beer.</emph> J. Burnett. London Ph.D. 1958.</para>
<para id="p739"><emph type="i">Aspects of the history of crime in England and Wales between 1805 and 1860.</emph> K.K. Macnab. Sussex D.Phil. 1965.</para>
<para id="p740"><emph type="i">An account of the progress of penal reform in England from 1810 to 1930, together with some conclusions.</emph> H.H. Ayscough. London Ph.D. 1933.</para>
<para id="p741"><emph type="i">The influence of social, economic and administrative change on crime and criminals in selected areas of England, 1815&ndash;75.</emph> J.J. Tobias. London Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<para id="p742"><emph type="i">Bywyd a gwaith Dr. Owen Owen Roberts, 1793&ndash;1866. (The life and work of Dr. O.O. Roberts.)</emph> E.H. Owen. Wales M.A. 1939.</para>
<para id="p743"><emph type="i">The life and work of James Braid, surgeon, with special reference to his influence on the development of hypnotism as an orthodox medical procedure.</emph> C.A.S. Wink. Oxford B.Litt. 1969.</para>
<para id="p744"><emph type="i">Recreations and amusements of the industrial working classes in the second quarter of the 19th century, with special reference to Lancashire.</emph> K. Allan. Manchester M.A. 1947.</para>
<para id="p745"><emph type="i">The growth and development of popular entertainment and pastimes in the Lancashire cotton towns, 1830&ndash;70.</emph> M.B. Smith. Lancaster M.Litt. 1970.</para>
<para id="p746"><emph type="i">Capitalism and class-consciousness in earlier 19th-century Oldham.</emph> J.O. Foster. Cambridge Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p747"><emph type="i">The development of Friendly societies in England, 1815&ndash;75.</emph> P.H.J.H. Gosden. London Ph.D. 1959.</para>
<para id="p748"><emph type="i">Some aspects of social and political life in England during the 19th century in relation to contemporary theory.</emph> Nellie M. Waterson. Birmingham M.A. 1921.</para>
<para id="p749"><emph type="i">Robert Owen and social legislation.</emph> E. Lloyd. Wales M.A. 1932.</para>
<para id="p750"><emph type="i">The development of the poor laws in Caernarvonshire and Anglesey, 1815&ndash;1914.</emph> C.F. Hughes. Wales M.A. 1945.</para>
<para id="p751"><emph type="i">The administration of the poor law in the West Riding of Yorkshire (1820&ndash;55).</emph> M.E. Rose. Oxford D.Phil. 1965.</para>
<para id="p752"><emph type="i">The temperance question in England, 1828&ndash;69.</emph> B.H. Harrison. Oxford D.Phil. 1965.</para>
<para id="p753"><emph type="i">Drink and sobriety in Wales, 1835&ndash;95.</emph> W.R. Lambert. Wales Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p754"><emph type="i">Movements towards social reform in South Wales during the period 1832&ndash;50.</emph> Lillian Williams. Wales M.A. 1933.</para>
<para id="p755"><emph type="i">The place of the Irish Catholics in the social life of the north of England, 1829&ndash;51.</emph> J.H. Treble. Leeds Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p756"><emph type="i">The Irish in London - a study of migration and settlement in the past 100 years.</emph> J.A. Jackson. London M.A. 1958.</para>
<para id="p757"><emph type="i">The origin and growth of the Irish community in Cardiff.</emph> J.V. Hickey. Wales M.A. 1959.</para>
<para id="p758"><emph type="i">The influence of Christianity on social progress, as illustrated by the career of Lord Shaftesbury.</emph> J.W. Bready. London Ph.D. 1927.</para>
<page start="200"/>
<para id="p759"><emph type="i">The 7th earl of Shaftesbury as social reformer.</emph> Evelyn M. Wightman. Birmingham M.A. 1923.</para>
<para id="p760"><emph type="i">Social administration in Lancashire, 1830&ndash;60: poor law, public health and police.</emph> E. Midwinter. York D.Phil. 1967.</para>
<para id="p761"><emph type="i">Public opinion and the police in Lancashire, 1838&ndash;42.</emph> D. Foster. Sheffield M.A. 1965.</para>
<para id="p762"><emph type="i">Machinery of public order in the Chartist period.</emph> F.C. Mather. Manchester M.A. 1948.</para>
<para id="p763"><emph type="i">A study of local sanitary administration in certain selected areas, 1830&ndash;75.</emph> A.J. Archer. Wales M.A. 1968.</para>
<para id="p764"><emph type="i">Edwin Chadwick and the public health movement, 1832&ndash;54.</emph> R.A. Lewis. Birmingham Ph.D. 1949.</para>
<para id="p765"><emph type="i">Urban administration and health: a case study of Hanley in the mid 19th century.</emph> W.E. Townley. Keele M.A. 1969.</para>
<para id="p766"><emph type="i">Public health in Leeds in the 19th century: a study in the growth of local government responsibility.</emph> Jean Toft. Manchester M.A. 1966.</para>
<para id="p767"><emph type="i">The administration of the poor law in the rural areas of Surrey, 1830&ndash;50.</emph> W. Pike. London M.A. 1950.</para>
<para id="p768"><emph type="i">A history of the relieving officer in England and Wales from 1834 to 1948.</emph> R.C. Mishra. London Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p769"><emph type="i">Poor law administration in west Glamorgan from 1834 to 1930.</emph> J.E. Thomas. Wales M.A. 1951.</para>
<para id="p770"><emph type="i">The education of pauper children in Monmouthshire, 1834&ndash;1929.</emph> D.B. Hughes. Wales M.A. 1967.</para>
<para id="p771"><emph type="i">The care and education of pauper children in England and Wales, 1834 to 1896.</emph> A.M. Ross. London Ph.D. 1955.</para>
<para id="p772"><emph type="i">The care and education of children in Union workhouses of Somerset, 1834&ndash;70.</emph> G.F. Baker. London M.A. (Ext.) 1960.</para>
<para id="p773"><emph type="i">The education of pauper children: policy and administration, 1834&ndash;55.</emph> F. Duke. Manchester M.A. 1968.</para>
<para id="p774"><emph type="i">Poor law and public health administration in the area of Merthyr Tydfil Union, 1834&ndash;94.</emph> T.D. Jones. Wales M.A. 1961.</para>
<para id="p775"><emph type="i">The medical services of the new poor law 1834&ndash;71.</emph> Gladys R. Hodgkinson. London Ph.D. 1951.</para>
<para id="p776"><emph type="i">The history of poor law administration in north-east Lancashire, 1834&ndash;71.</emph> R. Boyson. Manchester M.A. 1960.</para>
<para id="p777"><emph type="i">Local administration of the poor law in the Great Broughton and Wirral Unions and the Chester Local Act Incorporation, 1834&ndash;71.</emph> M.D. Handley. Wales M.A. 1969.</para>
<para id="p778"><emph type="i">The English poor law of 1834, with special reference to its working between 1834 and 1847: a study in social pathology.</emph> J.M. Mackinnon. London M.A. 1930.</para>
<para id="p779"><emph type="i">The working of the new poor law, 1834&ndash;42.</emph> H. Levy. Manchester M.A. 1923.</para>
<para id="p780"><emph type="i">Town-country relations in England and Wales in the pre-railway age, as revealed by the Poor Law Unions.</emph> Eileen M. Pierce. London M.A. 1957.</para>
<para id="p781"><emph type="i">The administration of the poor law in the Unions of Southwell and Basford, 1836&ndash;71.</emph> M. Caplan. Nottingham Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p782"><emph type="i">Poor law administration, 1840&ndash;3, with particular reference to the Cardiff Union.</emph> Valerie J. Russell. Wales M.A. 1967.</para>
<para id="p783"><emph type="i">Victoria Park, Manchester: a study of its administration and its relations with local government, 1836&ndash;1954.</emph> M. Spiers. Manchester M.A. 1961.</para>
<para id="p784"><emph type="i">Origins and achievements of Winchester College pupils, 1836 to 1934.</emph> T.J.H. Bishop. London Ph.D. 1962.</para>
<para id="p785"><emph type="i">Influences on the growth of literacy in Victorian working-class children.</emph> A.C.O. Ellis. Liverpool M.A. 1970.</para>
<para id="p786"><emph type="i">The royal household since the accession of Queen Victoria.</emph> Mrs. Angur B. Joshi. Oxford B.Litt. 1961.</para>
<para id="p787"><emph type="i">Personal injuries claims in Victorian Britain.</emph> H. Smith. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1970.</para>
<page start="201"/>
<para id="p788"><emph type="i">Some aspects of the historical development and present organisation of voluntary welfare societies for adult deaf persons in England, 1840&ndash;1963.</emph> C.K. Lysons. Liverpool M.A. 1964/5.</para>
<para id="p789"><emph type="i">The historical development, from the mid 19th century, of services for physically handicapped children, with special reference to the development of social work and its place in these services today.</emph> Margaret E. Paisley. London M.Sc. 1964.</para>
<para id="p790"><emph type="i">The Rebecca riots in Wales.</emph> Mabel Williams. Wales M.A. 1913.</para>
<para id="p791"><emph type="i">History of the Italian exiles in London, 1816&ndash;48.</emph> Margaret C.W. Wicks. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1930/1.</para>
<para id="p792"><emph type="i">The European revolutionaries in London, 1848&ndash;70.</emph> H.P. Grosshans. Oxford B.Litt. 1950.</para>
<para id="p793"><emph type="i">Housing in urban areas, 1840&ndash;1914.</emph> J.N. Tarn. Cambridge Ph.D. 1961/2.</para>
<para id="p794"><emph type="i">The housing of the working classes in Britain, 1850&ndash;1914: a study of the development of standards and methods of provision.</emph> Winifred V. Hole. London Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<para id="p795"><emph type="i">Fluctuations in house-building in the South Wales coalfield, 1851&ndash;1954.</emph> J.H. Richards. Wales M.A. 1956.</para>
<para id="p796"><emph type="i">Family structure in 19th-century Lancashire.</emph> M. Anderson. Cambridge Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p797"><emph type="i">The English middle-class concept of the standard of living and its relation to marriage and family size, 1850&ndash;1900.</emph> J.A. Banks. London M.A. 1952.</para>
<para id="p798"><emph type="i">The effect of married women's employment in the cotton textile districts on the organisation and structure of the home in Lancashire, 1840&ndash;80.</emph> Margaret Hewitt. London Ph.D. 1953.</para>
<para id="p799"><emph type="i">'The servant question': a study of the domestic labour market, 1851&ndash;1917.</emph> Sheila J. Richardson. London M.Phil. 1967.</para>
<para id="p800"><emph type="i">Changes in the social status of women in England: an analysis of the married women's property and divorce controversies, 1854&ndash;7.</emph> P. Softley. Leicester M.A. 1962.</para>
<para id="p801"><emph type="i">The Divorce Act of 1857: the genesis, and the arguments produced for and against it at the time.</emph> L. Bairstow. Durham M.A. 1951.</para>
<para id="p802"><emph type="i">Women and poor law administration, 1857&ndash;1909.</emph> Mrs. Elizabeth M. Ross. London M.A. 1956.</para>
<para id="p803"><emph type="i">The use of short-term building and repairing leases by Crown and corporate landowners on English urban estates in the 19th century, with special reference to London.</emph> D.A. Reeder. Leicester M.A. 1961.</para>
<para id="p804"><emph type="i">Residential displacement by railway construction in north Lambeth, 1858&ndash;61.</emph> H.C. Binford. Sussex M.A. 1967/8.</para>
<para id="p805"><emph type="i">The historical development and present-day significance of byelaw-housing morphology, with particular reference to Hull, York and Middlesbrough.</emph> C.A. Forster. Hull Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p806"><emph type="i">Housing legislation in England, 1851&ndash;67, with special reference to London.</emph> Vera Zoond. London M.A. 1932.</para>
<para id="p807"><emph type="i">The recruitment, regulation and role of prostitutes in Britain from the middle of the 19th century to the present day.</emph> Mrs. Helen R.E. Ware. London Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p808"><emph type="i">The English prison officer, 1850&ndash;1968.</emph> J.E. Thomas. York D.Phil. 1970.</para>
<para id="p809"><emph type="i">Geographical and historical aspects of the public water supply of London, 1852&ndash;1902.</emph> R.W. Morris. London Ph.D. 1941.</para>
<para id="p810"><emph type="i">The history of the Caernarvonshire police force, 1856&ndash;1900.</emph> J.O. Jones. Wales M.A. 1956.</para>
<para id="p811"><emph type="i">The rise and growth of the Liverpool police force in the 19th century.</emph> W.R. Cockcroft. Wales M.A. 1969.</para>
<page start="202"/>
<para id="p812"><emph type="i">The National Association for the Promotion of Social Science (1857&ndash;86): some sociological aspects.</emph> R.J. Pemble. Nottingham M.A. 1968.</para>
<para id="p813"><emph type="i">The late Victorian revolt, 1859&ndash;95.</emph> P.T. Cominos. Oxford D.Phil. 1958.</para>
<para id="p814"><emph type="i">The utilisation of hospital in-patient services for the physically ill in England and Wales between 1861 and 1938.</emph> R.A. Pinker. London M.Sc. 1965.</para>
<para id="p815"><emph type="i">The origins and development of England's first state hospitals, with special reference to the services provided by the Metropolitan Asylums Board for patients with infectious diseases, 1867&ndash;1930.</emph> Gwendoline M. Ayers. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1967.</para>
<para id="p816"><emph type="i">The genesis of modern British town planning: a study in economic and social history of the 19th and 20th centuries.</emph> W. Ashworth. London Ph.D. 1950.</para>
<para id="p817"><emph type="i">Thomas Coglan Horsfall, 1841&ndash;1932, pioneer of the town-planning movement in England.</emph> Josephine P. Reynolds. Liverpool M.A. 1952/3.</para>
<para id="p818"><emph type="i">The history of the Howard League for Penal Reform.</emph> A.G. Rose. Manchester Ph.D. 1960.</para>
<para id="p819"><emph type="i">John Ruskin as social reformer.</emph> F.U. Stribley. Birmingham M.A. 1925.</para>
<para id="p820"><emph type="i">The British anti-vaccination movement in the 19th century.</emph> D.L. Ross. Leicester M.Sc. 1968.</para>
<para id="p821"><emph type="i">Sanitary administration of Liverpool, 1847&ndash;1900.</emph> W. Bate. Liverpool M.A. 1954/5.</para>
<para id="p822"><emph type="i">The Ladies' Sanitary Association and the origins of the health visiting service.</emph> W.C. Dowling. London M.A. 1963.</para>
<para id="p823"><emph type="i">The role of Dr. Dyke in the public health administration of Merthyr Tydfil, 1865&ndash;1900.</emph> B.A. Frampton. Wales M.A. 1968.</para>
<para id="p824"><emph type="i">Some aspects of state activity in public health, 1858&ndash;71: with special reference to the Medical Department of the Privy Council and the Local Government Act Office.</emph> R.J. Lambert. Cambridge Ph.D. 1960.</para>
<para id="p825"><emph type="i">Sanitary administration under the Local Government Board, 1871&ndash;88.</emph> R.K.J.F. Young. Oxford B.Litt. 1964.</para>
<para id="p826"><emph type="i">The Charity Organisation Society and the rise of the Welfare State.</emph> C. Woodard. Cambridge Ph.D. 1961.</para>
<para id="p827"><emph type="i">The British Humanist movement, 1860&ndash;1966.</emph> Mrs. Susan Budd. Oxford D.Phil. 1969.</para>
<para id="p828"><emph type="i">George Jacob Holyoake and the secularist movement in Britain, 1841&ndash;61.</emph> E. Royle. Cambridge Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p829"><emph type="i">The social sources of the Salvation Army, 1865&ndash;90.</emph> Christine Ward. London M.Phil. 1970.</para>
<para id="p830"><emph type="i">The contribution of the Salvation Army to the religious and moral education of children and young people in Great Britain, 1865&ndash;1965.</emph> Marie K. Beard. London M.A. (Ext.) 1968.</para>
<para id="p831"><emph type="i">The Conservative party and some social problems primarily affecting the condition of the working classes, 1866&ndash;80.</emph> P. Smith. Oxford D.Phil. 1965.</para>
<para id="p832"><emph type="i">The organised provisions for cultural activities in urban centres and their impact on the community, 1870&ndash;1910, with special reference to the city of Bristol.</emph> Helen E. Meller. Bristol Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p833"><emph type="i">The development of physical recreation in Liverpool in the 19th century.</emph> R. Rees. Liverpool M.A. 1967/8.</para>
<para id="p834"><emph type="i">The development of physical recreation in the Birmingham district from 1871 to 1892.</emph> D.D. Molyneux. Birmingham M.A. 1957.</para>
<para id="p835"><emph type="i">The English elementary school considered as an agent of social transformation, 1870&ndash;1918.</emph> E.G. Pells. Oxford B.Litt. 1928.</para>
<page start="203"/>
<para id="p836"><emph type="i">The condition of the rural population of England and Wales, 1870&ndash;1928. A study of physical and mental conditions of the rural population, (a) in relation to migration and its effects in age and sex selection, (b) in relation to income and standards of living, (c) in relation to changes in social organisation.</emph> D.J. Davies. Wales Ph.D. 1931.</para>
<para id="p837"><emph type="i">The British medical profession and state intervention in public health, 1870&ndash;1911.</emph> Jeanne L. Brand. London Ph.D. 1953.</para>
<para id="p838"><emph type="i">The concept of evolution in social theory from Spencer to Hobhouse.</emph> J.W. Burrow. Cambridge Ph.D. 1961.</para>
<para id="p839"><emph type="i">The development of old age pensions policy in Great Britain, 1878&ndash;1925.</emph> Patricia M. Williams. London Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p840"><emph type="i">The development of 'The new biography': biographies of the Victorians, 1881&ndash;1915.</emph> S.J. Walker. Nottingham Ph.D. 1959.</para>
<para id="p841"><emph type="i">A study of English uniformed youth movements, 1883&ndash;1935: their origins, development and social and political influence.</emph> P. Wilkinson. Wales M.A. 1968.</para>
<para id="p842"><emph type="i">Canon Barnett and the first thirty years of Toynbee Hall.</emph> Mrs. Emily K. Abel. London Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p843"><emph type="i">The political left wing (the Liberals and emergent Labour party) and the issue of alien Jewish immigration, 1880&ndash;1910.</emph> J.A. Garrard. Manchester M.Sc. 1965.</para>
<para id="p844"><emph type="i">The economic and social history of alien immigrants to Leeds, 1880&ndash;1914.</emph> J. Buckman. Strathclyde Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p845"><emph type="i">The alien invasion: the origins of the Aliens Act.</emph> B. Gainer. Cambridge Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p846"><emph type="i">The problem of unemployment in English social policy, 1886&ndash;1914.</emph> Jos&eacute; F. Chambers. Cambridge Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p847"><emph type="i">The Liberal party and the social problem, 1892&ndash;1914.</emph> H.V. Emy. London Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p848"><emph type="i">Ideas concerning social policy and their influence on legislation in Britain, 1902&ndash;11.</emph> J. Brown. London Ph.D. 1964.</para>
<para id="p849"><emph type="i">Housing in Coventry: the development of municipal action, 1890&ndash;1908.</emph> A.T. Mallier. Birmingham M.Soc.Sc. 1970.</para>
<para id="p850"><emph type="i">Government and housing: a study in the development of social policy, 1906&ndash;39.</emph> P.R. Wilding. Manchester Ph.D. 1969/70.</para>
<para id="p851"><emph type="i">Fifty years of public health and social welfare in Bath, 1896&ndash;1945.</emph> J.F. Blackett. Bristol M.A. 1949.</para>
<para id="p852"><emph type="i">A study of social change and educational opportunity in west Cumberland from 1900 to the present day.</emph> Mrs. Mary H. Watkinson. London M.A. 1958.</para>
<para id="p853"><emph type="i">The child in public care, 1900 to 1939: a historical study.</emph> N.G. Middleton. London M.Phil. 1968.</para>
<para id="p854"><emph type="i">The Poor Law Commission, 1905&ndash;9: an investigation of its task and achievement.</emph> A. Maltby. Liverpool M.A. 1969.</para>
<para id="p855"><emph type="i">Social legislation and theory in Great Britain from 1906 to 1914.</emph> T.W. Price. Oxford B.Litt. 1930.</para>
<para id="p856"><emph type="i">Housing policy in four Lincolnshire towns, 1919&ndash;59.</emph> O.A. Hartley. Oxford D.Phil. 1969.</para>
<para id="p857"><emph type="i">Fluctuations in investment in housing in Britain and America, 1919&ndash;39.</emph> G.P. Braae. Oxford D.Phil. 1960.</para>
<para id="p858"><emph type="i">The approach of the Conservative party to social policy during World War II.</emph> H. Kopsch. London Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p859"><emph type="i">Air raid shelters in Britain in the Second World War.</emph> Mary M.M. Harrison. Birmingham M.A. 1949.</para>
<para id="p860"><emph type="i">The politics of race under the impact of migration: the United States (1900&ndash;30) and the United Kingdom (1948&ndash;68).</emph> I. Katznelson. Cambridge Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<page start="204"/>
</section>
</section>
<section id="s18">
<head>ECCLESIASTICAL HISTORY</head>
<section id="s19">
<head>General</head>
<para id="p861"><emph type="i">The influence of the Church of England and dissent upon Methodism in the 19th century.</emph> F. Hunter. Manchester M.A. 1939.</para>
<para id="p862"><emph type="i">Evangelicalism in England in the first half of the 19th century as exemplified in the life and works of William Jay (1769&ndash;1853).</emph> H.E. Pressly. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1950.</para>
<para id="p863"><emph type="i">The attitude of the Evangelicals to the empire and imperial problems (1820&ndash;50).</emph> A.F. Madden. Oxford D.Phil. 1950.</para>
<para id="p864"><emph type="i">Ebenezer Henderson (1784&ndash;1858), missionary, traveller, teacher, biblical scholar: his life and work in the north of Europe, with special reference to the great missionary awakening.</emph> J.H. Glassman. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1958.</para>
<para id="p865"><emph type="i">William Palmer and the Orthodox Church.</emph> F.J. Thomson. Cambridge Ph.D. 1963/4.</para>
<para id="p866"><emph type="i">The early Tractarians and the Eastern Church.</emph> P.E.O. Shaw. Oxford B.Litt. 1924.</para>
<para id="p867"><emph type="i">The attitude of the Tractarians to the Roman Catholic Church, 1833&ndash;50.</emph> R.H. Greenfield. Oxford D.Phil. 1956.</para>
<para id="p868"><emph type="i">The influence of North American evangelism in Great Britain between 1830 and 1914 on the origin and development of the ecumenical movement.</emph> J.W. White. Oxford D.Phil. 1963.</para>
<para id="p869"><emph type="i">The part played in British social and political life by the protestant Nonconformists between the years 1832 and 1859, with special reference to the disestablishment of the Church of England.</emph> B.J. Mason. Southampton M.A. 1958.</para>
<para id="p870"><emph type="i">The agitation for disestablishment of the Church of England in the 19th century (excluding Wales), with special reference to the minutes and papers of the Liberation Society.</emph> W.H. Macintosh. Oxford D.Phil. 1956.</para>
<para id="p871"><emph type="i">Christian Socialism, its rise and development, its economic and social results, and its relation to other working-class movements.</emph> I. Evans. Wales M.A. 1912.</para>
<para id="p872"><emph type="i">Robert Owen and Christian Socialism.</emph> F. Fraser. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1927.</para>
<para id="p873"><emph type="i">The social and religious thought of Charles Kingsley, and his place in the Christian Socialist school of 1848&ndash;54.</emph> H.W. West. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1947.</para>
<para id="p874"><emph type="i">Religious organisations in Wales considered in relation to economic conditions, 1850&ndash;1930.</emph> E.T. Lewis. Wales M.A. 1965.</para>
<para id="p875"><emph type="i">The relations between organised religion and English working-class movements, 1850&ndash;1914.</emph> S.H. Mayor. Manchester Ph.D. 1960.</para>
<para id="p876"><emph type="i">Religion and the working classes in mid 19th-century England.</emph> Hilary A. Evans. London M.Phil. 1970.</para>
<para id="p877"><emph type="i">The churches and society in Leicestershire, 1851&ndash;81.</emph> D.M. Thompson. Cambridge Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p878"><emph type="i">A factual and analytical account of the religious awakening in the United Kingdom in the years 1855&ndash;65.</emph> J.E. Orr. Oxford D.Phil. 1948.</para>
<para id="p879"><emph type="i">The religious awakening of 1858&ndash;60 in Great Britain and Ireland.</emph> O. Bussey. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1947.</para>
<para id="p880"><emph type="i">The influence of the Evangelicals upon the origin and development of voluntary charitable institutions in the second half of the 19th century.</emph> Kathleen J. Heasman. London Ph.D. 1960.</para>
<para id="p881"><emph type="i">A study of the work of revivalist movements in Great Britain and Ireland from 1870 to 1914 and of their effect upon organised Christianity there.</emph> P.B. Morgan. Oxford B.Litt. 1961.</para>
<page start="205"/>
<para id="p882"><emph type="i">English churches and the working classes, 1880&ndash;1900, with an introductory survey of tendencies earlier in the century.</emph> K.S. Inglis. Oxford D.Phil. 1956.</para>
<para id="p883"><emph type="i">The Labour Church and allied movements of the late 19th and early 20th centuries.</emph> D.F. Summers. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1958/9.</para>
<para id="p884"><emph type="i">The relation of theology to social theory and action in the Christian Social movement in England from 1877 to 1914.</emph> E.V. Newman. Oxford B.Litt. 1936.</para>
<para id="p885"><emph type="i">Christian Socialism in Britain and the U.S.A., 1880&ndash;1914.</emph> P.d'A. Jones. London Ph.D. 1964.</para>
<para id="p886"><emph type="i">Frederick Lewis Donaldson and the Christian Socialist movement.</emph> Mrs. Barbara J. Butler. Leeds M.Phil. 1970.</para>
<para id="p887"><emph type="i">Baron Friedrich von H&uuml;gel and the Modernist crisis in England.</emph> L.F. Barmann. Cambridge Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p888"><emph type="i">Religion and politics in Liverpool since 1900.</emph> D.A. Roberts. London M.Sc. (Ext.) 1965.</para>
<para id="p889"><emph type="i">Principles and characteristics of missionary policy during the last fifty years, as illustrated by the history of the London Missionary Society.</emph> N. Goodall. London Ph.D. 1950.</para>
<para id="p890"><emph type="i">Authority in church and state: aspects of the thought of J.N. Figgis and his contemporaries.</emph> D.G. Nicholls. Cambridge Ph.D. 1962.</para>
</section>
<section id="s20">
<head>Church of England</head>
<para id="p891"><emph type="i">The history of the English clergy, 1800&ndash;1900.</emph> C.K.F. Brown. Oxford D.Phil. 1949.</para>
<para id="p892"><emph type="i">A sociological analysis of the clergyman's role, with special reference to its development in the early 19th century.</emph> A.J. Russell. Oxford D.Phil. 1970.</para>
<para id="p893"><emph type="i">The intellectual development of E.B. Pusey, 1800&ndash;50.</emph> D.W.F. Forrester. Oxford D.Phil. 1967.</para>
<para id="p894"><emph type="i">The attitudes of English churchmen, 1800&ndash;50, toward the Reformation.</emph> W.J. Baker. Cambridge Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p895"><emph type="i">The diocese of Exeter, 1800&ndash;40.</emph> J.H. Bettey. Birmingham M.A. 1956.</para>
<para id="p896"><emph type="i">Anglican church extension and related movements, <emph type="i">c</emph>. 1800&ndash;1860, with special reference to London.</emph> B.I. Coleman. Cambridge Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p897"><emph type="i">The Church Building Commission, 1818&ndash;56.</emph> M.H. Port. Oxford B.Litt. 1956.</para>
<para id="p898"><emph type="i">Ecclesiastical reorganisation and church extension in the diocese of Llandaff, 1830&ndash;90.</emph> W.D. Wills. Wales M.A. 1965.</para>
<para id="p899"><emph type="i">Bishop Blomfield.</emph> P.J. Welch. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1952.</para>
<para id="p900"><emph type="i">The Church of England in its relations with parliament and Crown, 1825&ndash;45.</emph> L.O. Henderson. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1961.</para>
<para id="p901"><emph type="i">Relations between church and state in England between 1829 and 1839.</emph> F.M. Scully. Oxford B.Litt. 1935.</para>
<para id="p902"><emph type="i">The Anglican establishment, 1830&ndash;1930.</emph> G. Youell. Keele M.A. 1969.</para>
<para id="p903"><emph type="i">The relations between the Church of England and the state from 1838 to 1870.</emph> H.K. Smith. Sheffield M.A. 1946.</para>
<para id="p904"><emph type="i">The Church of England and society, 1830&ndash;50.</emph> C. Brackwell. Birmingham M.A. 1949.</para>
<para id="p905"><emph type="i">The Church of England in the town of Derby, 1824&ndash;85.</emph> M.R. Austin. Birmingham M.A. 1967.</para>
<para id="p906"><emph type="i">The Church of England and society in Birmingham, <emph type="i">c</emph>. 1830&ndash;1866.</emph> D.E.H. Mole. Cambridge Ph.D. 1961.</para>
<para id="p907"><emph type="i">John Kaye and the diocese of Lincoln.</emph> R. Foskett. Nottingham Ph.D. 1957.</para>
<para id="p908"><emph type="i">Edward Copleston, bishop of Llandaff.</emph> W.J. Cratchley. Oxford B.Litt. 1938.</para>
<page start="206"/>
<para id="p909"><emph type="i">Frederick Denison Maurice.</emph> A.C. Smith. Sheffield M.A. 1950.</para>
<para id="p910"><emph type="i">Hugh James Rose, rector of Hadleigh, Suffolk.</emph> Dorothy M.B. Snow. Oxford B.Litt. 1960.</para>
<para id="p911"><emph type="i">The Oxford Movement and church unity.</emph> F.S. Downs. St. Andrews Ph.D. 1960.</para>
<para id="p912"><emph type="i">Richard Bagot, bishop of Oxford, and the Oxford Movement, 1833&ndash;45.</emph> A.H. Mead. Oxford B.Litt. 1966.</para>
<para id="p913"><emph type="i">The Oxford Movement in a Manchester parish: the Miles Platting case.</emph> H.E. Sheen. Manchester M.A. 1941.</para>
<para id="p914"><emph type="i">New Anglican bishoprics, 1836&ndash;1919, their creation and endowment in England, with special reference to Truro and Birmingham.</emph> P.S. Morrish. London M.A. 1965.</para>
<para id="p915"><emph type="i">The formation of the see of Ripon and the episcopate of its first bishop, Charles Thomas Longley.</emph> A.M.G. Stephenson. Oxford B.Litt. 1960.</para>
<para id="p916"><emph type="i">A history of the Church Pastoral-Aid Society, 1836&ndash;61.</emph> P.B. Coombs. Bristol M.A. 1960.</para>
<para id="p917"><emph type="i">The episcopate of Samuel Wilberforce, bishop of Oxford 1845&ndash;69, and of Winchester 1869&ndash;73, with special reference to the administration of the diocese of Oxford.</emph> R.K. Pugh. Oxford D.Phil. 1957.</para>
<para id="p918"><emph type="i">The evangelical party in the Church of England, 1855&ndash;65.</emph> B.E. Hardman. Cambridge Ph.D. 1964.</para>
<para id="p919"><emph type="i">John Charles Ryle and the evangelical party in the 19th century.</emph> J.S. Casson. Nottingham M.Phil. 1969.</para>
<para id="p920"><emph type="i">The revival of the 'religious life' in the Church of England during the 19th century.</emph> A.M. Allchin. Oxford B.Litt. 1956.</para>
<para id="p921"><emph type="i">The development of church life in the rural deanery of Cleveland, <emph type="i">c</emph>. 1850&ndash;1880.</emph> C.H.N. Smith. Nottingham M.A. 1965.</para>
<para id="p922"><emph type="i">The life of J.B. Lightfoot (1828&ndash;89), with special reference to the training of the ministry.</emph> D.J. Wilson. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1955/6.</para>
<para id="p923"><emph type="i">Conflicts over religious inquiry among the Anglican clergy in the eighteen-sixties.</emph> Margaret A. Worden. Oxford D.Phil. 1968.</para>
<para id="p924"><emph type="i">Social and educational backgrounds of English diocesan bishops, 1860&ndash;1960.</emph> D.H.J. Morgan. Hull M.A. 1964.</para>
<para id="p925"><emph type="i">Some aspects of the career of William Thomson as archbishop of York, 1863&ndash;90.</emph> H.K. Smith. Sheffield Ph.D. 1953.</para>
<para id="p926"><emph type="i">Dean Farrar: a study in 19th-century Anglicanism.</emph> J.R. Jackson. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1957.</para>
<para id="p927"><emph type="i">The first Lambeth Conference of 1867.</emph> A.M.G. Stephenson. Oxford D.Phil. 1964.</para>
<para id="p928"><emph type="i">Gladstone and the Anglican Church in Ireland and England, 1868&ndash;74.</emph> J.F.M.D. Stephen. Cambridge M.Litt. 1955.</para>
<para id="p929"><emph type="i">Anglican attitudes to church, state and society during Mr. Gladstone's first ministry, 1868&ndash;74.</emph> P.T. Marsh. Cambridge Ph.D. 1962.</para>
<para id="p930"><emph type="i">Social concern in the Church of England, as revealed in its pronouncements on social and economic matters, especially during the years 1880&ndash;1940.</emph> F.W. Jones. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1968.</para>
<para id="p931"><emph type="i">George Body, D.D., 'Canon Missioner' of Durham.</emph> St.J.A. Turner. Durham M.A. 1961.</para>
<para id="p932"><emph type="i">Henry Scott Holland, 1847&ndash;1918.</emph> J.H. Foster. Wales Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p933"><emph type="i">The development of constitutional autonomy in the established church in later Victorian England.</emph> R.S.M. Withycombe. Cambridge Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p934"><emph type="i">Social thought in the Church of England from 1918 to 1933.</emph> J.K. Oliver. Cambridge M.Litt. 1964.</para>
<page start="207"/>
</section>
<section id="s21">
<head>Protestant Nonconformity</head>
<para id="p935"><emph type="i">The development of Methodism in Yorkshire in the 19th century.</emph> B. Greaves. Liverpool Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p936"><emph type="i">A study of the theological developments among Nonconformists in Wales during the 19th century.</emph> G. Richards. Oxford B.Litt. 1956.</para>
<para id="p937"><emph type="i">A survey of Baptist expansion in England from 1795 to 1850, with special reference to the emergence of permanent structures of organisation.</emph> S.M. Stone. Bristol M.A. 1959.</para>
<para id="p938"><emph type="i">John Foster (1770&ndash;1843): and his contribution to religious thought.</emph> S.T. Habel. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1945.</para>
<para id="p939"><emph type="i">The Baptists in the borough of Leeds during the 19th century: a study of local church history.</emph> R.J. Owen. Leeds M.Phil. 1970.</para>
<para id="p940"><emph type="i">Baptism in Nonconformist theology, 1820&ndash;1920, with special reference to the Baptists.</emph> J.R.C. Perkin. Oxford D.Phil. 1955.</para>
<para id="p941"><emph type="i">Political and social attitudes of representative English Unitarians (1795&ndash;1850).</emph> I. Sellers. Oxford B.Litt. 1956.</para>
<para id="p942"><emph type="i">The origin and early development of Primitive Methodism in Derbyshire, 1810&ndash;70.</emph> G.M. Morris. Nottingham M.A. 1960.</para>
<para id="p943"><emph type="i">Primitive Methodism in Nottinghamshire, 1815&ndash;1932.</emph> G.M. Morris. Nottingham Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p944"><emph type="i">Cornish Methodism: a study in division, 1814&ndash;57.</emph> M.S. Edwards. Birmingham M.A. 1962.</para>
<para id="p945"><emph type="i">The attitude of the Welsh Independents towards working-class movements, including public education, from 1815 to 1870.</emph> R.I. Parry. Wales M.A. 1931.</para>
<para id="p946"><emph type="i">The political activities of Dissenters in the East and West Ridings of Yorkshire, 1815&ndash;50.</emph> R.W. Ram. Hull M.A. 1964.</para>
<para id="p947"><emph type="i">Methodism and the working classes of England, 1800&ndash;50.</emph> R.F. Wearmouth. London Ph.D. 1935.</para>
<para id="p948"><emph type="i">The clash between radicalism and conservatism in Methodism, 1815&ndash;48.</emph> J.H.S. Kent. Cambridge Ph.D. 1951.</para>
<para id="p949"><emph type="i">The origins and early development of the Plymouth Brethren.</emph> P.L. Embley. Cambridge Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p950"><emph type="i">The origins of the Plymouth Brethren, <emph type="i">c</emph>. 1825&ndash;1850.</emph> H.H. Rowdon. London Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<para id="p951"><emph type="i">The Catholic Apostolic Church, sometimes called 'Irvingite': a historical study.</emph> P.E.O. Shaw. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1935.</para>
<para id="p952"><emph type="i">The contribution of Quakers to some aspects of local government in Birmingham, 1828&ndash;1902.</emph> M.H. Bailey. Birmingham M.A. 1952.</para>
<para id="p953"><emph type="i">Quakerism and public service, chiefly between 1832 and 1867.</emph> Erica I.J. Martineau. Oxford B.Litt. 1938.</para>
<para id="p954"><emph type="i">Quakers and society in Victorian England.</emph> Mrs. Elizabeth M. Isichei, <emph type="i">n&eacute;e</emph> Allo. Oxford D.Phil. 1967.</para>
<para id="p955"><emph type="i">The constitutional authority of Dr. Jabez Bunting over Wesleyan Methodism as seen through his correspondence.</emph> W.B. Maynard. Durham M.A. 1970.</para>
<para id="p956"><emph type="i">Methodist secessions and social conflict in south Lancashire, 1830&ndash;57.</emph> D.A. Gowland. Manchester Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p957"><emph type="i">Baptists in Lancashire, 1837&ndash;87: a study of mid-Victorian dissent.</emph> J.H. Lea. Liverpool Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p958"><emph type="i">Nonconformity in the eastern counties, 1840&ndash;85, with reference to its social background.</emph> J.C.G. Binfield. Cambridge Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<para id="p959"><emph type="i">Bywyd a gwaith Dr. Lewis Edwards. (The life and work of Lewis Edwards of Bala.)</emph> T.L. Evans. Wales M.A. 1949.</para>
<para id="p960"><emph type="i">Bywyd a gwaith John Evans (I.D. Ffraid). (The life and work of John Evans.)</emph> W.L. Roberts. Wales M.A. 1950.</para>
<para id="p961"><emph type="i">Life and teaching of John Pulsford, 1815&ndash;97.</emph> N.H. Kew. Oxford B.Litt. 1955.</para>
<page start="208"/>
<para id="p962"><emph type="i">History of the British 'Churches of Christ'.</emph> A.C. Watters. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1940.</para>
<para id="p963"><emph type="i">Wesleyan Methodism from 1850 to 1900 in relation to the life and thought of the Victorian age.</emph> P.C. Pearson. Manchester M.A. 1965.</para>
<para id="p964"><emph type="i">A statistical study of the development of Nonconformity in North Wales in the 19th century, with special reference to the period 1850&ndash;1901.</emph> W.A. Evans. Liverpool M.A. 1928.</para>
<para id="p965"><emph type="i">The life, work and thought of John Angell James (1785&ndash;1859).</emph> J.R. Kennedy. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1956/7.</para>
<para id="p966"><emph type="i">A history of Congregationalism in Suffolk from 1870 to 1940.</emph> J.H. Bennett. Oxford B.Litt. 1953.</para>
<para id="p967"><emph type="i">The dissenting reformed churches of England with respect to the doctrine of the church from 1870 to 1940, with special reference to the Congregational churches.</emph> J.W. Grant. Oxford D.Phil. 1948.</para>
<para id="p968"><emph type="i">John Clifford and radical Nonconformity.</emph> M.R. Watts. Oxford D.Phil. 1966.</para>
<para id="p969"><emph type="i">The history of the Free Church Council, 1892&ndash;1939.</emph> E.K.H. Jordan. Oxford D.Phil. 1953.</para>
</section>
<section id="s22">
<head>Roman Catholicism</head>
<para id="p970"><emph type="i">A survey of liberal Catholic theories of biblical inspiration, 1810&ndash;1910.</emph> J.T. Burtchaell. Cambridge Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p971"><emph type="i">William George Ward and 19th-century Catholicism.</emph> K.T. Hoppen. Cambridge Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p972"><emph type="i">The organisation and administration of Roman Catholic dioceses in England and Wales in the mid 19th century.</emph> R.J. Schiefen. London Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p973"><emph type="i">Newman and the use of history.</emph> J.D. Holmes. Cambridge Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p974"><emph type="i">The Acton-Newman relations.</emph> H.A. Macdougall. Cambridge Ph.D. 1960.</para>
<para id="p975"><emph type="i">Cardinal Newman.</emph> Helen M. Herrick. Liverpool M.A. 1932.</para>
<para id="p976"><emph type="i">The public life and influence of Henry Edward Manning, 1865&ndash;92, excluding his attitude towards the temporal power.</emph> V.A. McClelland. Birmingham M.A. 1958.</para>
</section>
</section>
<section id="s23">
<head>CULTURAL HISTORY</head>
<section id="s24">
<head>General</head>
<para id="p977"><emph type="i">The development of the architectural profession in Great Britain, 1800&ndash;1945.</emph> B.L.B. Kaye. London Ph.D. 1951.</para>
<para id="p978"><emph type="i">The career of Sir Robert Smirke, R.A.</emph> J.M. Crook. Oxford D.Phil. 1962.</para>
<para id="p979"><emph type="i">Joseph Hanson.</emph> D. Evinson. London M.A. 1966.</para>
<para id="p980"><emph type="i">The design of English domestic architecture from about 1850 to 1914.</emph> J.A.M. Bell. Manchester Ph.D. 1963.</para>
<para id="p981"><emph type="i">The origin and development of the idea of prehistory and related concepts in archaeology.</emph> Mrs. Judith M. Rodden. Cambridge M.Litt. 1964.</para>
<para id="p982"><emph type="i">Antiquarian and archaeological scholarship in Warwickshire, 1800&ndash;60.</emph> Barbara J. Ronchetti. Birmingham M.A. 1952.</para>
<para id="p983"><emph type="i">The early history of the Yorkshire Philosophical Society: a chapter in the history of provincial science.</emph> A.D. Orange. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1970.</para>
<para id="p984"><emph type="i">The history of the Society for the Diffusion of Useful Knowledge.</emph> T.L. Jarman. Oxford B.Litt. 1933.</para>
<para id="p985"><emph type="i">The Society for the Diffusion of Useful Knowledge, 1826&ndash;46.</emph> Monica C. Grobel. London M.A. 1933.</para>
<para id="p986"><emph type="i">Newspapers and opinion in three midland cities, 1800&ndash;50.</emph> D. Fraser. Leeds M.A. 1962.</para>
<page start="209"/>
<para id="p987"><emph type="i">The history of the agitation against the stamp duty on newspapers, 1830&ndash;55.</emph> Marjorie G. Moore. London M.A. 1935.</para>
<para id="p988"><emph type="i">The unstamped press in London and the taxes on knowledge, 1830&ndash;6.</emph> Mrs. Patricia L. Hollis. Oxford D.Phil. 1968.</para>
<para id="p989"><emph type="i">The press in Northumberland and Durham, 1855&ndash;1906.</emph> J.M. Milne. Newcastle M.Litt. 1969.</para>
<para id="p990"><emph type="i">George Potter and the <emph type="i">Bee-Hive</emph> newspaper.</emph> S.W. Coltham. Oxford D.Phil. 1956.</para>
<para id="p991"><emph type="i">Aspects of chemical affinity in the 19th century.</emph> T.H. Levere. Oxford D.Phil. 1969.</para>
<para id="p992"><emph type="i">The problem of the chemical elements, from Humphrey Davy to Benjamin Brodie the younger.</emph> D.M. Knight. Oxford D.Phil. 1964.</para>
<para id="p993"><emph type="i">Walter Bagehot: a study in Victorian ideas.</emph> M.A.-M. Nasr. London Ph.D. 1949.</para>
<para id="p994"><emph type="i">The life and work of Henry Clifton Sorby, LL.D., F.R.S. (1826&ndash;1908).</emph> N. Higham. Leeds M.A. 1962.</para>
<para id="p995"><emph type="i">The life and letters of Griffith Evans, pioneer in protozoon pathology, 1835&ndash;1935.</emph> Mrs. Jean E. Ware. Wales M.A. 1966.</para>
<para id="p996"><emph type="i">The development of Darwin's evolutionary thought after 1859.</emph> P.J. Vorzimer. Cambridge Ph.D. 1964.</para>
<para id="p997"><emph type="i">Edward Edwards, 1812&ndash;86, and the early history of municipal public libraries in England.</emph> W.A. Munford. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1963.</para>
<para id="p998"><emph type="i">Valentine Cameron Prinsep, in relation to the practice and theory of academic painting in late 19th-century England.</emph> P.V. Saville. Oxford B.Litt. 1970.</para>
<para id="p999"><emph type="i">M.H. Baillie Scott.</emph> J.D. Kornwolf. London Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p1000"><emph type="i">A natural law criticism of Bernard Bosanquet's political theory.</emph> Elizabeth A. McClure. Cambridge M.Litt. 1951.</para>
<para id="p1001"><emph type="i">The history of freedom of speech and of the press in England since 1900.</emph> A.F. Dawn. London M.Sc. 1933.</para>
<para id="p1002"><emph type="i">The history of <emph type="i">The Observer</emph>. 1905&ndash;10.</emph> A.M. Gollin. Oxford D.Phil. 1957.</para>
</section>
<section id="s25">
<head>Education</head>
<section id="s26">
<head><emph type="i">General</emph></head>
<para id="p1003"><emph type="i">The theology of church and state in relation to the concern for popular education in England, 1800&ndash;70.</emph> B.R. Marshall. Oxford D.Phil. 1956.</para>
<para id="p1004"><emph type="i">Scottish influence on English education between 1800 and 1840.</emph> E. Kerr-Waller. London M.A. 1952.</para>
<para id="p1005"><emph type="i">Education with a tradition: an account of the educational work of the Society of the Sacred Heart, 1800&ndash;1935.</emph> Mary F.M. O'Leary. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1935.</para>
<para id="p1006"><emph type="i">The educational experience of the Sisters of Notre Dame de Namur, 1804&ndash;1964.</emph> Margaret P. Linscott. Liverpool Ph.D. 1964/5.</para>
<para id="p1007"><emph type="i">A life of Charles Knight (1791&ndash;1873), with special reference to his political and educational activities.</emph> Althea C. Cherry. London M.A. 1942.</para>
<para id="p1008"><emph type="i">The influence of industry and commerce on the development of educational facilities in England and Wales, 1830 to 1870.</emph> J.A. Purton. London M.Sc. 1958.</para>
<para id="p1009"><emph type="i">Education and the political parties, 1830&ndash;70.</emph> R.E. Aldrich. London M.Phil. 1970.</para>
<para id="p1010"><emph type="i">The development of parliamentary opinion in respect to education, 1832&ndash;70.</emph> Mary K. Wilkinson. Wales M.A. 1925.</para>
<para id="p1011"><emph type="i">Steps towards a national system of education in England 1833&ndash;70, with special reference to the report of the Newcastle Commission 1861.</emph> F.P. Burns. Oxford B.Litt. 1965.</para>
<page start="210"/>
<para id="p1012"><emph type="i">The influence of the Massachusetts system of education on the movement for a national system in England and Wales in the 19th century.</emph> P.N. Farrar. Liverpool M.A. 1963/4.</para>
<para id="p1013"><emph type="i">The passing of the Education Act of 1870; a study of the formation of public opinion, 1843&ndash;70.</emph> E.E. Rich. London Ph.D. 1932.</para>
<para id="p1014"><emph type="i">An investigation into public opinion and the passing of the Education Act of 1870.</emph> R.B. Grove. London M.A. 1949.</para>
<para id="p1015"><emph type="i">Birmingham and the movement for national education, 1867&ndash;77: an account of the work and influence of the National Education League.</emph> A.F. Taylor. Leicester Ph.D. 1960.</para>
<para id="p1016"><emph type="i">The Endowed Schools Acts and the education of 'poor' children, 1869&ndash;1900.</emph> P. Gordon. London M.Sc. 1965.</para>
<para id="p1017"><emph type="i">The origins of the Endowed Schools Act, 1869, and its operation in England from 1869 to 1895.</emph> F.E. Balls. Cambridge Ph.D. 1964.</para>
<para id="p1018"><emph type="i">The work and influence of Dorothea Beale in the light of developments in the education of girls and women since 1850.</emph> M.P.G. Kerr. London M.A. 1952.</para>
<para id="p1019"><emph type="i">An investigation into the educational ideas and contribution of the British political parties, 1870&ndash;1918.</emph> L.O. Ward. London Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p1020"><emph type="i">A history of the origin and development of the Dual System in England and Wales with special reference to the period 1870 to 1944.</emph> Marjorie A. Cruickshank. Leeds Ph.D. 1955.</para>
<para id="p1021"><emph type="i">Trade unionist, Co-operative and Socialist organisations in relation to popular education, 1870&ndash;1902.</emph> W.P. McCann. Manchester Ph.D. 1960.</para>
<para id="p1022"><emph type="i">Nonconformity and education in England and Wales, 1870&ndash;1902.</emph> H. Foreman. London M.A. (Ext.) 1967.</para>
<para id="p1023"><emph type="i">John Scott Lidgett, 1854&ndash;1953, and the education of the people.</emph> D.H. Thomas. London Ph.D. 1960.</para>
<para id="p1024"><emph type="i">The influence of Sidney and Beatrice Webb on English education, 1892&ndash;1903.</emph> E.J.T. Brennan. Sheffield M.A. 1959.</para>
<para id="p1025"><emph type="i">The growth of the public system of education in England and Wales, 1895&ndash;1935.</emph> G.A.N. Lowndes. Oxford B.Litt. 1937.</para>
<para id="p1026"><emph type="i">The educational policies of the Labour party, 1900&ndash;61.</emph> R.S. Barker. London Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p1027"><emph type="i">The reaction of the established church to educational legislation, 1918&ndash;59.</emph> A. Pomfret. London M.A. 1969.</para>
<para id="p1028"><emph type="i">The political parties and the development of their attitude to educational problems, 1918&ndash;42.</emph> D.W. Dean. London M.Phil. 1968.</para>
</section>
<section id="s27">
<head><emph type="i">Administration</emph></head>
<para id="p1029"><emph type="i">State intervention in English education as illustrated by the relations between the state and the teacher in the early half of the 19th century.</emph> J. Gross. Liverpool M.A. 1932.</para>
<para id="p1030"><emph type="i">The development of the central authority for education in England, 1833&ndash;99.</emph> A.S. Bishop. Liverpool Ph.D. 1967/8.</para>
<para id="p1031"><emph type="i">The Education Department, 1839&ndash;64: a study of social policy and the growth of government.</emph> J.R.B. Johnson. Cambridge Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p1032"><emph type="i">The Department of Science and Art: policies and administration to 1864.</emph> C. Duke. London Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p1033"><emph type="i">The Science and Art Department, 1853&ndash;1900.</emph> H. Butterworth. Sheffield Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p1034"><emph type="i">The emergence and development of inspectorates of schools in the 19th century, with special reference to Yorkshire.</emph> E.L. Edmonds. Sheffield M.A. 1955.</para>
<para id="p1035"><emph type="i">The work of Her Majesty's inspectors of schools, 1839&ndash;49.</emph> Nancy Ball. Birmingham M.A. 1961.</para>
<para id="p1036"><emph type="i">The life and work of Sir James Kay-Shuttleworth.</emph> F. Smith. Wales Ph.D. 1923.</para>
<page start="211"/>
<para id="p1037"><emph type="i">The educational work and thought of Robert Lowe.</emph> J.P. Sullivan. London M.A. 1952.</para>
<para id="p1038"><emph type="i">Educational administration in England and Wales, 1870&ndash;1950: a case study in central-local government relations.</emph> W.B. Rust. London Ph.D. 1955.</para>
<para id="p1039"><emph type="i">A study of the Private Schools Association (latterly Independent Schools) in relation to changing policies in the administration of education by national and local government agencies, 1880&ndash;1944.</emph> G.B. Robinson. London M.A. 1966.</para>
<para id="p1040"><emph type="i">A critical and historical study of the relations between state and education from 1886 to 1926.</emph> E. Whitehead. Oxford B.Litt. 1934.</para>
<para id="p1041"><emph type="i">The administration of education, 1902&ndash;14.</emph> L.F.W. White. London Ph.D. 1934.</para>
<para id="p1042"><emph type="i">The Education Act of 1902: a study of its background, scope and legislative problems.</emph> P.L.P. Clarke. London Ph.D. 1964.</para>
<para id="p1043"><emph type="i">A study of the Education (Provision of Meals) Act, 1906, against its social, political and economic background.</emph> L.I. Andrews. London M.A. 1966.</para>
<para id="p1044"><emph type="i">The historical antecedents, 1834&ndash;1906, of the Education (Provision of Meals) Act, 1906.</emph> D.F. Adams. London Ph.D. 1954.</para>
<para id="p1045"><emph type="i">The Education Act 1918: an assessment of its place in the development of educational administration in England.</emph> L.I. Andrews. London Ph.D. 1970.</para>
</section>
<section id="s28">
<head><emph type="i">Regional Education</emph></head>
<para id="p1046"><emph type="i">Some aspects of the development of education in Newbury in the 19th century.</emph> T.V.B. Morrison. Reading M.Phil. 1966/7.</para>
<para id="p1047"><emph type="i">A history of the education of children in the Blackburn hundred to 1870.</emph> C. Birtwistle. London M.Sc. (Ext.) 1952.</para>
<para id="p1048"><emph type="i">The development of education in Chorley and district from 1800 to 1902.</emph> K.P.C. Thorne. Lancaster M.Litt. 1970.</para>
<para id="p1049"><emph type="i">The development of education in Barnsley in the 19th century, prior to direct state intervention.</emph> H.C. Hillary. Sheffield M.A. 1941.</para>
<para id="p1050"><emph type="i">The development of the educational facilities of South-port, 1825&ndash;1944.</emph> W.E. Marsden. Sheffield M.A. 1959.</para>
<para id="p1051"><emph type="i">The development of public education in Nelson, Lancashire, 1832&ndash;1902.</emph> G.I. Hawkes. Wales M.A. 1964.</para>
<para id="p1052"><emph type="i">St. Helens, 1845 and afterwards: an illustration of educational development.</emph> W.A. Fawcett. Liverpool M.A. 1936.</para>
<para id="p1053"><emph type="i">The educational work of the Sisters of Notre Dame in Lancashire since 1850.</emph> Margaret P. Linscott. Liverpool M.A. 1959/60.</para>
<para id="p1054"><emph type="i">The history of education and educational institutions in Nottinghamshire, excluding the city of Nottingham, from 1800 to 1930.</emph> Edith M. Becket. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1936.</para>
<para id="p1055"><emph type="i">The history of education in Nottingham, with special reference to the 19th century.</emph> D. Wardle. Nottingham Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<para id="p1056"><emph type="i">Rural education in Shropshire in the 19th century.</emph> J.P. Dodd. Birmingham M.A. 1958.</para>
<para id="p1057"><emph type="i">The progress of education in Bristol.</emph> H.J. Larcombe. Bristol M.A. 1924.</para>
<para id="p1058"><emph type="i">Educational development in the city of Bath, 1830&ndash;1902, with special reference to its interrelations with social and economic change.</emph> R.B. Hope. Bristol Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p1059"><emph type="i">A history of education in Rotherham and district up to 1902.</emph> R. Harrison. Bristol M.A. 1951.</para>
<para id="p1060"><emph type="i">Isaac Ironside and education in the Sheffield region in the first half of the 19th century.</emph> J. Salt. Sheffield M.A. 1960.</para>
<para id="p1061"><emph type="i">Thomas Asline Ward: his life and achievements and their effect upon the development of Sheffield.</emph> G.D. Jennett. Sheffield M.A. 1954.</para>
<page start="212"/>
<para id="p1062"><emph type="i">The history of education in the town of Brecon to 1902.</emph> T.P. Jones. London M.A. (Ext.) 1965.</para>
<para id="p1063"><emph type="i">The development of education in Swansea, 1846&ndash;1902.</emph> Jean A. Weaver. Wales M.A. 1957.</para>
<para id="p1064"><emph type="i">Church and chapel as sources and centres of education in Wales during the second half of the 19th century.</emph> L.S. Jones. Liverpool M.A. 1940.</para>
<para id="p1065"><emph type="i">A history of education in the towns of Barry and Penarth together with the neighbouring parishes of Leckwith, Llandough juxta Penarth, Lavernock, Sully, St. Andrews, Wenvoe, Highlight, Porthkerry and Penmark during the period 1860&ndash;1930.</emph> J. Thomas. Wales M.A. 1933.</para>
<para id="p1066"><emph type="i">The life and work of Sir Isambard Owen (1850&ndash;1927), with particular reference to his contribution to education in Wales.</emph> G.A. Jones. Wales M.A. 1967.</para>
<para id="p1067"><emph type="i">Educational policy and administration change: a study of evolving concepts and practices in educational administration in a Welsh rural county (Montgomeryshire, 1870&ndash;1967).</emph> J.A. Davies. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1968.</para>
<para id="p1068"><emph type="i">The development of educational provision in the rural county of Shropshire between 1870 and 1914, with particular reference to the policy of the county council.</emph> T.D.M. Jones. Keele M.A. 1968/9.</para>
<para id="p1069"><emph type="i">A historical investigation of the development of a local system of education in the city of Birmingham from 1870 to 1924.</emph> M.E.J. Shewell. London M.A. 1952.</para>
<para id="p1070"><emph type="i">Education in West Hartlepool before the Act of 1902.</emph> A.C. Klottrup. Sheffield M.A. 1969.</para>
<para id="p1071"><emph type="i">Public education in late Victorian Lancashire.</emph> E.C. Midwinter. Liverpool M.A. 1969/70.</para>
<para id="p1072"><emph type="i">Elementary and secondary education in Hampshire between 1890 and 1914.</emph> D.C. Savage. Southampton M.Phil. 1970.</para>
<para id="p1073"><emph type="i">Some researches into education in Dartford, Kent, with reference to Kentish educational development as a whole, from 1902 until the middle of the 20th century.</emph> J.W. Butler. London Ph.D. 1959.</para>
<para id="p1074"><emph type="i">The organisation, development and administration of public education in the area of the London County Council, 1903&ndash;22.</emph> P.H. Andrews. London Ph.D. 1963.</para>
<para id="p1075"><emph type="i">The development of education in Chesterfield, 1919&ndash;44.</emph> R.M. Lewis. Sheffield M.A. 1961.</para>
</section>
<section id="s29">
<head><emph type="i">Elementary Education</emph></head>
<para id="p1076"><emph type="i">The contribution of Methodism to popular education, 1800&ndash;50.</emph> H.F. Mathews. Liverpool M.A. 1946.</para>
<para id="p1077"><emph type="i">The development of elementary education in the 19th century: the role of the Committee of the Privy Council on Education and the Hertfordshire gentry.</emph> J.S. Hurt. London Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p1078"><emph type="i">The elementary school manager and the management of education, 1800&ndash;1902.</emph> P. Gordon. London Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p1079"><emph type="i">English elementary schools, 1801&ndash;40.</emph> A. Birtles. Leeds M.A. 1911.</para>
<para id="p1080"><emph type="i">The development of Catholic elementary education in the 19th century in the five counties of the diocese of Nottingham.</emph> J. Bastow. Nottingham M.Phil. 1970.</para>
<para id="p1081"><emph type="i">The history and development of boys' preparatory schools in England.</emph> F.C. Pritchard. London M.A. 1938.</para>
<para id="p1082"><emph type="i">A study of rewards and punishments in the elementary schools of England and Wales, 1800&ndash;93.</emph> P.J. Rooke. London M.A. (Ext.) 1962.</para>
<para id="p1083"><emph type="i">A study of the education of the working class in Stock-port during the 19th century.</emph> I.J.D. Steele. Sheffield M.A. 1968.</para>
<para id="p1084"><emph type="i">Manchester and the movement for national elementary education, 1800&ndash;70.</emph> S.E. Maltby. Manchester M.A. 1916.</para>
<page start="213"/>
<para id="p1085"><emph type="i">The changing social content of elementary education as reflected in school books in use in England, 1808&ndash;70.</emph> M. Goldstrom. Birmingham Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p1086"><emph type="i">The origin, development and organisation of certain Lancastrian schools in London, Middlesex and Surrey: a comparative study.</emph> J.R. Carr. London M.A. 1963.</para>
<para id="p1087"><emph type="i">The educational influence of Robert Owen in England, with particular reference to the infant schools directly developed from the New Lanark pattern between 1819 and 1839.</emph> D.A. Turner. London M.Phil. 1969.</para>
<para id="p1088"><emph type="i">The contribution of Henry Brougham to the movement for the extension of elementary education in England between 1815 and 1839.</emph> Monica Molloy. Liverpool M.A. 1956/7.</para>
<para id="p1089"><emph type="i">The Liverpool Corporation schools and the movement for national elementary education: an account of an experiment.</emph> J. Murphy. Liverpool Ph.D. 1955/6.</para>
<para id="p1090"><emph type="i">The work of the established church in the education of the people, 1833&ndash;70.</emph> H.J. Burgess. London Ph.D. 1954.</para>
<para id="p1091"><emph type="i">The Church of England's contribution to popular education in England after 1833.</emph> C.K.F. Brown. Oxford B.Litt. 1941.</para>
<para id="p1092"><emph type="i">The education of children engaged in industry in England, 1833&ndash;76.</emph> A.H. Robson. London Ph.D. 1930.</para>
<para id="p1093"><emph type="i">Sir Thomas Wyse and the Central Society of Education.</emph> I.D. Harry. Wales M.A. 1932.</para>
<para id="p1094"><emph type="i">The Ragged School Union and the education of the London poor in the 19th century.</emph> E.A.G. Clark. London M.A. 1967.</para>
<para id="p1095"><emph type="i">Voluntary effort in English elementary schools, 1846 to 1870: a study of the contribution of school managers to educational developments.</emph> Nancy Ball. Keele Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p1096"><emph type="i">Methodism and the education of the people (since 1851).</emph> H.F. Mathews. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1954.</para>
<para id="p1097"><emph type="i">A historical survey of legislation bearing on the education of mentally deficient children in England and Wales, 1850&ndash;1955.</emph> R.P. Singh. London M.A. 1960.</para>
<para id="p1098"><emph type="i">The dissemination of Froebelian doctrines and methods in the English system of elementary education, 1854 to 1914.</emph> Irene M. Lilley. London M.A. 1963.</para>
<para id="p1099"><emph type="i">Some researches into public elementary education in Dartford, Kent, in the second half of the 19th century.</emph> J.W. Butler. London M.A. 1956.</para>
<para id="p1100"><emph type="i">The development of elementary education in Walsall, 1862&ndash;1902.</emph> P. Liddle. London M.A. (Ext.) 1967.</para>
<para id="p1101"><emph type="i">The elementary schools of Bath, 1862&ndash;1902.</emph> P.F. Speed. Bristol M.A. 1958.</para>
<para id="p1102"><emph type="i">The contribution of the National Society to Welsh education (1811&ndash;70).</emph> T.P. Jones. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1968.</para>
<para id="p1103"><emph type="i">A contribution to the history of elementary education in North Wales (up to 1870), with special reference to National schools.</emph> T.R. Hughes. Liverpool M.A. 1935.</para>
<para id="p1104"><emph type="i">The history of church schools in Swansea during the 19th century to 1870.</emph> A.L. Trott. Wales M.A. 1941.</para>
<para id="p1105"><emph type="i">A history of elementary education in Wales, 1847&ndash;70.</emph> A.L. Trott. Wales Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p1106"><emph type="i">The struggle for the Elementary Education Act and its implementation - 1870 to 1873.</emph> D. Roland. Oxford B.Litt. 1958.</para>
<para id="p1107"><emph type="i">Some aspects of the making of policy in elementary education in England and Wales, 1870&ndash;95.</emph> Mrs. Gillian R. Sutherland, <emph type="i">n&eacute;e</emph> Thomas. Oxford D.Phil. 1970.</para>
<para id="p1108"><emph type="i">The problems of English elementary education since 1870: the evolution of opinion and the development of the system.</emph> H.A. Grimshaw. London M.Sc. 1918.</para>
<para id="p1109"><emph type="i">A history of the English village school in the light of changing educational policy and organisation between the Forster Act of 1870 and the Balfour Act of 1902.</emph> H.B.A. Wise. Oxford B.Litt. 1960.</para>
<page start="214"/>
<para id="p1110"><emph type="i">Provision for schooling in an English village, Wraysbury - 1870&ndash;1944.</emph> J.L. Robson. London M.A. (Ext.) 1965.</para>
<para id="p1111"><emph type="i">Elementary school work, 1875&ndash;1925.</emph> R.D. Bramwell. Durham Ph.D. 1958.</para>
<para id="p1112"><emph type="i">The history of the Birmingham School Board, 1870&ndash;1903.</emph> A.F. Taylor. Birmingham M.A. 1955.</para>
<para id="p1113"><emph type="i">A history of education in Bradford during the period of the Bradford School Board, 1870&ndash;1904.</emph> A.J. Evans. Leeds M.A. 1947.</para>
<para id="p1114"><emph type="i">The work of the school board in rural Essex, 1870 to 1903.</emph> Barbara J. Smith. London M.A. 1968.</para>
<para id="p1115"><emph type="i">Elementary education in the Lewisham district at the time of the School Board for London, 1870&ndash;1903.</emph> D.H.B. Andrews. London M.A. 1965.</para>
<para id="p1116"><emph type="i">The school boards of Stoke-upon-Trent and Burslem, 1870&ndash;1903.</emph> S. Clews. Sheffield M.A. 1962.</para>
<para id="p1117"><emph type="i">A history of elementary education in the Fylde area of Lancashire during the period 1870&ndash;1903.</emph> W. Bentley. Liverpool M.A. 1960/1.</para>
<para id="p1118"><emph type="i">The organisation and administration of elementary education by the school board of three selected districts of Surrey, Mitcham, Woking and Betchworth, between 1870 and 1903.</emph> J.A. Dewey. London M.A. 1964.</para>
<para id="p1119"><emph type="i">Truant schools of the School Board for London.</emph> T.D. Morgan. London M.A. 1956.</para>
<para id="p1120"><emph type="i">The early years of the Tynemouth School Board.</emph> B.G. Everett. Durham M.A. 1964.</para>
<para id="p1121"><emph type="i">A general survey of the school board movement as it affected Monmouthshire, with special reference to the town of Newport.</emph> D.E. Davies. Wales M.A. 1927.</para>
<para id="p1122"><emph type="i">The work of the Llanwonno School Board following the 1870 Education Act to 1902.</emph> Anita Jordan. Wales M.A. 1968.</para>
<para id="p1123"><emph type="i">The history of the Chesterfield School Board, from 1870 to 1912.</emph> W.R. Covell. Sheffield M.A. 1952.</para>
<para id="p1124"><emph type="i">A survey of the administrative problems facing the voluntary public elementary day schools during the period 1890&ndash;7.</emph> D. Tunstall. London M.A. 1959.</para>
<para id="p1125"><emph type="i">The voluntary schools in four Lancashire county boroughs, 1903&ndash;63: a study of policies and provision.</emph> S.E. Kelly. Keele M.A. 1968/9.</para>
<para id="p1126"><emph type="i">An examination of the political and legislative background to the development of Catholic elementary education in England in the early 20th century.</emph> R. Pattison. Leeds Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p1127"><emph type="i">The development of senior elementary schools in three administrative areas of Worcestershire, 1918&ndash;44.</emph> W.D. Robinson. Keele M.A. 1969/70.</para>
</section>
<section id="s30">
<head><emph type="i">Secondary Education</emph></head>
<para id="p1128"><emph type="i">The Methodist contribution to 19th-century secondary education.</emph> F.C. Pritchard. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1947.</para>
<para id="p1129"><emph type="i">The place of secondary education in Welsh society, 1800&ndash;1918.</emph> J.R. Webster. Wales Ph.D. 1959.</para>
<para id="p1130"><emph type="i">The content and quality of secondary education at an English Catholic seminary in the 19th century - Ushaw, 1808&ndash;63.</emph> J.S. Malone. London M.A. (Ext.) 1969.</para>
<para id="p1131"><emph type="i">A history of Harrow School and its relationship to its neighbourhood throughout the 19th century.</emph> T.F. May. London M.Phil. 1969.</para>
<para id="p1132"><emph type="i">The educational work of the Very Reverend Charles John Vaughan.</emph> M.D.W. Poole. Sheffield M.A. 1966.</para>
<para id="p1133"><emph type="i">The Victorian public school, 1828&ndash;1902: the school as a community.</emph> J.R. de S. Honey. Oxford D.Phil. 1970.</para>
<para id="p1134"><emph type="i">The history of Hazelwood School, Birmingham, and its influence on educational developments in the 19th century.</emph> C.G. Hey. Wales M.A. 1954.</para>
<page start="215"/>
<para id="p1135"><emph type="i">John Ford, 1801&ndash;75: the life, work and influence of a Quaker schoolmaster.</emph> L.J. Stroud. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1947.</para>
<para id="p1136"><emph type="i">The internal organisation of boys' secondary schools in England during the middle decades of the 19th century.</emph> R.H. Sturman. London M.A. 1932.</para>
<para id="p1137"><emph type="i">The established church and the education of the Victorian middle classes: a study of the Woodard schools, 1847&ndash;91.</emph> W.B.D. Heeney. Oxford D.Phil. 1962.</para>
<para id="p1138"><emph type="i">The life and work of Nathaniel Woodard, with special reference to the influence of the Oxford Movement on English education in the 19th century.</emph> R. Perry. Bristol M.A. 1932.</para>
<para id="p1139"><emph type="i">The Lancashire Public School Association, later the National Public School Association, in its role as a pressure group, with an account of the Manchester Model Secular School, later the Manchester Free School.</emph> D.K. Jones. Sheffield M.A. 1965.</para>
<para id="p1140"><emph type="i">The origin and subsequent development of St. Mary's College, Hammersmith, 1847&ndash;99.</emph> J.A. Britton. London M.A. 1964.</para>
<para id="p1141"><emph type="i">A short history of secondary grammar education in Jersey, as exemplified in the story of Victoria College, Jersey.</emph> P. Ahier. London M.A. (Ext.) 1963.</para>
<para id="p1142"><emph type="i">The life and influence of Edward Thring.</emph> C.J. Rigby. Oxford D.Phil. 1969.</para>
<para id="p1143"><emph type="i">The development of the theory and practice of further education in England since the Act of 1870.</emph> T.D. Buxton. London M.A. 1955.</para>
<para id="p1144"><emph type="i">The history of education in Wales from 1870, with special reference to secondary education to 1920.</emph> T.I. Ellis. Wales M.A. 1930.</para>
<para id="p1145"><emph type="i">A comparative study of the curriculum and organisation of secondary education in England and the United States between 1870 and 1900.</emph> B.S. Cane. London M.A. 1957.</para>
<para id="p1146"><emph type="i">Public opinion and reform of secondary education, 1888&ndash;1902, as reflected in parliament and the national press.</emph> D.R. Felsenstein. London M.A. 1965.</para>
<para id="p1147"><emph type="i">The development of secondary education in Radnorshire, 1889&ndash;1963.</emph> R.S. Griffiths. Wales M.A. 1965.</para>
<para id="p1148"><emph type="i">The development of secondary education in Montgomeryshire since 1889.</emph> L.H. Williams. Wales M.A. 1962.</para>
<para id="p1149"><emph type="i">A study in the growth of state secondary education in Breconshire, 1889&ndash;1939.</emph> J. Llewellyn. Wales M.A. 1968/9.</para>
<para id="p1150"><emph type="i">The development of secondary education in south Pembrokeshire, 1889&ndash;1939.</emph> K.D. Evans. Wales M.A. 1970.</para>
<para id="p1151"><emph type="i">The changing environment of the London grammar school, 1900&ndash;50.</emph> F.C. Campbell. London Ph.D. 1953.</para>
<para id="p1152"><emph type="i">The development in London of elementary education of a higher type, 1900&ndash;10.</emph> R. Morley. London M.A. 1961.</para>
<para id="p1153"><emph type="i">The concept and nature of the grammar school in relation to the development of secondary education since 1902.</emph> Olive L. Banks. London Ph.D. 1953.</para>
<para id="p1154"><emph type="i">The development of the bilateral system of secondary education in Caernarvonshire, 1903 to date.</emph> P.E. Owen. London Ph.D. 1961.</para>
<para id="p1155"><emph type="i">A critical survey of Board of Education policy in relation to resulting reforms in post-primary and secondary education since 1904.</emph> J.T.R. Graves. Oxford B.Litt. 1939.</para>
<para id="p1156"><emph type="i">The Labour party and the organisation of secondary education, 1918&ndash;65.</emph> M.H. Parkinson. Manchester M.A. 1968.</para>
</section>
<section id="s31">
<head><emph type="i">Higher Education</emph></head>
<para id="p1157"><emph type="i">Higher education in Lancashire in the 19th century.</emph> E. Smith. Oxford B.Litt. 1922.</para>
<para id="p1158"><emph type="i">The origins and development of the university movement in Wales, with particular reference to the period 1800&ndash;89.</emph> I.J. Morgan. Wales M.A. 1929.</para>
<page start="216"/>
<para id="p1159"><emph type="i">Henry Robinson Hartley: his family, his life and the establishment of the Hartley Institution.</emph> A. Anderson. Southampton M.A. 1962.</para>
<para id="p1160"><emph type="i">The University of London, 1820&ndash;60, with special reference to its influence on the development of higher education.</emph> F.G. Brook. London Ph.D. 1958.</para>
<para id="p1161"><emph type="i">Roman Catholics and higher education in England, 1830&ndash;1903.</emph> V.A. McClelland. Sheffield Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p1162"><emph type="i">A history of the Royal Academy Schools, 1837&ndash;78.</emph> H.C. Morgan. Leeds Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p1163"><emph type="i">The social and economic aspects of higher education for women between 1844 and 1870, with special reference to the North of England Council.</emph> Stella R. Wills. London M.A. 1952.</para>
<para id="p1164"><emph type="i">Higher education for women: the opposition in England during the 19th century.</emph> Joan N. Burstyn. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1968.</para>
<para id="p1165"><emph type="i">Susanna and Catherine Winkworth, 1830&ndash;60.</emph> B.H. Jackson. Manchester M.A. 1969.</para>
<para id="p1166"><emph type="i">The early development of the university extension movement under the influence of James Stuart.</emph> H. Gordon. Sheffield M.A. 1941.</para>
<para id="p1167"><emph type="i">The development of education in theological colleges in the Church of England and in the Protestant Episcopal Church of America, 1900&ndash;50.</emph> S.F.D. Walters. Oxford D.Phil. 1957.</para>
</section>
<section id="s32">
<head><emph type="i">Adult Education</emph></head>
<para id="p1168"><emph type="i">The development of adult education in Warrington during the 19th century.</emph> W.B. Stephens. Exeter M.A. 1958.</para>
<para id="p1169"><emph type="i">George Birkbeck, pioneer of adult education.</emph> T. Kelly. Liverpool Ph.D. 1957.</para>
<para id="p1170"><emph type="i">The origin and development of the Yorkshire Union of Mechanics' Institutes.</emph> J. Popple. Sheffield M.A. 1960.</para>
<para id="p1171"><emph type="i">The Mechanics' Institute movement in Lancashire and Yorkshire, 1824&ndash;60, with particular reference to the institutions in Manchester, Ashton-under-Lyne and Huddersfield.</emph> Mrs. Mabel Tylecote, <emph type="i">n&eacute;e</emph> Phythian. Manchester Ph.D. 1930.</para>
<para id="p1172"><emph type="i">Social and religious influences in adult education in Yorkshire between 1830 and 1870.</emph> J.F.C. Harrison. Leeds Ph.D. 1955.</para>
<para id="p1173"><emph type="i">The Mechanics' Institutes of South Wales.</emph> T. Evans. Sheffield Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p1174"><emph type="i">The miner's search for self-improvement: the history of evening classes in the Rhondda valley from 1862 to 1914.</emph> Margaret Turner. Wales M.A. 1967.</para>
<para id="p1175"><emph type="i">The development of state-aided evening schools for adults between 1870 and 1902.</emph> K.A. Percy. Nottingham M.A. 1969.</para>
<para id="p1176"><emph type="i">The London School Board and the development of evening education, 1870&ndash;93.</emph> S. Somper. London M.A. 1954.</para>
</section>
<section id="s33">
<head><emph type="i">Technical and Other Subjects</emph></head>
<para id="p1177"><emph type="i">The teaching of geography in 19th-century Britain.</emph> P.J. Hart. London M.A. 1957.</para>
<para id="p1178"><emph type="i">The historical development of the history syllabus in boys' secondary schools in England, 1800&ndash;1900.</emph> M.A.F. Cooper. London M.A. 1950.</para>
<para id="p1179"><emph type="i">The place of history in English secondary education from <emph type="i">c</emph>. 1830 to 1890.</emph> G.M.D. Henderson-Howat. Oxford B.Litt. 1963.</para>
<para id="p1180"><emph type="i">The sciences and humanities in English grammar schools in relation to the climate of opinion, 1805&ndash;1904.</emph> N.W. Saffin. London M.A. 1957.</para>
<para id="p1181"><emph type="i">The place of the Royal Institution of South Wales in the history of scientific and general education in the 19th century.</emph> H.M. Davies. Wales M.A. 1940.</para>
<page start="217"/>
<para id="p1182"><emph type="i">The development of scientific education during the second half of the 19th century, with special reference to the influence of John Tyndall.</emph> D. Thompson. Sheffield M.A. 1955.</para>
<para id="p1183"><emph type="i">The teaching of science in England during the latter half of the 19th century, and Huxley's influence on its development.</emph> W. Hall. Sheffield M.A. 1931.</para>
<para id="p1184"><emph type="i">The scientific and educational influence of Sir Henry Enfield Roscoe (1833&ndash;1915), with particular reference to his work in Manchester.</emph> N. Limgard. Liverpool M.A. 1969/70.</para>
<para id="p1185"><emph type="i">The development of the teaching of chemistry in England, 1799&ndash;1853.</emph> M.S. Byrne. Durham M.A. 1968.</para>
<para id="p1186"><emph type="i">The evolution of technical education in 19th-century England.</emph> P. Keane. Bath Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p1187"><emph type="i">The development of technical education in Essex.</emph> Marjorie M. Collison. London M.A. 1955.</para>
<para id="p1188"><emph type="i">The effect of national developments on technical education in Bury, Oldham and Preston before 1889.</emph> T.A. Smith. Liverpool M.A. 1966/7.</para>
<para id="p1189"><emph type="i">The history of Gloucester Technical College.</emph> P.G. Rossington. Bristol M.A. 1963.</para>
<para id="p1190"><emph type="i">The development of education in Swindon, with particular reference to the influence and requirements of the railway works and other local industries.</emph> B. Lloyd. Bristol M.A. 1954.</para>
<para id="p1191"><emph type="i">Origins and development of the administration of technical education in England, <emph type="i">c</emph>. 1850&ndash;1904.</emph> P.E. Hannon. London M.A. 1960.</para>
<para id="p1192"><emph type="i">The historical development of technical and vocational education within the area of the county borough of West Ham since 1850.</emph> J.R. Soar. London M.A. 1966.</para>
<para id="p1193"><emph type="i">The history of technical education in Rotherham with particular reference to the period 1850&ndash;1918.</emph> H.P. Reilly. Sheffield M.A. 1952.</para>
<para id="p1194"><emph type="i">The development of technical education in England from 1851 to 1889, with special reference to economic factors.</emph> D.H. Thomas. London Ph.D. 1940.</para>
<para id="p1195"><emph type="i">The history of technical education in Nottinghamshire, 1851&ndash;1902.</emph> H.K. Briscoe. Sheffield M.A. 1952.</para>
<para id="p1196"><emph type="i">Commercial education in England during 1851 to 1902: an institutional study.</emph> M.A. Dalvi. London Ph.D. 1957.</para>
<para id="p1197"><emph type="i">Public opinion and technical education in England, 1867&ndash;1906. (A study of the awakening of English opinion to the importance of scientific research and technical education as factors of economic and military power.)</emph> J. Blanchet. Oxford D.Phil. 1953.</para>
<para id="p1198"><emph type="i">An enquiry into the policy of the Free Churches with reference to religious education in the schools, 1870&ndash;1944.</emph> D.H. Thomas. Wales M.A. 1955.</para>
<para id="p1199"><emph type="i">Developments since 1870 in the teaching of religion in the public elementary schools of England, with special reference to senior schools.</emph> O. White. Oxford B.Litt. 1939.</para>
<para id="p1200"><emph type="i">The evolution of special education, 1893&ndash;1939.</emph> P.H. Butterfield. London Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p1201"><emph type="i">The London Polytechnic movement, with special reference to Quintin Hogg.</emph> F. Johnson. London M.A. 1929.</para>
<para id="p1202"><emph type="i">Post-elementary education in the area of the London Technical Education Board, 1893&ndash;1904.</emph> P.H. Andrews. London M.A. 1959.</para>
</section>
<section id="s34">
<head><emph type="i">Teaching Profession</emph></head>
<para id="p1203"><emph type="i">The training of teachers in England and Wales during the 19th century.</emph> R.W. Rich. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1934.</para>
<para id="p1204"><emph type="i">Sir James Kay-Shuttleworth: an examination of the influence of his work and ideas in the field of elementary teacher training from 1840 to 1899.</emph> G.H.W. Peach. London M.A. 1970.</para>
<page start="218"/>
<para id="p1205"><emph type="i">A history of the College of Sarum St. Michael (Salisbury Training College) from its foundation in 1841 until 1902.</emph> B.D. Bevan. London M.A. (Ext.) 1970.</para>
<para id="p1206"><emph type="i">The history of the training of teachers for secondary schools in England, <emph type="i">c</emph>. 1846&ndash;1930.</emph> Miriam G. Fitch. London M.A. 1931.</para>
<para id="p1207"><emph type="i">A critical examination of teacher training in Wales, 1846&ndash;98.</emph> L.M. Rees. Wales Ph.D. 1968/9.</para>
<para id="p1208"><emph type="i">The registration of teachers in England and Wales from 1846 to 1899, with special reference to the development of common interest and professional independence.</emph> F.L. Massey. London M.A. 1957.</para>
<para id="p1209"><emph type="i">Individual, local and national bargaining for teachers' salaries in England and Wales: a study of the period 1858&ndash;1944.</emph> S.E. Barnes. London Ph.D. 1959.</para>
<para id="p1210"><emph type="i">The development of professional status among the elementary teachers under the School Board for London, 1870&ndash;1904.</emph> R.A. Williams. London M.A. 1953.</para>
<para id="p1211"><emph type="i">The determination of teachers' salaries, with particular reference to secondary schools, 1870&ndash;1919.</emph> H.D. Papworth. London M.A. 1964.</para>
<para id="p1212"><emph type="i">The secondary schoolmaster, 1895&ndash;1914: a study of the qualifications, conditions of employment and professional associations of masters in English secondary schools.</emph> G. Baron. London Ph.D. 1952.</para>
<para id="p1213"><emph type="i">The training of teachers in England and Wales, 1900&ndash;39.</emph> A. Shakoor. Leicester Ph.D. 1964.</para>
<para id="p1214"><emph type="i">The history of Bangor Normal College from its inception to 1908.</emph> L.M. Rees. Wales M.A. 1955.</para>
</section>
</section>
</section>
<section id="s35">
<head>LOCAL HISTORY</head>
<para id="p1215"><emph type="i">The economic and social development of extra-metropolitan Middlesex during the 19th century (1800&ndash;1914).</emph> M. Rees. London M.Sc. 1955.</para>
<para id="p1216"><emph type="i">The economic and social development of Dewsbury in the 19th century.</emph> D.A. Dean. Sheffield M.A. 1963.</para>
<para id="p1217"><emph type="i">Some aspects of the economy of Hull in the 19th century, with special reference to business history.</emph> Joyce M. Bellamy. Hull Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<para id="p1218"><emph type="i">The evolution of Preston townscapes.</emph> K.M. Spencer. Liverpool M.A. 1968.</para>
<para id="p1219"><emph type="i">London, 1801&ndash;51: a geographical study.</emph> O.H.K. Spate. Cambridge Ph.D. 1937.</para>
<para id="p1220"><emph type="i">Urban growth in Bradford and environs, 1800&ndash;1960.</emph> M.J. Mortimore. Leeds M.A. 1963.</para>
<para id="p1221"><emph type="i">The growth, development and modern functions of the county borough of Bradford.</emph> H.B. Hodgson. Leeds M.A. 1939.</para>
<para id="p1222"><emph type="i">Studies in the development of the parish of Bradford, 1800&ndash;47.</emph> Lucy Flanagan. Liverpool M.A. 1931.</para>
<para id="p1223"><emph type="i">The functions and growth of the city of Exeter, 1800&ndash;41.</emph> N.M. Simmonds. Exeter M.A. 1959.</para>
<para id="p1224"><emph type="i">Victorian Exeter, 1837&ndash;1914.</emph> R. Newton. Exeter Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p1225"><emph type="i">The development of municipal government in Swansea in the 19th century.</emph> T. Ridd. Wales M.A. 1955.</para>
<para id="p1226"><emph type="i">The development of quarter sessions government in Devonshire in the 19th century and the transition to county council government.</emph> D.R. Tucker. London M.A. (Ext.) 1949.</para>
<para id="p1227"><emph type="i">The transition from quarter sessions to county councils in the 19th century.</emph> B.J.V. Scott. Exeter M.A. 1962.</para>
<para id="p1228"><emph type="i">The social and economic development of Crewe, 1800&ndash;1923.</emph> W.H. Chaloner. Manchester Ph.D. 1939.</para>
<para id="p1229"><emph type="i">The social and economic development of Crewe, 1830&ndash;80.</emph> W.H. Chaloner. Manchester M.A. 1937.</para>
<page start="219"/>
<para id="p1230"><emph type="i">Nuneaton: a study in urban growth.</emph> D. Milburn. London M.Sc. 1959.</para>
<para id="p1231"><emph type="i">Geographical aspects of the development of Wirksworth from the beginning of the 19th century to the present.</emph> F.S. Ottrey. Nottingham M.A. 1966.</para>
<para id="p1232"><emph type="i">Lincoln: a study in urban morphology.</emph> R. Knowles. Nottingham M.A. 1962.</para>
<para id="p1233"><emph type="i">An urban study of Loughborough.</emph> Gladys H. Wedlock. Nottingham M.A. 1952.</para>
<para id="p1234"><emph type="i">Wolverton: a study in urban geography.</emph> Moira Courtman. London M.Phil. 1968.</para>
<para id="p1235"><emph type="i">The development of Buxton and Matlock since 1800.</emph> T. Marchington. London M.A. 1961.</para>
<para id="p1236"><emph type="i">The public accounts of the county of Lancaster from 1820 to 1889.</emph> D. Gregory. Leeds M.A. 1966.</para>
<para id="p1237"><emph type="i">The administration of the county of Lancashire, 1838&ndash;88.</emph> A.F. Davie. Manchester Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p1238"><emph type="i">The old and the new: the corporation of Bristol, 1820&ndash;51.</emph> G.W.A. Bush. Bristol Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<para id="p1239"><emph type="i">The work of the Halifax town trustees from the passing of the Improvement Act of 1823 to the incorporation of the borough in 1848.</emph> G.R. Dalby. Leeds M.A. 1953.</para>
<para id="p1240"><emph type="i">The economic development of York, 1830&ndash;1914.</emph> B.F. Duckham. Manchester M.A. 1956.</para>
<para id="p1241"><emph type="i">The social structure of York, 1841&ndash;51.</emph> W.A. Armstrong. Birmingham Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p1242"><emph type="i">The social and economic history of St. Helens, 1830&ndash;1900.</emph> T.C. Barker. Manchester Ph.D. 1951.</para>
<para id="p1243"><emph type="i">The social and economic development of Middlesbrough, 1830&ndash;88.</emph> W.S. Martin. Manchester M.A. 1945.</para>
<para id="p1244"><emph type="i">Local government in Penzance, 1830&ndash;75.</emph> R.J. Sadler. Wales M.A. 1951/2.</para>
<para id="p1245"><emph type="i">Southampton in the early dock and railway age, 1830&ndash;60.</emph> Patricia H. Morris. Southampton M.A. 1957.</para>
<para id="p1246"><emph type="i">The development of local government in Salford, 1830&ndash;53.</emph> R.L. Greenall. Leicester M.A. 1970.</para>
<para id="p1247"><emph type="i">Urban development and redevelopment in Croydon, 1835&ndash;1940.</emph> R.C.W. Cox. Leicester Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p1248"><emph type="i">Some aspects of the urban development of Croydon, 1870&ndash;1940.</emph> R.C.W. Cox. Leicester M.A. 1966.</para>
<para id="p1249"><emph type="i">Reading, 1835&ndash;1930: a community power study.</emph> A.F. Cook. Reading Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p1250"><emph type="i">The social, economic and political development of Derby, 1835&ndash;88.</emph> J.D. Standen. Leeds M.A. 1959.</para>
<para id="p1251"><emph type="i">Early Fleetwood, 1835&ndash;47.</emph> J.H. Sutton. Lancaster M.Litt. 1968.</para>
<para id="p1252"><emph type="i">The Municipal Reform Act, 1835.</emph> G.B.A.M. Finlayson. Oxford B.Litt. 1959.</para>
<para id="p1253"><emph type="i">Coventry and the Municipal Corporations Act, 1835: an investigation of the workings of Coventry Corporation mainly between 1750 and 1835, and a critical examination of the Commissioners' Report of 1833.</emph> S.E. Kerrison. Birmingham M.A. 1939.</para>
<para id="p1254"><emph type="i">The suburban development of Greater London, south of the Thames, 1836&ndash;1914.</emph> H.J. Dyos. London Ph.D. 1952.</para>
<para id="p1255"><emph type="i">Local government and some aspects of social change in the parishes of Lambeth, Battersea, and Wandsworth, 1838&ndash;88.</emph> Janet Roebuck. London Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p1256"><emph type="i">Capital investment in the western suburbs of Victorian London.</emph> D.A. Reeder. Leicester Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<para id="p1257"><emph type="i">The Potteries of Kensington: a study of slum development in Victorian London.</emph> Mrs. Patricia E. Malcolmson. Leicester M.Phil. 1970.</para>
<para id="p1258"><emph type="i">The social and economic development of Nottingham in the 19th century.</emph> R.A. Church. Nottingham Ph.D. 1960.</para>
<para id="p1259"><emph type="i">The social structure of Nottingham and adjacent districts in the mid 19th century.</emph> R.J. Smith. Nottingham Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<page start="220"/>
<para id="p1260"><emph type="i">Township boundaries in Furness and Cartmel in the first edition of the Ordnance Survey (1846&ndash;7).</emph> C.J. Hogg. Liverpool M.A. 1951.</para>
<para id="p1261"><emph type="i">Social and economic conditions in the industrial towns of the West Riding of Yorkshire in the hungry forties.</emph> Joyce Hargrave. Leeds M.A. 1940.</para>
<para id="p1262"><emph type="i">Social and administrative development of Chadderton, 1847&ndash;1914.</emph> Elsie Beech. Manchester M.A. 1949.</para>
<para id="p1263"><emph type="i">The city of Wakefield: a study of the growth and functions of an urban settlement.</emph> Rosie Bentham. London M.A. 1939.</para>
<para id="p1264"><emph type="i">Some geographical aspects of urban development in the lower Lea valley since 1850.</emph> Alison D. Grady. London M.A. 1958.</para>
<para id="p1265"><emph type="i">The economic development of Kettering, 1850&ndash;1914.</emph> B.J. Loasby. Cambridge M.Litt. 1957.</para>
<para id="p1266"><emph type="i">The social and economic development of Whitstable, with particular reference to local government administration.</emph> R.A.R. Gray. Kent M.A. 1970.</para>
<para id="p1267"><emph type="i">A history of the development of Walthamstow, 1851&ndash;1901.</emph> R. Wall. London M.Phil. 1969.</para>
<para id="p1268"><emph type="i">Suburban growth in north-west Kent, 1861&ndash;1961.</emph> Mary Waugh. London Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p1269"><emph type="i">Mansfield: the evolution of an urban landscape, 1863&ndash;1963.</emph> J.R.G. Jennings. Nottingham Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p1270"><emph type="i">The role of religious dissent in the reform of municipal government in Birmingham, 1865&ndash;76.</emph> E.P. Hennock. Cambridge Ph.D. 1956.</para>
<para id="p1271"><emph type="i">The development of city government in the United States and the United Kingdom, with special reference to the period since 1870.</emph> E.S. Griffith. Oxford D.Phil. 1925.</para>
<para id="p1272"><emph type="i">Changes in land use in the borough of Northampton during the past 100 years.</emph> M.F. Collins. Oxford B.Litt. 1970.</para>
<para id="p1273"><emph type="i">The economic and social development of South Kirkby and South Elmsall, 1873&ndash;1921.</emph> W.G. Branford. Leeds M.A. 1957.</para>
<para id="p1274"><emph type="i">The growth of Aylesbury and the development of its urban morphology, 1878&ndash;1957.</emph> C.J. Cheshire. Birmingham M.A. 1958.</para>
<para id="p1275"><emph type="i">The social structure and economy of south-west Wales in the late 19th century.</emph> J.H. Davies. Wales M.A. 1967.</para>
<para id="p1276"><emph type="i">Barry: an urban and social geography, 1885&ndash;1966.</emph> J.A. Giggs. Wales Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p1277"><emph type="i">A history of local government in the West Riding of Yorkshire since 1888.</emph> H. Roberts. Leeds M.Comm. 1943.</para>
<para id="p1278"><emph type="i">A study of the change in social origins, political affiliations and length of service of members of the Leeds City Council, 1888&ndash;1953.</emph> Brenda M. Powell. Leeds M.A. 1958.</para>
<para id="p1279"><emph type="i">The political structure of the Wolverhampton Borough Council since 1900.</emph> G.W. Jones. Oxford D.Phil. 1965.</para>
<para id="p1280"><emph type="i">Eccles: a study in town development.</emph> Audrey E. Lumb. Manchester M.A. 1958.</para>
<para id="p1281"><emph type="i">Geographical aspects of the evolution of Boston, Lincolnshire, in the 20th century.</emph> F.H. Molyneux. Nottingham M.A. 1968.</para>
<para id="p1282"><emph type="i">An economic geography of Alfreton, Heanor and Ripley with special reference to changes in the 20th century.</emph> G.A. Measures. Nottingham M.A. 1969.</para>
<para id="p1283"><emph type="i">A comparative study of the contemporary and pre-war urban geography of the East End of London.</emph> Gillian M.L. Simpson. London M.A. 1959.</para>
</section>
<section id="s36">
<head>SCOTLAND</head>
<para id="p1284"><emph type="i">The history of the teaching of classics in Scotland until 1872.</emph> G.M. Sutton. St. Andrews Ph.D. 1956.</para>
<para id="p1285"><emph type="i">Education in Aberdeenshire before 1872.</emph> I.J. Simpson. Aberdeen Ph.D. 1942.</para>
<page start="221"/>
<para id="p1286"><emph type="i">Scottish teachers and educational policy, 1803&ndash;72: attitudes and influence.</emph> J.D. Myers. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p1287"><emph type="i">A history of education in Stirlingshire up to the Act of 1872.</emph> A. Bain. St. Andrews Ph.D. 1960.</para>
<para id="p1288"><emph type="i">A survey of church influence on education in Scotland, with special reference to the extent and content of religious teaching in the day schools before 1872.</emph> D.M. McFarlan. Glasgow Ph.D. 1956/7.</para>
<para id="p1289"><emph type="i">The Scottish tradition in education: an intimate study of the early 19th century.</emph> I.D.B. Finlayson. Glasgow Ph.D. 1956/7.</para>
<para id="p1290"><emph type="i">An enquiry into the reading habits of the working classes in Scotland from 1830 to 1840.</emph> A.R. Thompson. Glasgow B.Litt. 1961.</para>
<para id="p1291"><emph type="i">A history of the public library movement in Scotland.</emph> W.R. Aitken. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1956.</para>
<para id="p1292"><emph type="i">The development of public libraries in Scotland.</emph> W.E. Tyler. Strathclyde M.A. 1967.</para>
<para id="p1293"><emph type="i">A history of the Scottish farm worker, 1800&ndash;50.</emph> G.F.B. Houston. Oxford B.Litt. 1954.</para>
<para id="p1294"><emph type="i">James Loch and the house of Sutherland, 1812&ndash;55.</emph> E.S. Richards. Nottingham Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p1295"><emph type="i">The development of the port and trade of Dundee, 1815&ndash;1967.</emph> N.I. Beckles. Dundee Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p1296"><emph type="i">The decline of the handloom weaving industry in Scotland during the years 1815&ndash;45.</emph> Mrs. Brenda P.R. Gaskin. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1955.</para>
<para id="p1297"><emph type="i">James Young, Scottish industrialist and philanthropist.</emph> J. Butt. Glasgow Ph.D. 1964.</para>
<para id="p1298"><emph type="i">William Lindsay Alexander (1808&ndash;84), the man and his work.</emph> C.C. Wallick. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1950/1.</para>
<para id="p1299"><emph type="i">William Arnot: his life, work and thought.</emph> S.H. Merriam. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1956.</para>
<para id="p1300"><emph type="i">The influence, direct and indirect, of the writings of Erskine of Linlathen on religious thought in Scotland.</emph> R.A. Reid. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1930.</para>
<para id="p1301"><emph type="i">The contribution of Thomas Erskine of Linlathen and his writings to Scottish theology.</emph> J.C. Conn. St. Andrews Ph.D. 1935.</para>
<para id="p1302"><emph type="i">John Brown of Edinburgh, 1784&ndash;1858, churchman and theologian.</emph> W.L. McCoy. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1956.</para>
<para id="p1303"><emph type="i">William Symington, churchman and theologian, 1795&ndash;1862.</emph> R. Blackwood. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1962/3.</para>
<para id="p1304"><emph type="i">Robert Murray McCheyne (1813&ndash;43): a study of an early 19th-century Scottish Evangelical.</emph> D.V. Yeaworth. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1957.</para>
<para id="p1305"><emph type="i">Coal mining in the west of Scotland in the 19th century: the Dixon enterprises.</emph> A. Slaven. Glasgow B.Litt. 1967.</para>
<para id="p1306"><emph type="i">The growth and fluctuations of the Scottish pig iron trade, 1828&ndash;73.</emph> R.H. Campbell. Aberdeen Ph.D. 1956.</para>
<para id="p1307"><emph type="i">The economic history of the Scottish iron and steel industry, with particular reference to the period 1830&ndash;80.</emph> I.F. Gibson. London Ph.D. 1955.</para>
<para id="p1308"><emph type="i">Religion and society in the early 19th century: a comparative study of church parties within the established churches of Massachusetts and Scotland.</emph> Wendy S. Wilson. Aberdeen M.Litt. 1969.</para>
<para id="p1309"><emph type="i">The voluntary controversy in the Church of Scotland, 1829&ndash;43.</emph> A.B. Montgomery. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1953.</para>
<para id="p1310"><emph type="i">The failure and recovery of social criticism in the Scottish Church, 1830&ndash;1950.</emph> D.C. Smith. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1964.</para>
<para id="p1311"><emph type="i">Middle-class housing and the growth of suburban communities in the West End of Glasgow, 1830&ndash;1914.</emph> M.A. Simpson. Glasgow B.Litt. 1970.</para>
<para id="p1312"><emph type="i">The American Negro in Scotland in the 19th century.</emph> E.S.H. Dixon. Edinburgh M.Litt. 1968/9.</para>
<page start="222"/>
<para id="p1313"><emph type="i">Glasgow parliamentary constituency, 1832&ndash;46.</emph> D.A. Teviotdale. Glasgow B.Litt. 1963.</para>
<para id="p1314"><emph type="i">Scottish Chartism and its economic background.</emph> L.C. Wright. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1951.</para>
<para id="p1315"><emph type="i">The Chartist movement in Scotland.</emph> A. Wilson. Oxford D.Phil. 1951.</para>
<para id="p1316"><emph type="i">Andrew A. Bonar, 1810&ndash;92: a study of his life, work and religious thought.</emph> R.E. Palmer. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1955.</para>
<para id="p1317"><emph type="i">Railways and the transformation of the Scottish economy.</emph> W. Vamplew. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p1318"><emph type="i">School inspection in Scotland, 1840&ndash;1966.</emph> T.R. Bone. Glasgow Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p1319"><emph type="i">The life and work of William Bell Scott, 1811&ndash;90.</emph> Mrs. Vera Smith. Durham Ph.D. 1953.</para>
<para id="p1320"><emph type="i">Note issue in Scottish banking, 1844&ndash;1953.</emph> M. Gaskin. Liverpool M.A. 1954/5.</para>
<para id="p1321"><emph type="i">Aspects of the population geography of the eastern border counties of Scotland, 1850&ndash;1967.</emph> Joan MacC. Galt. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p1322"><emph type="i">The rural-urban fringe of Edinburgh, 1850&ndash;1967.</emph> A.J. Strachan. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p1323"><emph type="i">The renascence of churchmanship in the Church of Scotland, 1850&ndash;1920.</emph> W. Horsburgh. St. Andrews Ph.D. 1958.</para>
<para id="p1324"><emph type="i">The Scots coal industry, 1854&ndash;66.</emph> A.T. Youngson. Aberdeen Ph.D. 1953.</para>
<para id="p1325"><emph type="i">An economic history of shipbuilding and engineering, with special reference to the west of Scotland.</emph> W.S. Cormack. Glasgow Ph.D. 1930.</para>
<para id="p1326"><emph type="i">Changing forms of church life: a study of the churches and town of St. Andrews, 1865&ndash;1965.</emph> W.F. Hobbs. St. Andrews Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p1327"><emph type="i">The origin and development of the Old Catholic group of churches, etc.</emph> W.H. de Voil. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1937.</para>
<para id="p1328"><emph type="i">Education in Lanarkshire: a historical survey on the Act of 1872 from original and contemporary sources.</emph> Mary M. Mackintosh. Glasgow Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p1329"><emph type="i">The ad hoc administration of education in Scotland, 1872&ndash;1929.</emph> J.H. Walker. Glasgow Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p1330"><emph type="i">The School Board of Glasgow, 1873&ndash;1919.</emph> J.M. Roxburgh. Glasgow B.Litt. 1969.</para>
<para id="p1331"><emph type="i">The Scottish economy during the 'Great Depression', 1873&ndash;96, with special reference to the heavy industries of the south-west.</emph> T.J. Byres. Glasgow B.Litt. 1963.</para>
<para id="p1332"><emph type="i">The Liberal party in Scotland, 1885&ndash;95.</emph> J.G. Kellas. London Ph.D. 1962.</para>
<para id="p1333"><emph type="i">The industrial geography of Ayrshire and its development since 1900.</emph> D.F. Hagger. London M.Sc. 1955.</para>
<para id="p1334"><emph type="i">Local authority housing in Dundee, 1919&ndash;39.</emph> W.D. Carroll. Dundee B.Phil. 1969.</para>
<para id="p1335"><emph type="i">A survey of Scottish internal transport since 1920.</emph> R.T. Foster. Wales M.A. 1965.</para>
</section>
<section id="s37">
<head>IRELAND</head>
<para id="p1336"><emph type="i">The application in Ireland of English and British legislation made before 1801.</emph> A.G. Donaldson. Belfast Ph.D. 1952.</para>
<para id="p1337"><emph type="i">Urban settlements of Co. Antrim.</emph> D.A. Clerk. Belfast M.A. 1949.</para>
<para id="p1338"><emph type="i">The development of education in the county of Londonderry from 1800 to 1922.</emph> W.D. Hamilton. Belfast M.A. 1963.</para>
<para id="p1339"><emph type="i">A history of the Londonderry shirt industry.</emph> E.H. Slade. Belfast M.A. 1937.</para>
<para id="p1340"><emph type="i">The historical geography of Londonderry in the 19th century.</emph> J.H. Johnson. London Ph.D. 1962.</para>
<page start="223"/>
<para id="p1341"><emph type="i">The economic significance of the London companies as landlords in Ireland during the period 1800&ndash;70.</emph> Olive Robinson. Belfast Ph.D. 1957.</para>
<para id="p1342"><emph type="i">The Downshire estates in Ireland under the 3rd marquis of Downshire, 1801&ndash;45: a study of Irish estate management in the first half of the 19th century.</emph> W.A. Maguire. Belfast Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p1343"><emph type="i">Irish immigration into Great Britain, 1798&ndash;1838.</emph> Barbara M. Kerr. Oxford B.Litt. 1939.</para>
<para id="p1344"><emph type="i">Irish immigration in Great Britain during the first half of the 19th century.</emph> F.L. Wilson. Manchester M.A. 1946.</para>
<para id="p1345"><emph type="i">The civil administration of Ireland, 1801&ndash;48.</emph> S.M. Houghton. Manchester M.A. 1924.</para>
<para id="p1346"><emph type="i">An assessment of the social, religious and political aspects of Congregationalism in Ireland in the 19th century.</emph> J.M. Henry. Belfast Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<para id="p1347"><emph type="i">Presbyterian missionary activity among Irish Roman Catholics in the 19th century.</emph> R.J. Rodgers. Belfast M.A. 1969.</para>
<para id="p1348"><emph type="i">History of the ruling eldership in Irish Presbyterianism.</emph> J.M. Barkley. Belfast M.A. 1952.</para>
<para id="p1349"><emph type="i">The training of teachers in Ireland from 1811 to the present day.</emph> J.W. Musson. Belfast Ph.D. 1955.</para>
<para id="p1350"><emph type="i">The influence of the Rev. Henry Cooke on the political life of Ulster.</emph> J. Jamieson. Belfast M.A. 1950.</para>
<para id="p1351"><emph type="i">Robert Sullivan - an Irish educationalist and benefactor: a study of his life and times.</emph> J. Robinson. Belfast M.A. 1962.</para>
<para id="p1352"><emph type="i">The emergence of the Irish banking system, 1820&ndash;45.</emph> G.L. Barrow. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1970.</para>
<para id="p1353"><emph type="i">The struggle for tenant-right in Ulster, 1829&ndash;50.</emph> B.A. Kennedy. Belfast M.A. 1943.</para>
<para id="p1354"><emph type="i">Geographical factors in the growth and decline of the ports of north-east Ireland.</emph> Sybil Ward. Belfast M.A. 1940.</para>
<para id="p1355"><emph type="i">The chief factors determining the developments in primary education, Ireland 1831&ndash;1947.</emph> W. Jacques. Belfast Ph.D. 1952.</para>
<para id="p1356"><emph type="i">Catholic reaction to mixed elementary education in Ireland between 1831 and 1870.</emph> M. McKeown. Belfast M.A. 1962.</para>
<para id="p1357"><emph type="i">The development of National schools in Belfast, 1831&ndash;51.</emph> A. Jordan. Belfast M.A. 1970.</para>
<para id="p1358"><emph type="i">The development of educational facilities for handicapped children in Ireland, with particular reference to the deaf in Ulster.</emph> J.G. McClelland. Belfast M.A. 1965/6.</para>
<para id="p1359"><emph type="i">The Irish Board of Works, 1831&ndash;78, with particular reference to the Famine years.</emph> A.R.G. Griffiths. Cambridge Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p1360"><emph type="i">An investigation into the effects of the 1832 Reform Act on the general elections of 1832, 1835 and 1837 in Ireland.</emph> R.C. Brewer. London M.Sc. (Ext.) 1965.</para>
<para id="p1361"><emph type="i">The condition of the Irish peasantry, 1840&ndash;50.</emph> P. Hinckley. Leeds M.A. 1917.</para>
<para id="p1362"><emph type="i">The internal migration of labour in Ireland, 1841&ndash;1911.</emph> M.E.M. El Rayah. Belfast M.A. 1961.</para>
<para id="p1363"><emph type="i">The development of the urban pattern of Ireland, 1841&ndash;81.</emph> H.L. Mason. Wales Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p1364"><emph type="i">The relations between Great Britain and Ireland: 1841&ndash;8.</emph> K.B. Nowlan. Cambridge Ph.D. 1955.</para>
<para id="p1365"><emph type="i">The political and social teachings of the Young Irelanders, 1842&ndash;8.</emph> G.R. Clarke. Belfast M.A. 1936.</para>
<para id="p1366"><emph type="i">An economic history of livestock in Ireland since the Famine.</emph> J. O'Donovan. Oxford B.Litt. 1931.</para>
<para id="p1367"><emph type="i">Irish overseas emigration and the state during the great Famine.</emph> O.O.G.M. MacDonagh. Cambridge Ph.D. 1952.</para>
<page start="224"/>
<para id="p1368"><emph type="i">The regional variations in the fall of population in Ireland, 1846&ndash;61, following the great Irish Famine.</emph> S.H. Cousens. Cambridge Ph.D. 1958.</para>
<para id="p1369"><emph type="i">The administration of the poor laws in Ireland till 30 November 1921 and in Northern Ireland from 1 December 1921 till present date, 1942.</emph> H. Miller. Belfast M.Com.Sc. 1942.</para>
<para id="p1370"><emph type="i">The economic history of the engineering industry in the north of Ireland to 1914.</emph> W.E. Coe. Belfast Ph.D. 1964.</para>
<para id="p1371"><emph type="i">Institutional factors in the development of Irish agriculture, 1850&ndash;1915.</emph> J.P. Huttman. London Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p1372"><emph type="i">An economic history of agriculture in Northern Ireland, 1850&ndash;1900.</emph> D.L. Armstrong. Belfast Ph.D. 1952.</para>
<para id="p1373"><emph type="i">The general election of 1852 in Ireland.</emph> J.H. Whyte. Oxford B.Litt. 1951.</para>
<para id="p1374"><emph type="i">Newman's work for university education in Ireland.</emph> J.S.F. McGrath. Oxford D.Phil. 1948.</para>
<para id="p1375"><emph type="i">The Irish university question and party politics, 1865&ndash;79.</emph> P. Ramsden. Durham M.A. 1965.</para>
<para id="p1376"><emph type="i">The Catholic movement for the disestablishment of the Irish Church, 1864&ndash;9.</emph> E.R. Norman. Cambridge Ph.D. 1964.</para>
<para id="p1377"><emph type="i">Irish land reform and English Liberal politics, 1865&ndash;70.</emph> E.D. Steele. Cambridge Ph.D. 1963.</para>
<para id="p1378"><emph type="i">The economic objects and results of land legislation in Ireland in the Gladstonian era.</emph> E.R. Nuttall. Wales M.A. 1936.</para>
<para id="p1379"><emph type="i">The Irish Protestant churches and social and political issues, 1870&ndash;1914.</emph> A.J. Megahey. Belfast Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p1380"><emph type="i">The Catholic Church and Irish politics, 1879&ndash;92.</emph> C.J. Woods. Nottingham Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p1381"><emph type="i">William Abraham, 1842&ndash;1922.</emph> E.W. Evans. Wales M.A. 1953.</para>
<para id="p1382"><emph type="i">The Ulster issue against its social and economic background, <emph type="i">c</emph>.1880&ndash;93: the evolution and interaction of society and politics in Ulster from about 1880 to the defeat of the Second Home Rule Bill.</emph> B.P. Lenman. Cambridge M.Litt. 1965.</para>
<para id="p1383"><emph type="i">Trade union beginnings in Belfast and district, with special reference to the period 1881&ndash;1900 and to the work of the Belfast and District United Trades Council during that period.</emph> D.W. Bleakley. Belfast M.A. 1955.</para>
<para id="p1384"><emph type="i">A study of devolution, with special reference to the government of Northern Ireland.</emph> P.N.S. Mansergh. Oxford D.Phil. 1936.</para>
<para id="p1385"><emph type="i">Public opinion and educational reform in the north of Ireland, 1900&ndash;54.</emph> J.E. Holmes. Belfast M.A. 1968/9.</para>
<para id="p1386"><emph type="i">Joseph Devlin: Ulsterman and Irishman.</emph> F.J. Whitford. London M.A. (Ext.) 1959.</para>
<para id="p1387"><emph type="i">The educational work of Sir Bertram Windle, F.R.S. (1858&ndash;1929), with particular reference to his contributions to higher education in Ireland.</emph> H. Neeson. Belfast M.A. 1962.</para>
<para id="p1388"><emph type="i">Wages and prices in Belfast, 1914&ndash;23.</emph> W. Semple. Belfast M.Com.Sc. 1923.</para>
<para id="p1389"><emph type="i">The economic life of Ireland since 1918.</emph> E.G. Thomas. Manchester Ph.D. 1934.</para>
<para id="p1390"><emph type="i">An outline political geography of Northern Ireland since Partition.</emph> J.R.V. Prescott. Durham M.A. 1958.</para>
<para id="p1391"><emph type="i">The Irish Free State and Commonwealth development, 1919&ndash;32.</emph> G.H. Byrne. Belfast M.A. 1969.</para>
<para id="p1392"><emph type="i">Church and state in the Republic of Ireland.</emph> J.H. Whyte. Belfast Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p1393"><emph type="i">The career of Michael Collins, with special reference to the treaty of 1921.</emph> Mrs. Patricia A. Freeman. Bristol M.A. 1963.</para>
<para id="p1394"><emph type="i">The senate in Northern Ireland, 1921&ndash;62.</emph> P.F. McGill. Belfast Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<para id="p1395"><emph type="i">The development of industry in the Republic of Ireland since 1922: a geographical investigation.</emph> D.J. Dwyer. London Ph.D. 1960.</para>
<page start="225"/>
<para id="p1396"><emph type="i">The development of post-primary education in Eire since 1922, with special reference to vocational education.</emph> P.K. O'Leary. Belfast Ph.D. 1962.</para>
</section>
</section>
</report>
