<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="154862" pubid="1512" publish="true">
<title>Britain: Long Periods from the 17th-Century</title>
<subtitle></subtitle>
<page start="125"/>
<section id="s1">
<head>BRITAIN: LONG PERIODS FROM THE 17TH CENTURY</head>
<section id="s2">
<head>HISTORICAL GEOGRAPHY</head>
<para id="p1"><emph type="i">The historical geography of the woodlands of the southern Chilterns, 1600&ndash;1947.</emph> A.J. Mansfield. London M.Sc. 1952.</para>
<para id="p2"><emph type="i">Some aspects of the historical geography of the Humber warplands, <emph type="i">c</emph>. 1600&ndash;1940.</emph> G.G. Robinson. Hull M.A. 1968/9.</para>
<para id="p3"><emph type="i">The changing landscape of south-west Essex from 1600 to 1850.</emph> R. Allison. London Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p4"><emph type="i">Changes in the pattern of rural settlement in northern Essex between 1650 and 1850.</emph> Susan E. Cunningham. Manchester M.A. 1968.</para>
<para id="p5"><emph type="i">Regional geography in Britain, 1650&ndash;1750.</emph> F.V. Emery. Oxford B.Litt. 1955.</para>
<para id="p6"><emph type="i">A contribution to the historical geography of northeast Hampshire, <emph type="i">c</emph>. 1600&ndash;1850.</emph> G.I.M. Jones. London M.Phil. 1969.</para>
<para id="p7"><emph type="i">Bournemouth - a geographical study.</emph> D.L.W. Sherry. Manchester M.A. 1969.</para>
<para id="p8"><emph type="i">An analysis of the town plan of Nottingham: a study in historical geography.</emph> F.I. Straw. Nottingham M.A. 1967.</para>
<para id="p9"><emph type="i">Bromley, Beckenham and Penge, Kent, since 1750: a comparative study of the changing geography of three towns on the southern fringe of the metropolis.</emph> Bessie Taylor (Mother Mary Baptist). London Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p10"><emph type="i">The settlement pattern of the Yorkshire wolds, 1770 to 1850.</emph> M.B. Gleave. Hull M.A. 1960.</para>
<para id="p11"><emph type="i">The growth of the borough and the distribution and density of population in the Chesterfield region since the Industrial Revolution.</emph> F.C. Couzens. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1941.</para>
<para id="p12"><emph type="i">Population changes and industrial growth in Leicestershire since the late 18th century.</emph> T.J. Chandler. London M.Sc. 1955.</para>
<para id="p13"><emph type="i">Rural settlement in North Wales since the late 18th century.</emph> Muriel M. Rees. Oxford B.Litt. 1951.</para>
<para id="p14"><emph type="i">Population and settlement in Kesteven, <emph type="i">c</emph>. 1775-<emph type="i">c</emph>. 1885.</emph> D.R. Mills. Nottingham M.A. 1957.</para>
<para id="p15"><emph type="i">Comparative studies in the historical geography of woodlands in south-east England and Wales, 1790&ndash;1919.</emph> J.A. Evans. London Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p16"><emph type="i">A regional study of urban development in coastal Sussex since the 18th century.</emph> H.C. Brookfield. London Ph.D. 1950.</para>
</section>
<section id="s3">
<head>POLITICAL HISTORY</head>
<para id="p17"><emph type="i">Stamford and the Cecils 1700&ndash;1885: a study in political control.</emph> J.M. Lee. Oxford B.Litt. 1957.</para>
<para id="p18"><emph type="i">The parliamentary history of Reading, 1750&ndash;1850.</emph> R.C.J.F. Baily. Reading Ph.D. 1944.</para>
<para id="p19"><emph type="i">The royal instructions to colonial governors, 1783&ndash;1854: a study in British colonial policy.</emph> J.C. Beaglehole. London Ph.D. 1929.</para>
<para id="p20"><emph type="i">Imperial land policy, 1783&ndash;1848.</emph> R.G. Riddell. Oxford B.Litt. 1934.</para>
<page start="126"/>
</section>
<section id="s4">
<head>ECONOMIC AND SOCIAL HISTORY</head>
<section id="s5">
<head>General</head>
<para id="p21"><emph type="i">The effect of economic progress on profits and interest: an essay in the history of British economic thought, 1650&ndash;1850.</emph> G.S.L. Tucker. Cambridge Ph.D. 1954.</para>
<para id="p22"><emph type="i">The creation and liquidation of public debt in the United Kingdom during the 18th and 19th centuries economically and financially regarded.</emph> C.P. Spruill. Oxford B.Litt. 1922.</para>
<para id="p23"><emph type="i">Some aspects of English country banking, 1750 to 1844.</emph> L.S. Pressnell. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1953.</para>
<para id="p24"><emph type="i">Some aspects of Bank of England policy, 1780&ndash;1850.</emph> J.K. Horsefield. Bristol M.A. 1949.</para>
<para id="p25"><emph type="i">The development of industries in London south of the Thames, 1750&ndash;1850.</emph> R.J. Hartridge. London M.Sc. 1955.</para>
<para id="p26"><emph type="i">The development of industry in Burton-upon-Trent prior to 1900.</emph> C.C. Owen. Sheffield Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p27"><emph type="i">The east Midlands industrial area: a regional study of industrial location.</emph> D.M. Smith. Nottingham Ph.D. 1961.</para>
<para id="p28"><emph type="i">The economic development of Wolverhampton, 1750&ndash;1850.</emph> D.B.M. Huffer. London M.A. 1958.</para>
<para id="p29"><emph type="i">Greater Nottingham: a geographical study of industrial development.</emph> J.M. Hunter. Reading Ph.D. 1953.</para>
<para id="p30"><emph type="i">The economic development of the Erewash valley: a study in economic geography.</emph> E. Pearson. London M.Sc. (Ext.) 1936.</para>
<para id="p31"><emph type="i">Industrial change and settlement in north-east Worcestershire, <emph type="i">c</emph>. 1775&ndash;1875.</emph> B.C.G. Nokes. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1968.</para>
<para id="p32"><emph type="i">A geographical analysis of the development of certain industries in north-east England.</emph> P. Pilbin. Durham M.Sc. 1935.</para>
<para id="p33"><emph type="i">Industrial settlement in the Colne and Holme valleys, 1750&ndash;1960.</emph> J.C.R. Camm. Hull M.Sc. 1963.</para>
<para id="p34"><emph type="i">The economic development of Tees-side, 1750&ndash;1850.</emph> A.J. Parkinson. Durham M.A. 1951.</para>
<para id="p35"><emph type="i">The development of the coal, iron and shipbuilding industries of west Cumberland, 1750&ndash;1914.</emph> O. Wood. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1952.</para>
<para id="p36"><emph type="i">The problems of the economic and social geography of the south central Lancashire coal and cotton area.</emph> P.J. Rimmer. Manchester M.A. 1960.</para>
<para id="p37"><emph type="i">Aspects of the modern economic geography of the Calder-Darwen valley towns, Lancashire.</emph> K. Wallwork. Manchester M.A. 1955.</para>
<para id="p38"><emph type="i">The evolution of an industrial landscape: the Calder-Darwen valley, Lancashire, from <emph type="i">c</emph>. 1740 to 1914.</emph> K.L. Wallwork. Leicester Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p39"><emph type="i">Lead, land and coal as sources of landlords' income in Northumberland between 1700 and 1850.</emph> W.M. Hughes. Newcastle Ph.D. 1963.</para>
<para id="p40"><emph type="i">The industrial development of Ashton-under-Lyne, 1780&ndash;1850.</emph> F. Kenworthy. Manchester M.A. 1929.</para>
<para id="p41"><emph type="i">The Industrial Revolution in Cornwall, 1740&ndash;1870.</emph> W.J. Rowe. Oxford D.Phil. 1950.</para>
<para id="p42"><emph type="i">The evolution of industries and settlements between Merthyr Tydfil and Abergavenny from 1740 to 1840.</emph> C. Davies. Wales M.A. 1949.</para>
<para id="p43"><emph type="i">A study of the economic development of the lower Conway valley and Creuddyn peninsula, 1750&ndash;1914.</emph> D.G. Griffith. Wales M.A. 1954.</para>
<para id="p44"><emph type="i">Aberdare, 1750&ndash;1850: a study in the growth of an industrial community.</emph> A.C. Davies. Wales M.A. 1963.</para>
<para id="p45"><emph type="i">The industrial history of the parish of Aberdare from 1800 to 1900.</emph> G.I. Thomas. Wales M.A. 1943.</para>
<para id="p46"><emph type="i">Certain aspects of the Industrial Revolution in South Wales, 1760&ndash;1850.</emph> A.H. John. Cambridge Ph.D. 1940.</para>
<page start="127"/>
<para id="p47"><emph type="i">The growth of industrialism in the valley of Ebbw Vale.</emph> F.J. Ball. London M.A. (Ext.) 1959.</para>
<para id="p48"><emph type="i">The Llwchwr and Amman valleys to 1939: a study in industrial development.</emph> D. Davies. Wales M.A. 1959.</para>
<para id="p49"><emph type="i">The industrial development of the Rhondda valleys to 1910.</emph> E.D. Lewis. Wales M.A. 1940.</para>
<para id="p50"><emph type="i">A study of the course of change in the customary and in the specified or normal hours of work of manual workers in certain British industries and of the factors affecting changes in the specified or normal hours from the 18th century to the present day.</emph> M.A. Bienefeld. London Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p51"><emph type="i">Wages in the Leeds area, 1770&ndash;1850.</emph> J.H. Lenton. Leeds M.Phil. 1969.</para>
<para id="p52"><emph type="i">The influence of technological change on the social attitudes and trade-union policies of workers in the British engineering industry, 1780&ndash;1860.</emph> K.R. Burgess. Leeds Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p53"><emph type="i">Development of productive techniques in Birmingham, 1760 to 1851.</emph> J.R. Immer. Oxford B.Litt. 1954.</para>
<para id="p54"><emph type="i">Women workers and the Industrial Revolution, 1750&ndash;1850.</emph> Ivy Pinchbeck. London Ph.D. 1930.</para>
<para id="p55"><emph type="i">The responsibilities of employers and others for the maintenance and support of injured workmen and their families, including the families of deceased workmen, during the half century before 1840.</emph> H. Smith. London M.A. (Ext.) 1964.</para>
</section>
<section id="s6">
<head>Specific Industries</head>
<para id="p56"><emph type="i">A geographical study of the Cumberland coalfield.</emph> T.H. Bainbridge. Durham M.Sc. 1934.</para>
<para id="p57"><emph type="i">A detailed survey of the history and development of the South Wales coal industry, <emph type="i">c</emph>. 1750 to <emph type="i">c</emph>. 1850.</emph> L.B. Collier. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1941.</para>
<para id="p58"><emph type="i">A study of the Daucleddau coalfield, Pembrokeshire.</emph> G. Edwards. Birmingham M.A. 1950.</para>
<para id="p59"><emph type="i">An economic and historical survey of the development of the anthracite industry, with special reference to the Swansea valley.</emph> D.G. John. Wales M.A. 1923.</para>
<para id="p60"><emph type="i">The development of lead mining and of the coal and iron industries in north Derbyshire and south Yorkshire, 1700&ndash;1850.</emph> G.G. Hopkinson. Sheffield Ph.D. 1958.</para>
<para id="p61"><emph type="i">The economic and social conditions of lead-miners in the northern Pennines in the 18th and 19th centuries.</emph> C.J. Hunt. Durham M.Litt. 1968.</para>
<para id="p62"><emph type="i">The social and economic conditions of the Lancashire miner, to 1870.</emph> Dorothy I. Moore. Manchester M.A. 1921.</para>
<para id="p63"><emph type="i">The copper industry in Lancashire and North Wales.</emph> J.R. Harris. Manchester Ph.D. 1952.</para>
<para id="p64"><emph type="i">The history of the growth and organisation of the copper industry of Swansea and district.</emph> W.R. John. Wales M.A. 1912.</para>
<para id="p65"><emph type="i">Iron and steel industry of south Staffordshire, 1760&ndash;1950.</emph> D.B. Evans. Birmingham M.A. 1951.</para>
<para id="p66"><emph type="i">The Dowlais ironworks and its industrial community, 1760&ndash;1850: a local study in economic and social history of the late 18th and early 19th centuries.</emph> K.T. Weetch. London M.Sc. 1963.</para>
<para id="p67"><emph type="i">The Crawshay dynasty: a study in industrial organisation and development, 1765&ndash;1867.</emph> J.P. Addis. Wales M.A. 1954.</para>
<para id="p68"><emph type="i">The economic history of the British iron and steel industry, 1784&ndash;1897.</emph> A. Birch. Manchester Ph.D. 1953.</para>
<para id="p69"><emph type="i">The slate industry of North Wales: a study of the changes in economic organisation from 1780 to the present day.</emph> D.D. Pritchard. Wales M.A. 1935.</para>
<page start="128"/>
<para id="p70"><emph type="i">The social and historical geography of the Ffestiniog slate industry.</emph> J.G. Jones. Wales M.A. 1959.</para>
<para id="p71"><emph type="i">The slate industry in North Wales, with special reference to Merioneth.</emph> E.L. Lewis. Wales M.A. 1917.</para>
<para id="p72"><emph type="i">An introduction to the development of the mechanical engineering industry, 1750&ndash;1900.</emph> A.T. Kings. London M.Sc. 1923.</para>
<para id="p73"><emph type="i">The historical geography of the engineering industry in Leicester.</emph> G.T. Rimmington. Leicester M.A. 1958.</para>
<para id="p74"><emph type="i">Studies in the history of textile technology.</emph> R.L. Hills. Manchester Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p75"><emph type="i">The Gloucestershire woollen industry in the 18th and 19th centuries.</emph> R. Perry. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1947.</para>
<para id="p76"><emph type="i">The west of England woollen industry, 1750&ndash;1840.</emph> J.H. Morris. London M.Sc. 1934.</para>
<para id="p77"><emph type="i">The Industrial Revolution and the textile industries of Somerset.</emph> H.C. Oram. Bristol M.A. 1930.</para>
<para id="p78"><emph type="i">Bolton and the development of the cotton industry from the Industrial Revolution to 1870.</emph> Constance V. Bradley. Manchester M.A. 1921.</para>
<para id="p79"><emph type="i">The contribution of water power development to the progress of the cotton spinning industry, with particular reference to the Bolton district (period 1770&ndash;1845).</emph> E.J. Foulkes. Wales M.A. 1943.</para>
<para id="p80"><emph type="i">M'Connel and Kennedy, fine cotton spinners: a study in business enterprise in the cotton industry, 1795&ndash;1840.</emph> C.H. Lee. Cambridge M.Litt. 1966.</para>
<para id="p81"><emph type="i">The economic development of Norwich, 1750&ndash;1850, with special reference to the worsted industry.</emph> J.K. Edwards. Leeds Ph.D. 1963.</para>
<para id="p82"><emph type="i">The British hosiery trade: its history and organisation.</emph> F.A. Wells. London Ph.D. 1931.</para>
<para id="p83"><emph type="i">The Coventry silk-ribbon industry from the introduction of the use of the Dutch engine loom (<emph type="i">c</emph>. 1770) to the Cobden Commercial Treaty (1860).</emph> H. Miles. Oxford B.Litt. 1930.</para>
<para id="p84"><emph type="i">History of the Birmingham gun trade.</emph> Dorothy W. Young. Birmingham M.Com. 1936.</para>
<para id="p85"><emph type="i">An account of the needle industry up to the beginning of the factory system.</emph> S.H. Hardy. Birmingham M.Com. 1940.</para>
<para id="p86"><emph type="i">The history, development and organisation of the Birmingham jewellery trade.</emph> J.C. Roche. Birmingham M.Com. 1926.</para>
<para id="p87"><emph type="i">The Sheffield cutlery and allied trades and their markets in the 18th and 19th centuries.</emph> P.C. Garlick. Sheffield M.A. 1951.</para>
<para id="p88"><emph type="i">The development and location of the soap-manufacturing industry in Great Britain, 1700&ndash;1950.</emph> L. Gittins. London Ph.D. 1962.</para>
<para id="p89"><emph type="i">The economic development of the north Staffordshire potteries since 1730, with special reference to the Industrial Revolution.</emph> J. Thomas. London Ph.D. 1934.</para>
<para id="p90"><emph type="i">The history of the straw-hat and straw-plaiting industries of Great Britain to 1914, with special reference to the social conditions of the workers engaged in them.</emph> J.G. Dony. London Ph.D. 1941.</para>
<para id="p91"><emph type="i">A history of the nut and bolt industry in the west Midlands.</emph> J.A.C. Baker. Birmingham M.Com. 1965.</para>
<para id="p92"><emph type="i">A history of the pharmaceutical industry, with particular reference to Allen and Hanbury, 1775&ndash;1843.</emph> S.S. Stander. London M.Sc. 1965.</para>
<para id="p93"><emph type="i">Howards, chemical manufacturers, 1797&ndash;1837, a study in business history.</emph> A.W. Slater. London M.Sc. 1956.</para>
<para id="p94"><emph type="i">A historico-geographical survey of the alkali industry of Great Britain from 1789 to the present day.</emph> H. Thomas. London Ph.D. 1935.</para>
<para id="p95"><emph type="i">The growth and decline of the port of Whitehaven, Cumberland, 1650 to 1900.</emph> J.E. Williams. Leeds M.A. 1951.</para>
<page start="129"/>
<para id="p96"><emph type="i">The Dee estuary - an historical geography of its use as a port.</emph> J.P. Bethell. Wales M.Sc. 1952.</para>
<para id="p97"><emph type="i">The estuarine ports of the Exe and the Teign, with special reference to the period 1660&ndash;1880: a study in historical geography.</emph> E.A.G. Clark. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1957.</para>
<para id="p98"><emph type="i">The haven of Milford and its influence on the human geography of the adjacent area with particular reference to the period after 1700.</emph> J.A. Evans. Birmingham M.A. 1961.</para>
<para id="p99"><emph type="i">The Devon fishing industry, 1760&ndash;1860.</emph> A.M. Northway. Exeter M.A. 1969.</para>
<para id="p100"><emph type="i">The British Fisheries Society, 1786&ndash;1893.</emph> Jean M. Dunlop. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1952.</para>
<para id="p101"><emph type="i">The historical geography of the seafaring industry off the coast of Cardigan Bay during the 18th and 19th centuries.</emph> Margaret E. Hughes. Wales M.A. 1962.</para>
<para id="p102"><emph type="i">Dover: the historical geography of the town and port since 1750.</emph> D.R.E. Philpott. London M.A. 1964.</para>
<para id="p103"><emph type="i">The geography of the port of Great Yarmouth, 1750&ndash;1850.</emph> D.A. Lewis. Manchester M.A. 1955.</para>
</section>
<section id="s7">
<head>Transport and Communications</head>
<para id="p104"><emph type="i">The postal history of Kent, 1633&ndash;1840.</emph> B. Austen. Kent M.A. 1970.</para>
<para id="p105"><emph type="i">Transport in the west Midlands from 1660 to 1840.</emph> D.W. Blundell. Birmingham M.Com. 1933.</para>
<para id="p106"><emph type="i">A geographical study of the development of roads through the Surrey-Sussex Weald to the south coast, during the period 1700&ndash;1900.</emph> G. Joan Fuller. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1950.</para>
<para id="p107"><emph type="i">The road transport system in England, 1700&ndash;1839.</emph> W.I. Albert. London Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p108"><emph type="i">The navigation of the river Great Ouse, 1700-<emph type="i">c</emph>. 1860.</emph> D.E. Summers. London M.A. (Ext.) 1969.</para>
<para id="p109"><emph type="i">The development of the road system in Glamorgan up to 1844, with special reference to turnpike roads, together with a bibliography of maps and topographical works.</emph> D.E. Fraser. Wales M.A. 1940.</para>
<para id="p110"><emph type="i">A history of the development of the means of communication in the county of Monmouth, 1760&ndash;1914.</emph> Mary A. Swallow. London Ph.D. 1932.</para>
<para id="p111"><emph type="i">The development of communications in Glamorgan, with special reference to the growth of industry, between 1760 and 1840.</emph> Enid Walker. Wales M.A. 1947.</para>
<para id="p112"><emph type="i">The development and administration of roads in Carmarthenshire, 1760&ndash;1860.</emph> A.H.T. Lewis. Wales M.A. 1968.</para>
<para id="p113"><emph type="i">The English canal system in its geographical and industrial relations.</emph> R.W.G. Bryant. London M.Sc. 1939.</para>
<para id="p114"><emph type="i">Road and railway investment in Britain, 1750&ndash;1850.</emph> J.E. Ginarlis. Sheffield Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p115"><emph type="i">The Thames Navigation Commission, 1771&ndash;1867.</emph> H.S. Davies. Reading M.A. 1967.</para>
<para id="p116"><emph type="i">A study of the origin and growth of the canal settlement at Barnton in Cheshire between 1775 and 1845.</emph> D.A. Iredale. Leicester Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p117"><emph type="i">Urban genesis and development: the case of canal-created river ports of the English Industrial Revolution.</emph> J.D. Porteous. Hull Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p118"><emph type="i">Transport in the urban development of Kentish Thames-side since the late 18th century.</emph> R.F. Baker. London M.A. 1968.</para>
</section>
<section id="s8">
<head>Agrarian History</head>
<para id="p119"><emph type="i">A geographical study of open field cultivation in Derbyshire.</emph> J.C. Jackson. Leicester M.A. 1959.</para>
<page start="130"/>
<para id="p120"><emph type="i">The development and distribution of landscape parks in the East and West Ridings of Yorkshire.</emph> B.E. Coates. Leeds M.A. 1960.</para>
<para id="p121"><emph type="i">Landscape gardens in the Chilterns.</emph> H.C. Prince. London M.A. 1954.</para>
<para id="p122"><emph type="i">Historical geography of Breckland, 1600 to 1850.</emph> M.R. Postgate. London M.A. 1961.</para>
<para id="p123"><emph type="i">An historical geography of the Sandlings of Suffolk, 1600 to 1850.</emph> Elizabeth D.R. Burrell. London M.Sc. 1960.</para>
<para id="p124"><emph type="i">The drainage of the Fens and its effects upon the parishes of the South Division of the Bedford Level, 1600&ndash;1850.</emph> Lucy M. Warren. London M.A. 1927.</para>
<para id="p125"><emph type="i">The coastal marshland of east Essex between the 17th and mid 19th centuries.</emph> D.W. Gramolt. London M.A. 1961.</para>
<para id="p126"><emph type="i">The reclamation of the middle level of the Fens.</emph> Phyllis M. Crowther. Reading Ph.D. 1929.</para>
<para id="p127"><emph type="i">The reclamation and land use of the Thames marshes of north-west Kent.</emph> Eileen E.M. Bowler. London Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p128"><emph type="i">The alluvial marshlands of the lower Thames estuary: a study in changing use patterns.</emph> B.E. Cracknell. London Ph.D. 1953.</para>
<para id="p129"><emph type="i">Geographical aspects of the reclamation and development of Hatfield Chase.</emph> B. Metcalfe. Leeds M.A. 1961.</para>
<para id="p130"><emph type="i">The Giffards of Chillingham, a Catholic landed family, 1642&ndash;1861.</emph> P.J. Doyle. Durham M.A. 1968.</para>
<para id="p131"><emph type="i">The Crosswood estate: its growth and economic development, 1683&ndash;1899.</emph> J.M. Howells. Wales M.A. 1956.</para>
<para id="p132"><emph type="i">The Camer estate, 1716&ndash;1852.</emph> Margaret Roake. Kent M.A. 1969.</para>
<para id="p133"><emph type="i">Glamorgan and the Bute estate, 1766&ndash;1947.</emph> J. Davies. Wales Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p134"><emph type="i">The Dudley estate: its rise and decline between 1774 and 1947.</emph> T.J. Raybould. Kent Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p135"><emph type="i">The Kingswinford estate of Lord Dudley: its development and organisation between 1774 and 1833.</emph> T.J. Raybould. Birmingham M.A. 1967.</para>
<para id="p136"><emph type="i">The financial affairs and estate management of the Cokes of Holkham in the 18th and 19th centuries.</emph> R.A.C. Parker. Oxford D.Phil. 1956.</para>
<para id="p137"><emph type="i">Some geographical aspects of the agriculture of Durham.</emph> A.S. Gaught. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1939.</para>
<para id="p138"><emph type="i">The agricultural geography of Norfolk, with special reference to changes in land utilisation and human occupancy.</emph> J.E.G. Mosby. London Ph.D. 1938.</para>
<para id="p139"><emph type="i">Parliamentary enclosure in Oxfordshire, 1696&ndash;1882.</emph> W.E. Tate. Oxford B.Litt. 1947.</para>
<para id="p140"><emph type="i">The progress of enclosures in the county of Dorset since 1700.</emph> G.B. Endacott. Oxford B.Litt. 1938.</para>
<para id="p141"><emph type="i">The distribution of parliamentary enclosures in the West Riding of Yorkshire, 1729&ndash;1850.</emph> W.S. Rodgers. Leeds M.Com. 1953.</para>
<para id="p142"><emph type="i">The parliamentary enclosure movement in Leicestershire, 1730&ndash;1842.</emph> H.G. Hunt. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1956.</para>
<para id="p143"><emph type="i">Some geographical aspects of the enclosure of the vale of Pickering in the 18th and 19th centuries.</emph> B. Loughbrough. Hull M.A. 1960.</para>
<para id="p144"><emph type="i">Warwickshire and the parliamentary enclosure movement.</emph> J.M. Martin. Birmingham Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<para id="p145"><emph type="i">Parliamentary enclosure in Bulmer wapentake.</emph> M. Kirk. Leeds M.A. 1948.</para>
<para id="p146"><emph type="i">The effect of parliamentary enclosure on the landscape of Caernarvonshire and Merioneth.</emph> C. Morgan. Wales M.Sc. 1959.</para>
<para id="p147"><emph type="i">The enclosure movement in Caernarvonshire, with special reference to the Porth-yr-aur papers.</emph> Gertrude A. Plume. Wales M.A. 1935.</para>
<page start="131"/>
<para id="p148"><emph type="i">Enclosure and agricultural improvement in the vale of Clwyd, 1750&ndash;1875.</emph> J.W. Edwards. London M.A. 1963.</para>
<para id="p149"><emph type="i">Parliamentary enclosures in Lindsey.</emph> T.H. Swales. Leeds M.A. 1936.</para>
<para id="p150"><emph type="i">The enclosure movement in Anglesey, 1788&ndash;1866.</emph> E.J. Jones. Wales M.A. 1924.</para>
<para id="p151"><emph type="i">Changes in the agricultural geography of the south Hertfordshire plateau, 1750&ndash;1888.</emph> Aileen M. Carpenter. London M.A. 1965.</para>
<para id="p152"><emph type="i">Changing agriculture and the moorland edge in the north York moors, 1750&ndash;1960.</emph> J. Chapman. London M.A. 1961.</para>
<para id="p153"><emph type="i">The changing land-use in the upper basin of the river Mole.</emph> M.J. Frost. London M.Sc. 1963.</para>
<para id="p154"><emph type="i">Changes in land utilisation in Uwchgwyrfai, Caernarvonshire, 1750 to 1956.</emph> P.E. Jones. Wales M.A. 1959.</para>
<para id="p155"><emph type="i">Changes in land utilisation in the upper Severn valley, Montgomeryshire, during the period 1750&ndash;1936.</emph> L.S. Andrews. Wales M.Sc. 1940.</para>
<para id="p156"><emph type="i">Changes in land utilisation in the Towy valley, Carmarthenshire, since the end of the 18th century.</emph> B.L. Davies. Wales M.A. 1938.</para>
<para id="p157"><emph type="i">The agriculture of the west midland conurbation.</emph> I. Davies. Birmingham M.A. 1955.</para>
<para id="p158"><emph type="i">The history of Hertfordshire agriculture, 1750&ndash;1860.</emph> E.J. Connell. London M.Sc. 1966.</para>
<para id="p159"><emph type="i">The agricultural history of Cheshire, 1750&ndash;1850.</emph> Clarice S. Davies. Manchester Ph.D. 1953.</para>
<para id="p160"><emph type="i">The agrarian revolution in Cambridgeshire, 1770&ndash;1850.</emph> P.H.P. Watson. London M.A. (Ext.) 1951.</para>
<para id="p161"><emph type="i">The agricultural revolution in East Anglia.</emph> Nora Walsh. Liverpool M.A. 1934.</para>
<para id="p162"><emph type="i">An historical study of the agriculture of part of south-eastern Sussex from 1780.</emph> H.B. Smith. London M.A. 1940.</para>
<para id="p163"><emph type="i">The historical geography of a part of east Sussex from 1780 (with special reference to agriculture).</emph> E.W.H. Briault. London Ph.D. 1939.</para>
<para id="p164"><emph type="i">Agricultural change in south Lincolnshire, 1790&ndash;1875.</emph> D.B. Grigg. Cambridge Ph.D. 1961.</para>
</section>
<section id="s9">
<head>Social History</head>
<para id="p165"><emph type="i">The demography of the British peerage: an analysis of the levels and trends of marriage, fertility and mortality of the peerage, dukes to barons inclusive, from the beginning of the 17th to the beginning of the 20th centuries.</emph> T.H. Hollingsworth. London Ph.D. 1963.</para>
<para id="p166"><emph type="i">Marriage patterns in the British peerage in the 18th and 19th centuries.</emph> D.N. Thomas. London M.Phil. 1969.</para>
<para id="p167"><emph type="i">The poor law of 1601, with some consideration of modern developments of the poor law problem.</emph> Gladys Boone. Birmingham M.A. 1917.</para>
<para id="p168"><emph type="i">Poor law administration in Glamorganshire before the Poor Law Amendment Act of 1834.</emph> W.E. Allin. Wales M.A. 1936.</para>
<para id="p169"><emph type="i">Administration of the old 'poor law' in the West Derby hundred of Lancashire, 1607&ndash;1837.</emph> G.W. Oxley. Liverpool M.A. 1966.</para>
<para id="p170"><emph type="i">The origins of public superannuation schemes in England, 1684&ndash;1859.</emph> M. Raphael. London Ph.D. 1957.</para>
<para id="p171"><emph type="i">The reaction of English Pembrokeshire to the social and intellectual movements of modern Wales since 1689.</emph> Elnith R. Griffiths. Wales M.A. 1927.</para>
<para id="p172"><emph type="i">Popular recreations in English society, 1700&ndash;1850.</emph> R.W. Malcolmson. Warwick Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p173"><emph type="i">The treatment of poverty in Norfolk, from 1700 to 1850.</emph> Mrs. Muriel F. Lloyd Prichard. Cambridge Ph.D. 1949.</para>
<page start="132"/>
<para id="p174"><emph type="i">The development of the great affiliated Friendly societies from their humble and often obscure origins in the 18th century.</emph> W.T. Bushrod. Manchester M.A. 1924.</para>
<para id="p175"><emph type="i">West of England Friendly societies of the 18th and 19th centuries, with particular reference to their insignia.</emph> Margaret D. Fuller. Reading M.A. 1957/8.</para>
<para id="p176"><emph type="i">The economic and social development of the Jews in England, 1730&ndash;1860.</emph> J. Rumney. London Ph.D. 1933.</para>
<para id="p177"><emph type="i">Lunacy legislation and administration in England, 1744&ndash;1845.</emph> Kathleen Jones. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1953.</para>
<para id="p178"><emph type="i">Poor law administration in selected London parishes between 1750 and 1850.</emph> Ann J. Froshaug. Nottingham M.A. 1969.</para>
<para id="p179"><emph type="i">Poor law administration in Glamorgan, 1750&ndash;1850.</emph> K.E. Skinner. Wales M.A. 1956.</para>
<para id="p180"><emph type="i">Poverty and its treatment in Cardiganshire, 1750&ndash;1850.</emph> A.M.E. Davies. Wales M.A. 1968.</para>
<para id="p181"><emph type="i">The history of the Honourable Society of Cymmrodorion.</emph> Helen M. Jones. Wales M.A. 1939.</para>
<para id="p182"><emph type="i">Some aspects of the history of the Society of Arts, London, 1754&ndash;1952.</emph> K.W. Luckhurst. London Ph.D. 1957.</para>
<para id="p183"><emph type="i">Medical education and the rise of the general practitioner, 1760&ndash;1860.</emph> Mrs. Rachel E. Waterhouse. Birmingham Ph.D. 1950.</para>
<para id="p184"><emph type="i">Public health and hospital administration in Swansea and west Glamorgan from the end of the 18th century to 1914.</emph> G.D. Fielder. Wales M.A. 1962.</para>
</section>
</section>
<section id="s10">
<head>ECCLESIASTICAL HISTORY</head>
<para id="p185"><emph type="i">The changes and development within Presbyterianism in the counties of Derby, Leicester and Nottingham from its organisation in the Commonwealth to the transformation to Independency and Unitarianism <emph type="i">c</emph>.1780.</emph> C.G. Bolam. Nottingham M.A. 1957.</para>
<para id="p186"><emph type="i">Nonconformity in Exeter, 1650&ndash;1875.</emph> A.A. Brockett. Exeter M.A. 1960.</para>
<para id="p187"><emph type="i">The Quakers in Leicestershire, 1648&ndash;1780.</emph> E.K.L. Quine. Nottingham Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p188"><emph type="i">Bristol Quakerism.</emph> R.S. Mortimer. Bristol M.A. 1946.</para>
<para id="p189"><emph type="i">The Society of Friends in Glamorgan, 1654&ndash;1900.</emph> Margaret F. Williams. Wales M.A. 1950.</para>
<para id="p190"><emph type="i">The history of the Society of Friends in Plymouth and west Devon from 1654 to the early 19th century.</emph> A.D. Selleck. London M.A. (Ext.) 1959.</para>
<para id="p191"><emph type="i">The consistory courts of the diocese of St. Davids, 1660&ndash;1858: studies of the records of the courts illustrative of their work and practice.</emph> W.T. Morgan. Wales M.A. 1962.</para>
<para id="p192"><emph type="i">Protestant Nonconformity in the Black Country, 1662&ndash;1851.</emph> A.G. Cumberland. Birmingham M.A. 1951.</para>
<para id="p193"><emph type="i">Nonconformity in Shropshire, 1662&ndash;1815: a study in the rise and progress of Baptist, Congregational, Presbyterian, Quaker and Methodist societies.</emph> R.F. Skinner. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1967.</para>
<para id="p194"><emph type="i">The Arian movement in England.</emph> J.H. Colligan. Manchester M.A. 1911.</para>
<para id="p195"><emph type="i">Dissent and democracy.</emph> F.M. Scully. Bristol M.A. 1937.</para>
<para id="p196"><emph type="i">The renewed church of the United Brethren, 1722&ndash;1930.</emph> W.G.C. Addison. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1931.</para>
<para id="p197"><emph type="i">The rise and growth of Welsh Wesleyan Methodism to 1858.</emph> A.H. Williams. Wales M.A. 1932.</para>
<para id="p198"><emph type="i">The Evangelicals in Oxford, 1735&ndash;1871.</emph> J.S. Reynolds. Oxford B.Litt. 1950.</para>
<para id="p199"><emph type="i">The history of Unitarianism in Birmingham from the middle of the 18th century to 1893.</emph> Emily Bushrod. Birmingham M.A. 1954.</para>
<page start="133"/>
<para id="p200"><emph type="i">The development of the Anglican and Roman Catholic clergy as a profession since the middle of the 18th century.</emph> M.J. Woolgar. Leicester Ph.D. 1960.</para>
<para id="p201"><emph type="i">The Baptists of north-west England, 1750&ndash;1850.</emph> G.A. Weston. Sheffield Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p202"><emph type="i">The history of Congregationalism in Derbyshire from the Methodist revival to 1850.</emph> R. Mansfield. Manchester Ph.D. 1958.</para>
<para id="p203"><emph type="i">The economic and social history of the principal protestant denominations in Leeds, 1760&ndash;1844.</emph> C.M. Elliott. Oxford D.Phil. 1962.</para>
<para id="p204"><emph type="i">The parish clergy of rural Oxfordshire from the institution of Bishop John Butler (1777) to the translation of Bishop Samuel Wilberforce (1869) with particular reference to their non-ecclesiastical activities.</emph> Mrs. Diana McClatchey. Oxford D.Phil. 1949.</para>
<para id="p205"><emph type="i">A study of the Church of England in the diocese of Bath and Wells, 1790&ndash;1840.</emph> W.St.J. Kemm. Birmingham M.A. 1965.</para>
<para id="p206"><emph type="i">The old dissenting meeting-house: its structure, furniture and services.</emph> G.R. Jones. Manchester M.A. 1919.</para>
<para id="p207"><emph type="i">The Methodist class meeting: a historical study.</emph> P.D. Mackenzie. St. Andrews M.Th. 1970.</para>
<para id="p208"><emph type="i">The architectural expression of Methodism in England in the 18th and 19th centuries.</emph> G.W. Dolbey. Manchester M.A. 1962.</para>
<para id="p209"><emph type="i">Nonconformity in Liverpool, 1786&ndash;1914.</emph> I. Sellers. Keele Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p210"><emph type="i">The divisions and reunion of British Methodism, 1791&ndash;1932, with special reference to social and organisational factors.</emph> R. Currie. Oxford D.Phil. 1966.</para>
<para id="p211"><emph type="i">The development of Wesleyan Methodist principles and ideas, 1791&ndash;1914.</emph> I.D. Cleland. Nottingham M.Phil. 1970.</para>
<para id="p212"><emph type="i">Church and ministry in Wesleyan Methodism from the death of John Wesley to the death of Jabez Bunting (1791&ndash;1858).</emph> J.C. Bowmer. Leeds Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p213"><emph type="i">Methodism from the death of Wesley, 1791, to the Wesleyan centenary, 1839.</emph> R.P. Wearmouth. Birmingham M.A. 1928.</para>
<para id="p214"><emph type="i">Methodism and Anglicanism, 1791&ndash;1850.</emph> J.M. Turner. Bristol M.A. 1956.</para>
</section>
<section id="s11">
<head>CULTURAL HISTORY</head>
<para id="p215"><emph type="i">The history of science teaching in England.</emph> Dorothy M. Turner. London Ph.D. 1928.</para>
<para id="p216"><emph type="i">A history of the teaching of physics in England from 1650 to 1850.</emph> G.D. Bishop. London Ph.D. 1959.</para>
<para id="p217"><emph type="i">The study and teaching of history in English education from the 17th century to the death of Thomas Arnold.</emph> R.A. Lewin. London M.A. 1955.</para>
<para id="p218"><emph type="i">School and community in Okehampton, 1600 to 1903.</emph> R.L. Taverner. Wales M.A. 1963.</para>
<para id="p219"><emph type="i">The Jewish schooling systems of London, 1656&ndash;1956.</emph> P.L.S. Quinn. London Ph.D. 1958.</para>
<para id="p220"><emph type="i">Witney grammar school, 1660&ndash;1960.</emph> Mary A. Fleming. Reading M.A. 1959/60.</para>
<para id="p221"><emph type="i">A history of Hipperholme School from 1660 to 1914, with a biography of its founder Matthew Brodley (1586&ndash;1648).</emph> P. Facer. London M.A. 1966.</para>
<para id="p222"><emph type="i">The work of religious societies in English education, 1660&ndash;1870.</emph> F.M. Osborne. London M.A. 1925.</para>
<para id="p223"><emph type="i">Nonconformist academies in Wales, 1662&ndash;1862.</emph> H.P. Roberts. Liverpool M.A. 1922.</para>
<para id="p224"><emph type="i">The activities of Catholics in the matter of education in England.</emph> A.P. Braddock. London M.A. 1917.</para>
<page start="134"/>
<para id="p225"><emph type="i">Roman Catholic education from 1700 to 1870: a study of Roman Catholic educational endeavour from the early 18th century to the Elementary Education Act of 1870.</emph> J. Kitching. Leeds Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p226"><emph type="i">The history of Brigg grammar school.</emph> F. Henthorn. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1961.</para>
<para id="p227"><emph type="i">Elementary education in the Forest of Dean between the years 1698 and 1870.</emph> D.R.A. Williams. Bristol M.A. 1962.</para>
<para id="p228"><emph type="i">The development of elementary education in Gloucestershire, 1698&ndash;1846.</emph> G.H. Hainton. Bristol M.A. 1952.</para>
<para id="p229"><emph type="i">The rise and progress of the periodical press in Wales up to 1860.</emph> Catherine Evans. Wales M.A. 1926.</para>
<para id="p230"><emph type="i">A history of the South Wales newspapers to 1855.</emph> R.D. Rees. Reading M.A. 1955.</para>
<para id="p231"><emph type="i">Chapters in the history of the provincial newspaper press, 1700&ndash;1855.</emph> D.F. Gallop. Reading M.A. 1952.</para>
<para id="p232"><emph type="i">The Derbyshire newspaper press, 1720&ndash;1855.</emph> J.D. Andrew. Reading M.A. 1954.</para>
<para id="p233"><emph type="i">The early newspaper press in Berkshire (1723&ndash;1855).</emph> K.G. Burton. Reading M.A. 1950.</para>
<para id="p234"><emph type="i">The Oliver Whitby School, Chichester: a study of the repercussions of contemporary trends, social and educational, in the fortunes of the school, 1702&ndash;1904.</emph> G.L. Barnard. London Ph.D. 1961.</para>
<para id="p235"><emph type="i">The development of chemistry in Britain through medicine and pharmacy from 1700 to 1850.</emph> J.K. Crellin. London Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p236"><emph type="i">The educational aims of pioneers in elementary Welsh education, 1730&ndash;1870.</emph> F. Williams. Wales M.A. 1929.</para>
<para id="p237"><emph type="i">Wesleyan Methodism's contribution to national education (1739&ndash;1902).</emph> H. Cloke. London M.A. 1936.</para>
<para id="p238"><emph type="i">A short history and a statistical survey of charity school education.</emph> R.W. Hitchcock. London M.A. 1933.</para>
<para id="p239"><emph type="i">A history of charity school education and a statistical survey of some measures of educational growth.</emph> R.W. Hitchcock. London Ph.D. 1938.</para>
<para id="p240"><emph type="i">Science education in Ireland and Scotland, 1750&ndash;1900.</emph> B.B. Kelham. Manchester Ph.D. 1968.</para>
<para id="p241"><emph type="i">Elementary education provided by the governors of the Free Grammar School of King Edward VI in Birmingham, 1751&ndash;1883.</emph> J.C. Tyson. Birmingham M.A. 1960.</para>
<para id="p242"><emph type="i">Education and the handicapped, 1760&ndash;1960.</emph> D.G. Pritchard. Liverpool Ph.D. 1963/4.</para>
<para id="p243"><emph type="i">Congregationalism and the education of the people, 1760&ndash;1914: the quest for freedom.</emph> A. McLellan. Birmingham M.A. 1963.</para>
<para id="p244"><emph type="i">A comparative study of the Sunday School movement in England and Wales.</emph> Dorothi M. Griffith. Wales M.A. 1923.</para>
<para id="p245"><emph type="i">The origin and development of the Sunday School movement in England from 1780 to 1880, in relation to the state provision of education.</emph> J.K. Meir. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1954.</para>
<para id="p246"><emph type="i">The history and development of the Sunday School in England.</emph> W.A. Christie. Liverpool M.A. 1937.</para>
<para id="p247"><emph type="i">A history of education in York, 1780&ndash;1902.</emph> E. Benson. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1933.</para>
<para id="p248"><emph type="i">Press and people, 1790&ndash;1850: opinion in three English cities.</emph> D. Read. Sheffield Ph.D. 1961.</para>
<para id="p249"><emph type="i">The educational activities of Baptists in England during the 18th and 19th centuries, with particular reference to the north-west.</emph> J.E. Watson. Liverpool M.A. 1947.</para>
<para id="p250"><emph type="i">The development of education in Hitchin, Hertfordshire, 1780&ndash;1880.</emph> K.R.J. Aitken. Nottingham M.A. 1960.</para>
<para id="p251"><emph type="i">The basic education of labour in Lancashire, 1780&ndash;1839.</emph> J.M. Sanderson. Cambridge Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p252"><emph type="i">The development of education in Accrington, 1790&ndash;1903.</emph> E. Stones. Sheffield M.A. 1957.</para>
<page start="135"/>
<para id="p253"><emph type="i">Demands for the education of girls between 1790 and 1865.</emph> Shirley C. Gordon. London M.A. 1950.</para>
<para id="p254"><emph type="i">The dame schools in Great Britain.</emph> J.H. Higginson. Leeds M.A. 1939.</para>
</section>
<section id="s12">
<head>LOCAL HISTORY</head>
<para id="p255"><emph type="i">The social and economic history of the East Fen village of Wrangle, 1603&ndash;1837.</emph> F. West. Leicester Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p256"><emph type="i">The corporation and community of Okehampton, 1623&ndash;1885.</emph> R.L. Taverner. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1969.</para>
<para id="p257"><emph type="i">A study of parish government, 1660&ndash;1894, illustrated by documents from the parish chest of Eye, Northants.</emph> R.A. Shannon. London M.A. (Ext.) 1949.</para>
<para id="p258"><emph type="i">An administrative history of the borough of Newport, in the county of Monmouth, 1623&ndash;1850.</emph> B.P. Jones. Wales M.A. 1955.</para>
<para id="p259"><emph type="i">The history of Bury, Lancashire, from 1660 to 1876.</emph> Margaret Gray. Oxford B.Litt. 1963.</para>
<para id="p260"><emph type="i">The parish of Ecclesfield in an era of change, 1672&ndash;1851.</emph> D.G. Hey. Leicester M.A. 1967.</para>
<para id="p261"><emph type="i">Local government in the borough of Neath: a study in urban administration, 1694&ndash;1884.</emph> R.D. Till. Wales M.A. 1970.</para>
<para id="p262"><emph type="i">The economic and social history of the Furness area from 1711 to 1875.</emph> J.D. Marshall. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1956.</para>
<para id="p263"><emph type="i">A study in demography based on the ancient Lancashire parish of Warton.</emph> R. Speake. Lancaster M.Litt. 1968.</para>
<para id="p264"><emph type="i">The urban geography of Leicester.</emph> Jennifer Pugh. Leicester M.A. 1965.</para>
<para id="p265"><emph type="i">A study of some of the social and economic changes in the town and parish of Amlwch, 1750&ndash;1850.</emph> J. Rowlands. Wales M.A. 1960.</para>
<para id="p266"><emph type="i">Social and economic development of Styal, 1750&ndash;1850.</emph> W.C. Lazenby. Manchester M.A. 1949.</para>
<para id="p267"><emph type="i">The government and growth of the parish of Halifax, 1760&ndash;1848.</emph> J.W. Houseman. Liverpool M.A. 1928.</para>
<para id="p268"><emph type="i">Aspects of the economic and social geography of the Mansfield area.</emph> C.M. Law. Nottingham M.Sc. 1961.</para>
<para id="p269"><emph type="i">A comparative study of the urban development of York and Lincoln.</emph> Patricia A. Grimshaw. Nottingham M.A. 1960.</para>
<para id="p270"><emph type="i">The north-eastern expansion of London since 1770.</emph> H. Rees. London M.Sc. 1946.</para>
<para id="p271"><emph type="i">Contribution towards the study of the economic development of Bristol in the 18th and 19th centuries.</emph> A.J. Pugsley. Bristol M.A. 1921.</para>
<para id="p272"><emph type="i">The economic and social development of Gainsborough, with special reference to the 18th and 19th centuries.</emph> T.H. Chafer. Sheffield M.A. 1956.</para>
</section>
<section id="s13">
<head>SCOTLAND</head>
<para id="p273"><emph type="i">Servitudes in the law of Scotland: principles, sources and influences which have affected the law.</emph> T.A. Ross. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1931/2.</para>
<para id="p274"><emph type="i">The Scottish woollen industry, 1603&ndash;1914.</emph> C. Gulvin. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p275"><emph type="i">The rise, progress and decline of the Quaker movement in Scotland.</emph> G.B. Burnet. Glasgow Ph.D. 1936.</para>
<para id="p276"><emph type="i">The history of the Episcopal Church in the diocese of Brechin, 1688&ndash;1875.</emph> W. Christie. Dundee Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p277"><emph type="i">Sunday observance in Scotland, 1689&ndash;1900.</emph> R.D. Brackenridge. Glasgow Ph.D. 1962.</para>
<para id="p278"><emph type="i">The distribution and structure of the population of north-east Scotland, 1696&ndash;1931.</emph> K. Walton. Aberdeen Ph.D. 1951.</para>
<page start="136"/>
<para id="p279"><emph type="i">Settlement in Trotternish, Isle of Skye, 1700&ndash;1958.</emph> M.D. MacSween. Glasgow B.Litt. 1962.</para>
<para id="p280"><emph type="i">Settlement changes in the south-west Highlands of Scotland, 1700&ndash;1960.</emph> R.A. Gailey. Glasgow Ph.D. 1961.</para>
<para id="p281"><emph type="i">The industrial archaeology of Galloway: the regional economy of south-west Scotland, 1700&ndash;1900.</emph> I.L. Donnachie. Strathclyde M.Litt. 1969.</para>
<para id="p282"><emph type="i">Division of commonty in Scotland: the use of 18th- and 19th-century estate plans held by the Scottish Record Office in a study of historical geography.</emph> I.H. Adams. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p283"><emph type="i">The paper industry in Scotland, 1700&ndash;1861.</emph> A.G. Thomson. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<para id="p284"><emph type="i">Scottish bleachfields, 1718&ndash;1862.</emph> Mrs. Enid M. Gauldie. St. Andrews B.Phil. 1967.</para>
<para id="p285"><emph type="i">The operation of the poor law in the north-east of Scotland, 1745&ndash;1845.</emph> Jean Lindsay. Aberdeen Ph.D. 1962.</para>
<para id="p286"><emph type="i">The migration of Highlanders into lowland Scotland, <emph type="i">c</emph>. 1750&ndash;1890, with particular reference to Greenock.</emph> R.D. Lobban. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p287"><emph type="i">The geography of crofting in Scotland.</emph> J.R. Coull. Aberdeen Ph.D. 1962.</para>
<para id="p288"><emph type="i">The crofting areas of Sutherland since 1756.</emph> P.T. Wheeler. London Ph.D. 1961.</para>
<para id="p289"><emph type="i">Locational factors in the development of the Scottish iron and steel industry, 1760&ndash;1970.</emph> W.D. Campbell. Edinburgh M.Sc. 1969/70.</para>
<para id="p290"><emph type="i">The history of deaf education in Scotland from 1760 to 1939.</emph> T.J. Watson. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1949.</para>
<para id="p291"><emph type="i">Population movements in Scotland, 1770&ndash;1850.</emph> D.F. Macdonald. Oxford D.Phil. 1932/3.</para>
<para id="p292"><emph type="i">Monymusk, 1770&ndash;1850: a study of the economic development of a Scottish estate.</emph> T.P. Soper. Aberdeen Ph.D. 1954.</para>
<para id="p293"><emph type="i">The Dumbarton Glass Work Company, <emph type="i">c</emph>.1777&ndash;<emph type="i">c</emph>.1850.</emph> J.C. Logan. Strathclyde M.Litt. 1970.</para>
<para id="p294"><emph type="i">Some geographical aspects of the Blair Atholl papers.</emph> Thelma Blance. Aberdeen Ph.D. 1956.</para>
<para id="p295"><emph type="i">Scottish experiments in rural education from the 18th century to the present day, with special reference to rural arts and crafts.</emph> J. Mason. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1930/1.</para>
<para id="p296"><emph type="i">The history of roads in the Highlands of Scotland in the 18th and 19th centuries contrasting the military roads (i.e. those of Wade and Caulfield) with the parliamentary roads (i.e. those constructed by Telford).</emph> J.S. Stephen. Aberdeen Ph.D. 1936.</para>
<para id="p297"><emph type="i">The Baptists in Scotland: an historical survey.</emph> J. Scott. Glasgow Ph.D. 1927.</para>
<para id="p298"><emph type="i">Electoral law and procedure in the 18th and 19th century in Scotland.</emph> W. Ferguson. Glasgow Ph.D. 1957.</para>
</section>
<section id="s14">
<head>IRELAND</head>
<para id="p299"><emph type="i">Aspects of the population geography of Co. Cork.</emph> T. Burke. Birmingham Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p300"><emph type="i">The collieries of east Tyrone from the mid 17th century to the present day.</emph> W.A. McCutcheon. Belfast M.A. 1958.</para>
<para id="p301"><emph type="i">A survey of turf working in Co. Down.</emph> L.T. Brown. Belfast M.Sc. 1968.</para>
<para id="p302"><emph type="i">Scottish ecclesiastical influence upon Irish Presbyterianism from the non-subscription controversy to the union of the synods.</emph> R. Allen. Belfast M.A. 1940.</para>
<para id="p303"><emph type="i">The population of Ireland from 1750 to 1846, and the social and economic factors associated with its increase.</emph> K.H. Connell. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1948.</para>
<para id="p304"><emph type="i">The Evangelicals in the Church of Ireland, 1784&ndash;1859.</emph> A.R. Acheson. Belfast Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<page start="137"/>
<para id="p305"><emph type="i">The development and distribution of Methodism in Ireland: a demographic study.</emph> J.H. Cooke. Belfast M.A. 1964.</para>
<para id="p306"><emph type="i">A history of Methodism in Ireland from Wesley's death in 1791 to the reunion of Primitives and Wesleyans in 1878.</emph> June R. Binns. Belfast M.A. 1960.</para>
<para id="p307"><emph type="i">A critical survey of the development of secondary education in Ireland, 1791&ndash;1880, with special reference to schools in Ulster.</emph> G. Stevenson. Belfast M.A. 1957.</para>
<para id="p308"><emph type="i">The history of iron shipbuilding in the Queen's Island up till July 1874.</emph> D. Rebbeck. Belfast Ph.D. 1950.</para>
<para id="p309"><emph type="i">A history of inland transport in Ireland down to the period of the railways.</emph> P. O'Kelly. London M.Sc. 1922.</para>
<para id="p310"><emph type="i">The development and subsequent decline of the chief inland waterways and standard gauge railways of the north of Ireland.</emph> W.A. McCutcheon. Belfast Ph.D. 1962.</para>
</section>
</section>
</report>
