<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="154860" pubid="1512" publish="true">
<title>Britain: Long Periods from the 15th-Century</title>
<subtitle></subtitle>
<section id="s1">
<head>BRITAIN: LONG PERIODS
FROM THE 15TH CENTURY</head>
<section id="s2">
<head>POLITICAL HISTORY</head>
<para id="p1"><emph type="i">The history and place of public policy in English private law.</emph> C.L. Emrich. Oxford D.Phil. 1938.</para>
<para id="p2"><emph type="i">The history of <emph type="i">mens rea</emph> in the law of homicide.</emph> A.W.G. Kean. Cambridge M.Litt. 1938/9.</para>
<page start="095"/>
<para id="p3"><emph type="i">Researches in the history of the rights of the subject in England.</emph> L.E.D. Horanszky de Hora. Aberdeen Ph.D. 1927.</para>
<para id="p4"><emph type="i">Punishment as applied by the ordinary criminal courts from 1400 to 1747.</emph> R.A. MacTaggart. Glasgow Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p5"><emph type="i">The history and development of the charitable trust from the 15th century onwards.</emph> G.H. Jones. London Ph.D. 1961.</para>
<para id="p6"><emph type="i">The historical background of the English land law from 1535.</emph> S.H. Brookfield. Liverpool M.A. 1935.</para>
<para id="p7"><emph type="i">A history of English assizes from 1558 to 1714.</emph> J.S. Cockburn. Leeds Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p8"><emph type="i">The action on the case: the development of the action as reflected on the plea rolls of the 16th and 17th centuries.</emph> A.K. Kiralfy. London Ph.D. 1949.</para>
<para id="p9"><emph type="i">The parliamentary representation of Grampound.</emph> R.C.D. Jasper. Leeds M.A. 1940.</para>
<para id="p10"><emph type="i">The parliamentary representation of Glamorgan, 1536&ndash;1832.</emph> L.B. John. Wales M.A. 1934.</para>
<para id="p11"><emph type="i">The parliamentary representation of Pembrokeshire, the Pembroke boroughs and Haverfordwest, 1536&ndash;1761.</emph> Mary E. Jones. Wales M.A. 1958.</para>
<para id="p12"><emph type="i">The parliamentary representation of Radnorshire, 1536&ndash;1832.</emph> D.R.L. Adams. Wales M.A. 1970.</para>
<para id="p13"><emph type="i">The parliamentary representation of Monmouthshire and the Monmouth boroughs, 1536&ndash;1832.</emph> Ethel E. Havill. Wales M.A. 1949.</para>
<para id="p14"><emph type="i">The boroughs of North Wales: their parliamentary history from the Act of Union to the First Reform Act, 1536&ndash;1832.</emph> G. Roberts. Wales M.A. 1928/9.</para>
<para id="p15"><emph type="i">The evolution of radical theory after the Reformation.</emph> A.J. Clark. London M.A. 1910.</para>
<para id="p16"><emph type="i">Political journalism, 1572&ndash;1714.</emph> R. Britton. Kent Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p17"><emph type="i">The history of the Petitions of Right from the 17th century.</emph> M.F. Spungin. Oxford B.Litt. 1959.</para>
<para id="p18"><emph type="i">The origins of the Petition of Right.</emph> L. Ehrlich. Oxford B.Litt. 1915.</para>
</section>
<section id="s3">
<head>ECONOMIC AND SOCIAL HISTORY</head>
<para id="p19"><emph type="i">The changing landscape of rural Middlesex, 1500&ndash;1850.</emph> G.B.G. Bull. London Ph.D. 1958.</para>
<para id="p20"><emph type="i">Changing agricultural landscapes in Cumberland.</emph> G.G. Elliott. Liverpool M.A. 1956.</para>
<para id="p21"><emph type="i">Rural Cambridgeshire, 1520&ndash;1680.</emph> Mrs. H. Margaret Spufford. Leicester M.A. 1962.</para>
<para id="p22"><emph type="i">Pauperism and vagrancy in Cambridgeshire to 1834.</emph> Ethel M. Hampson. Cambridge Ph.D. 1930/1.</para>
<para id="p23"><emph type="i">Some aspects of the historical geography of central Surrey: a study in economic change.</emph> G.J. Ashworth. Reading M.Phil. 1967/8.</para>
<para id="p24"><emph type="i">Settlement and agriculture in North Wales, 1536&ndash;1670.</emph> B.M. Evans. Cambridge Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p25"><emph type="i">The Petre lands in the Wid basin and adjacent areas from 1539 to 1939.</emph> Joyce G. Minton. London Ph.D. 1959.</para>
<para id="p26"><emph type="i">A contribution to the historical geography of Needwood Forest, Staffordshire, from Elizabeth I to enclosure in the early 19th century.</emph> P.H. Nicholls. London M.A. 1965.</para>
<para id="p27"><emph type="i">West Cleveland land use, <emph type="i">c</emph>.1550&ndash;1850.</emph> P.K. Mitchell. Durham Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<para id="p28"><emph type="i">The economy of the Northamptonshire royal forests, 1558&ndash;1714.</emph> P.A.J. Pettit. Oxford D.Phil. 1959.</para>
<para id="p29"><emph type="i">Pre-inclosure agricultural systems in the East Riding of Yorkshire.</emph> A. Harris. London M.A. (Ext.) 1951.</para>
<para id="p30"><emph type="i">Enclosure and the agricultural landscape of Lindsey from the 16th to the 19th century.</emph> S.A. Johnson. Liverpool M.A. 1957.</para>
<page start="096"/>
<para id="p31"><emph type="i">Lincolnshire glebe terriers of the deaneries of Calcewaith and Hill, 1577&ndash;1706.</emph> Olga Beaumont. Reading M.A. 1952.</para>
<para id="p32"><emph type="i">The rural economy of Oxfordshire, 1580&ndash;1730.</emph> M.A. Havinden. Oxford B.Litt. 1961.</para>
<para id="p33"><emph type="i">Economic changes in the manor of Cranborne (Dorset) in the 16th and 17th centuries.</emph> Elizabeth B. Clarke. Oxford B.Litt. 1939.</para>
<para id="p34"><emph type="i">Open field, enclosure and farm production in east Worcestershire.</emph> J.A. Yelling. Birmingham Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p35"><emph type="i">The south-western peninsulas of England and Wales: studies in agricultural geography, 1550&ndash;1900.</emph> T.R.B. Dicks. Wales Ph.D. 1964.</para>
<para id="p36"><emph type="i">Development of the port of Harwich.</emph> Mrs. Frances N. Mellen. London M.A. 1965.</para>
<para id="p37"><emph type="i">The contribution of Wales to the British empire in the 16th and 17th centuries.</emph> W.A. Bebb. Wales M.A. 1920.</para>
<para id="p38"><emph type="i">The historical geography of the paper-making industry in England.</emph> A.H. Shorter. London Ph.D. 1954.</para>
<para id="p39"><emph type="i">The history of the Yorkshire woollen and worsted industries from the earliest times up to the Industrial Revolution.</emph> H. Heaton. Birmingham M.Com. 1914.</para>
<para id="p40"><emph type="i">The historical geography of the Norfolk and Suffolk woollen industry.</emph> J.S. Bishop. London M.A. 1929.</para>
<para id="p41"><emph type="i">The wool supply and the worsted cloth industry in Norfolk in the 16th and 17th centuries.</emph> K.J. Allison. Leeds Ph.D. 1956.</para>
<para id="p42"><emph type="i">Aspects of the development of the Gloucestershire woollen industry.</emph> Mrs. Jennifer Tann. Leicester Ph.D. 1964.</para>
<para id="p43"><emph type="i">Woollen trade and industry in the rural areas of Gloucestershire.</emph> F.C. Raggatt. Bristol M.A. 1933.</para>
<para id="p44"><emph type="i">The internal wool trade in England during the 16th and 17th centuries: a study in economic history.</emph> P.J. Bowden. Leeds Ph.D. 1952.</para>
<para id="p45"><emph type="i">The history of English coal mining, 1500&ndash;1750.</emph> Asta W.R. Moller. Oxford D.Phil. 1932/3.</para>
<para id="p46"><emph type="i">The Willoughbys of Wollaton, 1500&ndash;1643, with special reference to early mining in Nottinghamshire.</emph> R.S. Smith. Nottingham Ph.D. 1964.</para>
<para id="p47"><emph type="i">The economic and social development of the Leicestershire and south Derbyshire coalfield, 1550&ndash;1914.</emph> C.P. Griffin. Nottingham Ph.D. 1969.</para>
<para id="p48"><emph type="i">The development of the coal industry in the Radstock area of Somerset from earliest times to 1830.</emph> J.A. Bulley. London M.A. (Ext.) 1952.</para>
<para id="p49"><emph type="i">The geography of the south-west Lancashire mining industry, 1590&ndash;1799.</emph> J. Langton. Wales Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p50"><emph type="i">Studies in the history of mining and metallurgy to the middle of the 17th century considered in relation to the progress of scientific knowledge and with some reference to mining in Cornwall.</emph> P.C. Davey. London Ph.D. 1954.</para>
<para id="p51"><emph type="i">Changes of population in west Cornwall with the rise and decline of mining.</emph> T.W. McGuinness. London M.Sc. 1938.</para>
<para id="p52"><emph type="i">The lead-mining industry of Swaledale.</emph> B. Jennings. Leeds M.A. 1959.</para>
<para id="p53"><emph type="i">The lead industry in Cardiganshire.</emph> L. Jones. Wales M.A. 1915.</para>
<para id="p54"><emph type="i">The lead and silver mining industry in Wales, 1558&ndash;1765.</emph> L. Jones. Oxford B.Litt. 1923.</para>
<para id="p55"><emph type="i">Birmingham: an analysis of geographical influences on the metal industries.</emph> Jean Rushton. London M.Sc. 1936.</para>
<para id="p56"><emph type="i">The history of the Midland glass industry, with special reference to the flint glass section.</emph> D.N. Sandilands. Birmingham M.Com. 1927.</para>
<para id="p57"><emph type="i">The economic history of the modern English glass industry.</emph> J.N. Reedman. Sheffield Ph.D. 1930.</para>
<para id="p58"><emph type="i">History of the alum trade.</emph> J. Rudsdale. Leeds M.A. 1932.</para>
<page start="097"/>
<para id="p59"><emph type="i">The Walsall and Midlands leather trades: a study in their history and organisation from the earliest times to the present day.</emph> E. Tonkinson. Birmingham M.Com. 1948.</para>
<para id="p60"><emph type="i">The English leather industry in the 16th and 17th centuries, 1563&ndash;1700.</emph> L.A. Clarkson. Nottingham Ph.D. 1960.</para>
<para id="p61"><emph type="i">English leather glove trade.</emph> Muriel K. Fudge. Bristol M.A. 1930.</para>
<para id="p62"><emph type="i">The location of footwear manufacture in England and Wales.</emph> P.R. Mounfield. Nottingham Ph.D. 1962.</para>
</section>
<section id="s4">
<head>ECCLESIASTICAL HISTORY</head>
<para id="p63"><emph type="i">An historical and anthropological study of magic and religion amongst the gypsies of Britain.</emph> E.B. Trigg. Oxford D.Phil. 1968.</para>
<para id="p64"><emph type="i">A history of the attempts towards reunion between the Anglican and the Eastern-Orthodox churches, especially since the 16th century.</emph> W.W. Price. Birmingham M.A. 1929.</para>
<para id="p65"><emph type="i">Religious societies (<emph type="i">ecclesiolae in ecclesia</emph>) from 1500 to 1800, excluding those of the church of Rome.</emph> F.W.B. Bullock. Cambridge Ph.D. 1937/8.</para>
<para id="p66"><emph type="i">A history and source book on training for the ministry in the Church of England, 1511&ndash;1717.</emph> F. Bussby. Durham M.Litt. 1952.</para>
<para id="p67"><emph type="i">The controversy between Roman Catholics and Anglicans from Elizabeth to the Revolution.</emph> G. Windsor. Cambridge Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p68"><emph type="i">(1) The archdeacon's court: liber actorum; (2) episcopal visitation book for the archdeaconry of Buckingham, 1662; (3) the study and use of archdeacon's court records, illustrated from the Oxford records, 1566&ndash;1759.</emph> E.R.C. Brinkworth. Birmingham M.A. 1951.</para>
<para id="p69"><emph type="i">Puritan devotion, 1570&ndash;1700, and its place in the development of Christian piety.</emph> G.S. Wakefield. Oxford B.Litt. 1954.</para>
<para id="p70"><emph type="i">The worship of the English Puritans during the 16th, 17th and early 18th centuries.</emph> D.H.M. Davies. Oxford D.Phil. 1943.</para>
<para id="p71"><emph type="i">The indissolubility of marriage in Reformation and post-Reformation Anglican teaching and practice.</emph> A.R. Winnett. London Ph.D. 1953.</para>
<para id="p72"><emph type="i">The history of marriage and divorce in England since the Reformation.</emph> D.T.I. Jenkins. Birmingham M.A. 1963/4.</para>
<para id="p73"><emph type="i">The organisation and development of cathedral worship in England since the Reformation.</emph> P.C. Moore. Oxford D.Phil. 1954.</para>
<para id="p74"><emph type="i">Lay-preaching in England from the Reformation to the rise of Methodism: a study in its development, nature and significance.</emph> J.H. Blackmore. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1951/2.</para>
<para id="p75"><emph type="i">A study of the causes, administration and results of Lancashire church briefs, and studies of collections for Lancashire and non-Lancashire briefs, with reference to collections elsewhere in England.</emph> Joan Beck. London M.A. (Ext.) 1954.</para>
<para id="p76"><emph type="i">The history of the doctrine of the Priesthood of All Believers.</emph> J.R. Crawford. Aberdeen Ph.D. 1958.</para>
<para id="p77"><emph type="i">An investigation of the doctrine of the Priesthood of All Believers from the Reformation to the present day.</emph> C.C. Eastwood. London Ph.D. 1957.</para>
<para id="p78"><emph type="i">The inter-relation of civil and ecclesiastical authority in dealing with trials of bishops, 1558&ndash;1725.</emph> R.E. Head. Oxford B.Litt. 1959.</para>
<para id="p79"><emph type="i">Llenyddiaeth Gatholig y Cymry (1559&ndash;1829) rhyddiaith a barddoniaeth. (Catholic literature of the Welsh (1559&ndash;1829), prose and poetry.)</emph> G. Bowen. Liverpool M.A. 1952/3.</para>
<page start="098"/>
<para id="p80"><emph type="i">The parish registers of the churches of SS. Philip and Jacob and of St. Thomas in Bristol to 1812.</emph> D.K. Gosling. Bristol M.A. 1934.</para>
<para id="p81"><emph type="i">The theory and practice of the Lord's Supper among the early Separatists, Baptists and Independents, from 1580 to 1700.</emph> E.P. Winter. Oxford B.Litt. 1954.</para>
<para id="p82"><emph type="i">Our Lady of Batersey. The story of Battersea church and parish told from original sources.</emph> J.G. Taylor. London Ph.D. 1925.</para>
</section>
<section id="s5">
<head>CULTURAL HISTORY</head>
<section id="s6">
<head>General</head>
<para id="p83"><emph type="i">English biography before 1700.</emph> D.A. Stauffer. Oxford B.Litt. 1931.</para>
<para id="p84"><emph type="i">Studies in the history of the song school at Durham from the early 15th century to the early 18th century.</emph> G.B. Crosby. Durham M.A. 1966.</para>
<para id="p85"><emph type="i">Efforts of patrons to establish endowed schools in Jersey and to provide scholarships at the English universities for Jersey scholars from 1477 to 1679.</emph> W. Moran. London M.A. (Ext.) 1964.</para>
<para id="p86"><emph type="i">The origin and development of academic costume and its bearing on the choir office robes of the Anglican clergy.</emph> F.R.S. Rogers. Bristol M.A. 1962.</para>
<para id="p87"><emph type="i">The education of English Catholics, 1559&ndash;1800.</emph> W.F. Hastings. London M.A. 1923.</para>
<para id="p88"><emph type="i">The provision for the vocational training of children in the East Riding, 1563&ndash;1811.</emph> K.J.R. Robson. Sheffield M.A. 1952.</para>
<para id="p89"><emph type="i">An investigation into the Lettice Dykes Educational Charity at East Bergholt in the county of Suffolk.</emph> M.H. Hyndman. Reading M.A. 1965/6.</para>
<para id="p90"><emph type="i">An outline of development in education in Wallasey, 1595&ndash;1962.</emph> B.E. Baylis. Wales M.A. 1964.</para>
<para id="p91"><emph type="i">The growth of educational institutions in Loughborough, with special reference to the history of Loughborough grammar school and the Burton charity.</emph> A. White. Nottingham Ph.D. 1962.</para>
<para id="p92"><emph type="i">The history of Nottingham High School, 1513&ndash;1903.</emph> A.W. Thomas. Nottingham Ph.D. 1956.</para>
<para id="p93"><emph type="i">A history of Whitchurch grammar school, Shropshire, 1550&ndash;1950.</emph> E. Clarke. Sheffield M.A. 1953.</para>
<para id="p94"><emph type="i">The history of Marlborough grammar school, 1550&ndash;1944, with some account of the mediaeval hospital of St. John Baptist, Marlborough.</emph> A.R. Stedman. London M.A. 1945.</para>
<para id="p95"><emph type="i">The history of St. Clement Danes Holborn Estate grammar school, 1552&ndash;1952.</emph> R.J.B. Pooley. London M.A. 1955.</para>
<para id="p96"><emph type="i">History of St. Peter's School, York.</emph> A. Raine. Durham M.A. 1946.</para>
<para id="p97"><emph type="i">Attitudes towards exercise and physical education in England: 1560&ndash;1714.</emph> D.W. Brailsford. Southampton Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p98"><emph type="i">History of Hampton-upon-Thames in the 16th and 17th centuries, with special reference to educational foundations.</emph> B. Garside. London M.A. 1930.</para>
<para id="p99"><emph type="i">The history of the grammar schools in Monmouthshire.</emph> M. Stephens. Wales M.A. 1957.</para>
<para id="p100"><emph type="i">The history of the Welsh language in Radnorshire since 1536.</emph> L.H. Owen. Liverpool M.A. 1953/4.</para>
<para id="p101"><emph type="i">The vicissitudes of the Welsh language in the Marches of Wales, with special reference to its territorial distribution in modern times.</emph> W.H. Rees. Wales Ph.D. 1947.</para>
<page start="099"/>
</section>
<section id="s7">
<head>Art and Architecture</head>
<para id="p102"><emph type="i">Transition from timber to brick in buildings of rural Leicestershire.</emph> V.R. Webster. Nottingham M.A. 1965.</para>
<para id="p103"><emph type="i">The development of smaller domestic architecture in the Oxford region from the late 15th to the early 18th century.</emph> D. Portman. Oxford B.Litt. 1960.</para>
<para id="p104"><emph type="i">Country house building in Warwickshire, 1500&ndash;1914.</emph> G.C. Tyack. Oxford B.Litt. 1970.</para>
<para id="p105"><emph type="i">Minor domestic architecture in the lower Trent valley, 1550&ndash;1850.</emph> T.L. Marsden. Manchester M.A. 1952.</para>
<para id="p106"><emph type="i">Minor domestic architecture in the county of Rutland and vicinity: an investigation of stages in the historical development of the smaller rural house.</emph> T.L. Marsden. Manchester Ph.D. 1958.</para>
<para id="p107"><emph type="i">Post-medieval timber-framed houses in England.</emph> K.H. Allmark. Manchester M.A. 1955.</para>
<para id="p108"><emph type="i">The development of timber-framed buildings in Tewkesbury.</emph> D.R. Franklin. Birmingham M.A. 1965.</para>
<para id="p109"><emph type="i">Rural domestic architecture in south Lancashire, prior to the early 19th century.</emph> R.S. Partington. Manchester M.A. 1952.</para>
<para id="p110"><emph type="i">Treasures of the Surrey churches in the diocese of Guildford.</emph> C.K.F. Brown. Leeds M.A. 1942.</para>
<para id="p111"><emph type="i">The history of Welsh domestic art from the 16th century, as exhibited in the native furniture, with illustrations together with a study of its relation to the furniture of other parts of the British Isles and the continent of Europe.</emph> D.R. Jones. Wales M.A. 1925.</para>
<para id="p112"><emph type="i">The Oxford school of sculptors from 1550 to 1800.</emph> J.E.K. Esdaile. Oxford B.Litt. 1935.</para>
</section>
</section>
<section id="s8">
<head>LOCAL HISTORY</head>
<para id="p113"><emph type="i">A study of the economic development of the commote of Carnwyllion from 1500.</emph> J.H. Morgan. Wales M.A. 1933.</para>
<para id="p114"><emph type="i">The early history of Hunslet.</emph> G.G. Gamble. Leeds M.A. 1948.</para>
<para id="p115"><emph type="i">Local administration (excluding borough administration) as exemplified in Monmouthshire, 1536&ndash;1835.</emph> B. Howell. Wales M.A. 1951.</para>
<para id="p116"><emph type="i">The origins and early history of the Melton Mowbray town estate: a study in the government of an unincorporated town.</emph> Dorothy Pockley. Leicester Ph.D. 1964.</para>
<para id="p117"><emph type="i">The Scilly Islands during Tudor and Stuart times (approx. 1547&ndash;1700).</emph> T.F.G. Matthews. Oxford B.Litt. 1943.</para>
<para id="p118"><emph type="i">A Kentish Wealden parish (Tonbridge), 1550&ndash;1750.</emph> C.W. Chalklin. Oxford B.Litt. 1960.</para>
<para id="p119"><emph type="i">Sussex market towns, 1550&ndash;1750.</emph> G.O. Cowley. London M.A. 1965.</para>
<para id="p120"><emph type="i">Evolution of local government authorities and areas in Suffolk, 1555 to 1894.</emph> J.H. Whitfield. Kent M.A. 1970.</para>
<para id="p121"><emph type="i">Local government in Wales from the 16th to the 18th century, as exemplified by the work of the quarter sessions of the county.</emph> T.H. Lewis. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1941.</para>
<para id="p122"><emph type="i">The history of South Shields in the 16th and 17th centuries.</emph> Dorothy W. McCallum. Durham M.A. 1936.</para>
<para id="p123"><emph type="i">Borough courts of quarter sessions from the beginning until the end of the 17th century.</emph> M.A. Reed. Birmingham M.A. 1958.</para>
<para id="p124"><emph type="i">The court of Taunton in the 16th and 17th centuries.</emph> R.G.H. Whitty. London M.A. (Ext.) 1932.</para>
<para id="p125"><emph type="i">Local government in the principality of Wales during the 16th and 17th centuries, as illustrated mainly by the extant data relating to the county of Merioneth.</emph> I. Ab Owen Edwards. Wales M.A. 1925.</para>
<page start="100"/>
<para id="p126"><emph type="i">The borough of Tewkesbury, 1575&ndash;1714.</emph> Mary F. Redmond. Birmingham M.A. 1950.</para>
<para id="p127"><emph type="i">The map of Kent, 1575 to 1807.</emph> B.T. Westmarland. London M.A. 1955.</para>
<para id="p128"><emph type="i">Maps of the Isle of Wight, from Boazio to Milne, 1591&ndash;1791.</emph> A.J. Jubb. London M.A. 1959.</para>
<para id="p129"><emph type="i">Marine cartography in Britain from the 16th to the 19th centuries.</emph> A.H.W. Robinson. London Ph.D. 1960.</para>
</section>
<section id="s9">
<head>SCOTLAND</head>
<para id="p130"><emph type="i">Origins and background of the law of succession to arms and dignities in Scotland.</emph> Sir Rupert I.K. Moncreiffe, Bt. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1958.</para>
<para id="p131"><emph type="i">The origin and nature of the legal rights of spouses and children in the Scottish law of succession.</emph> J.C. Gardner. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1927.</para>
<para id="p132"><emph type="i">The jurisdiction of the Scottish privy council, 1532&ndash;1708.</emph> P.G.B. McNeill. Glasgow Ph.D. 1961.</para>
<para id="p133"><emph type="i">Scots burgh finances prior to 1707.</emph> G.S. Pryde. St. Andrews Ph.D. 1926.</para>
<para id="p134"><emph type="i">The survival of a Celtic society in the Mackay country formerly called Strathnaver in northern Scotland from the 16th century.</emph> I. Grimble. Aberdeen Ph.D. 1964.</para>
<para id="p135"><emph type="i">Witchcraft and the church in Scotland subsequent to the Reformation.</emph> J. Gilmore. Glasgow Ph.D. 1948.</para>
<para id="p136"><emph type="i">History of church discipline in Scotland.</emph> I.M. Clark. Aberdeen Ph.D. 1926.</para>
<para id="p137"><emph type="i">An historical survey of education in Angus to the year 1872 from original and contemporary sources, embracing early education and the beginnings of systematic education; the parish school system; burgh schools; schools of industry; and the origin and establishment of infant schools.</emph> J.C. Jessop. St. Andrews Ph.D. 1930.</para>
<para id="p138"><emph type="i">Education in Fife, from the Reformation to 1872.</emph> J.M. Beale. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1953.</para>
<para id="p139"><emph type="i">Church and state in Scottish school education during the Reformation period (1560&ndash;1700).</emph> B.M. Wyllie. London M.A. 1952.</para>
<para id="p140"><emph type="i">An enquiry into the history of registration for publication in Scotland.</emph> L. Ockrent. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1938.</para>
<para id="p141"><emph type="i">The influence of geographical factors on the economic evolution of Scotland to the beginning of the 18th century, mainly as revealed in the development of overseas trade, especially that of the Clyde ports.</emph> J. Walker. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1928.</para>
</section>
<section id="s10">
<head>IRELAND</head>
<para id="p142"><emph type="i">The composition and distribution of woods in Ireland from the 16th century to the establishment of the first Ordnance Survey.</emph> Eileen M. McCracken. Belfast M.Sc. 1944.</para>
<para id="p143"><emph type="i">The history of penal laws against Irish Catholics from 1534 to the treaty of Limerick (1691).</emph> R.W.D. Edwards. London Ph.D. 1933.</para>
<para id="p144"><emph type="i">The financial administration of Ireland to 1817.</emph> T.J. Kiernan. London Ph.D. 1929.</para>
</section>
</section>
</report>
