<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="154855" pubid="1512" publish="true">
<title>Medieval Wales</title>
<subtitle></subtitle>
<section id="s1">
<head>MEDIEVAL WALES</head>
<para id="p1"><emph type="i">The archaeology of east central Wales.</emph> H.N. Jerman. Wales M.A. 1934.</para>
<para id="p2"><emph type="i">The Anglo-Celtic frontier in the lowlands and uplands of the Dee basin of north-east Wales.</emph> J.I. Thomas. Liverpool M.A. 1964.</para>
<para id="p3"><emph type="i">Beliefs and practices of the Celtic Church in Britain.</emph> L. Hardinge. London Ph.D. 1964.</para>
<para id="p4"><emph type="i">Ritual background of Celtic heroes and saints - a study of some of the survivals of pagan elements in early Celtic Christianity.</emph> A.D. Rees. Wales M.A. 1937.</para>
<para id="p5"><emph type="i">Norse relations with Wales.</emph> B.G. Charles. Wales M.A. 1932.</para>
<para id="p6"><emph type="i">The characteristics of the early Christian church in Wales considered especially in relation to the churches in Ireland and in Gaul.</emph> E. Davies. Oxford B.Litt. 1934.</para>
<para id="p7"><emph type="i">The older churches of North Wales.</emph> J.G. Hetherington. Leeds M.A. 1929.</para>
<para id="p8"><emph type="i">The history of the Eisteddfod.</emph> Elizabeth J. Lloyd. Wales M.A. 1913.</para>
<para id="p9"><emph type="i">Transport and communication in medieval Wales.</emph> W.H. Waters. Wales M.A. 1923.</para>
<para id="p10"><emph type="i">A contribution to the study of early invasions of Wales.</emph> H. Higgins. Liverpool M.A. 1921.</para>
<para id="p11"><emph type="i">The Norman conquests in Wales up to 1100 A.D.</emph> J.W. Wilkinson. Wales M.A. 1901.</para>
<para id="p12"><emph type="i">Monasticism in South Wales after the Norman Conquest.</emph> F.G. Cowley. Wales Ph.D. 1965.</para>
<para id="p13"><emph type="i">The medieval pottery of the central Welsh border from the Conquest to 1400.</emph> P.A. Barker. Leicester M.A. 1966.</para>
<para id="p14"><emph type="i">Social classes in the Welsh border region in the early Norman period.</emph> T.A. Gwynne. Nottingham M.A. 1969.</para>
<para id="p15"><emph type="i">The family of Mortimer.</emph> B.P. Evans. Wales Ph.D. 1934.</para>
<para id="p16"><emph type="i">The history of the Nannau family (Merionethshire) to 1623.</emph> B.R. Parry. Wales M.A. 1958.</para>
<para id="p17"><emph type="i">Studies in the social and agrarian history of medieval and early modern Pembrokeshire.</emph> B.E. Howells. Wales M.A. 1956.</para>
<para id="p18"><emph type="i">The medieval boroughs of Pembrokeshire.</emph> P.G. Sudbury. Wales M.A. 1947.</para>
<para id="p19"><emph type="i">The history of the town and castle of Pembroke to 1603.</emph> E.P. Jones. Wales M.A. 1905.</para>
<page start="062"/>
<para id="p20"><emph type="i">The castle and borough of Pembroke during the middle ages.</emph> H. Rees. Wales M.A. 1927.</para>
<para id="p21"><emph type="i">The lordship of Brecon, 1066&ndash;1325.</emph> W. Rees. Wales M.A. 1914.</para>
<para id="p22"><emph type="i">The history of the town, lordship and castle of Builth, from the 11th to the 16th centuries.</emph> G. Wozencroft. Wales M.A. 1919.</para>
<para id="p23"><emph type="i">History of the town and castle of Cardigan.</emph> G. Owen. Wales M.A. 1907.</para>
<para id="p24"><emph type="i">The Norman lordship of Glamorgan, its settlement and early organisation to the death of Gilbert de Clare, 1314.</emph> G. Nesta Jones. Wales M.A. 1921.</para>
<para id="p25"><emph type="i">The lordship of Glamorgan: a study in Marcher government.</emph> J.B. Smith. Wales M.A. 1957.</para>
<para id="p26"><emph type="i">The ecclesiastical history of Glamorgan during the middle ages, up to 1188, with special reference to the period A.D. 1056 to 1188.</emph> L.C. Simons. Wales M.A. 1914.</para>
<para id="p27"><emph type="i">The history of the borough of Kenfig, to 1485.</emph> J.H. Lewis. Wales M.A. 1922.</para>
<para id="p28"><emph type="i">The medieval lordship of Montgomery.</emph> Dora Ward. Wales M.A. 1924.</para>
<para id="p29"><emph type="i">The castle and town of Welshpool during the 12th and 13th centuries.</emph> Alicia G. Jones. Wales M.A. 1911.</para>
<para id="p30"><emph type="i">The boroughs of Radnor to the Act of Union and beyond.</emph> R.M. Morgan. Wales M.A. 1911.</para>
<para id="p31"><emph type="i">The early charter memoranda of the Book of Llandaff.</emph> Wendy E. Davies. London Ph.D. 1970.</para>
<para id="p32"><emph type="i">Llyfr Coch Asaph: a textual and historical study.</emph> O.E. Jones. Wales M.A. 1968.</para>
<para id="p33"><emph type="i">A critical study of the Latin texts of the Welsh laws.</emph> H.D. Emanuel. Wales Ph.D. 1960.</para>
<para id="p34"><emph type="i">Hywel Dda, together with an outline of the origins, affinities and history of the laws called after his name.</emph> W.H. Harris. Oxford B.Litt. 1912.</para>
<para id="p35"><emph type="i">A critical edition of the text of the Gwynedd (or Venedotian) code of medieval Welsh law.</emph> A.I.R. Wiliam. Oxford D.Phil. 1952.</para>
<para id="p36"><emph type="i">The policy of Powys in the 12th and 13th centuries.</emph> F.L. Rees. Wales M.A. 1911.</para>
<para id="p37"><emph type="i">The early history of Flintshire, with special reference to the foundation of the diocese of St. Asaph.</emph> J.F. Sharp. Liverpool M.A. 1924.</para>
<para id="p38"><emph type="i">The history of Valle Crucis abbey, Denbighshire.</emph> E.J. Fisher. Liverpool M.A. 1929.</para>
<para id="p39"><emph type="i">Pre-Edwardian castles in North Wales.</emph> H. Owen. Liverpool M.A. 1914.</para>
<para id="p40"><emph type="i">The influence of topographical conditions on the English campaigns in Wales in the 12th and 13th centuries.</emph> D.W. Rees. Wales M.A. 1923.</para>
<para id="p41"><emph type="i">The military geography of Gwynedd in the 13th century.</emph> G.R.J. Jones. Wales M.A. 1949.</para>
<para id="p42"><emph type="i">The cymwds of Gwynedd, prior to the Edwardian conquest of Wales.</emph> G.L. Jones. Wales M.A. 1919.</para>
<para id="p43"><emph type="i">The early history of Newcastle Emlyn, to include a study of the data relating to castle, town and lordship down to the Act of Union, 1536.</emph> T.J. James. Wales M.A. 1913.</para>
<para id="p44"><emph type="i">The medieval borough of Beaumaris and the commote of Dindaethwy, 1200&ndash;1600.</emph> C.M. Evans. Wales M.A. 1949.</para>
<para id="p45"><emph type="i">The history of the town and castle of Carmarthen to 1603.</emph> D.M. Roberts. Wales M.A. 1908.</para>
<para id="p46"><emph type="i">The development of the Penrhyn estate up to 1431.</emph> J.R. Jones. Wales M.A. 1955.</para>
<para id="p47"><emph type="i">Giraldus Cambrensis, De Invectionibus, transcribed from the Vatican manuscript and edited with an historical introduction.</emph> W.S. Davies. Wales M.A. 1921.</para>
<para id="p48"><emph type="i">Types of social life illustrated by the writings of Gerald of Wales.</emph> Dorothy Humphreys. Oxford B.Litt. 1936.</para>
<page start="063"/>
<para id="p49"><emph type="i">The life of St. David by Giraldus Cambrensis.</emph> T.B. Jones. Wales M.A. 1934.</para>
<para id="p50"><emph type="i">The Friars in Wales.</emph> Ruth C. Easterling. Wales M.A. 1913.</para>
<para id="p51"><emph type="i">A study of Anglo-Welsh political relations, with special reference to constitutional matters, 1218&ndash;82.</emph> A.J. Roderick. Wales M.A. 1935.</para>
<para id="p52"><emph type="i">The Book of Aneirin.</emph> I. Williams. Wales M.A. 1907.</para>
<para id="p53"><emph type="i">The Welsh Church under Edward I.</emph> Elizabeth Thomas. Wales M.A. 1912.</para>
<para id="p54"><emph type="i">The bishops and chapter of St. David's, <emph type="i">c</emph>. 1280&ndash;1407.</emph> W. Greenway. Cambridge M.Litt. 1959.</para>
<para id="p55"><emph type="i">The growth and development of the municipal element in the principality of North Wales up to the close of the 14th century.</emph> E.A. Lewis. Wales M.A. 1902.</para>
<para id="p56"><emph type="i">The lordship and castle of Chirk, 1282&ndash;1660.</emph> Mary Jones. Wales M.A. 1920.</para>
<para id="p57"><emph type="i">The barons of Edeyrnion, 1282&ndash;1485: a study of tenure by Welsh barony, with special reference to Edeyrnion.</emph> A.D. Carr. Wales M.A. 1963.</para>
<para id="p58"><emph type="i">The lordship of Denbigh, 1282&ndash;1425.</emph> D.H. Owen. Wales Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p59"><emph type="i">Flint: the castle and town in the 13th and 14th centuries.</emph> E.O. Parry. Wales M.A. 1927.</para>
<para id="p60"><emph type="i">The castle, town, and lordship of Kidwelly to 1300 A.D.</emph> A.J. Richard. Wales M.A. 1912.</para>
<para id="p61"><emph type="i">The Edwardian settlement of Wales, 1284&ndash;1307.</emph> J.G. Edwards. Manchester M.A. 1915.</para>
<para id="p62"><emph type="i">The Edwardian settlement of North Wales.</emph> W.H. Waters. Cambridge M.Litt. 1925/6.</para>
<para id="p63"><emph type="i">Wales and the Marches in the reign of Edward II, with special reference to Glamorgan and the revolt of Llewelyn Bren.</emph> T.A. Dyke. Wales M.A. 1912.</para>
<para id="p64"><emph type="i">The history of Wales during the reign of Edward II, 1307&ndash;27.</emph> J. Conway Davies. Wales M.A. 1914.</para>
<para id="p65"><emph type="i">The principality of Wales under Edward the Black Prince.</emph> D.L. Evans. Oxford B.Litt. 1930.</para>
<para id="p66"><emph type="i">The Lancaster and Bohun lordships in Wales in the 14th and early 15th centuries.</emph> R.R. Davies. Oxford D.Phil. 1965.</para>
<para id="p67"><emph type="i">The available data for the Black Death in Wales.</emph> Winifred S. Williams. Wales M.A. 1920.</para>
<para id="p68"><emph type="i">The religious and social condition of Wales at the outbreak of the Glyndwr movement, with special reference to the attitude of the clergy, both regular and secular, to the movement.</emph> J.R. Gabriel. Wales M.A. 1906.</para>
<para id="p69"><emph type="i">The Welsh Church and Welsh politics in the war of Owen Glyndwr.</emph> J.T. Davies. Liverpool M.A. 1920.</para>
<para id="p70"><emph type="i">Royal government in the southern counties of the principality of Wales, 1422&ndash;85.</emph> R.A. Griffiths. Bristol Ph.D. 1962.</para>
<para id="p71"><emph type="i">The rise and fall of the house of Dinefwr (the Rhys family), 1430&ndash;1530.</emph> J.M. Lloyd. Wales M.A. 1963.</para>
<para id="p72"><emph type="i">Welsh politics from Mortimer's Cross to Bosworth Field.</emph> W.G. Jones. Liverpool M.A. 1908.</para>
<para id="p73"><emph type="i">The bardic order in the 15th century.</emph> T.W.L. Davies. Wales M.A. 1910.</para>
</section>
</report>
