<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE report SYSTEM "dtd/report.dtd">
<report id="154856" pubid="1512" publish="true">
<title>Medieval Scotland</title>
<subtitle></subtitle>
<section id="s1">
<head>MEDIEVAL SCOTLAND</head>
<para id="p1"><emph type="i">A new survey of contacts between Celtic Scotland and pre-Viking Northumbria (<emph type="i">c</emph>.500-<emph type="i">c</emph>.850).</emph> D.P. Kirby. Durham Ph.D. 1962.</para>
<para id="p2"><emph type="i">A critical examination of some of the sources for the history of the Picts from A.D. 550 to A.D. 850.</emph> Mrs. Isabel B. Henderson. Cambridge Ph.D. 1962.</para>
<page start="064"/>
<para id="p3"><emph type="i">Scoto-Celtic architecture - its place among the styles.</emph> C. Sinclair. Glasgow Ph.D. 1932.</para>
<para id="p4"><emph type="i">A critical edition of the <emph type="i">Senchus Fer nAlban</emph>, with an assessment of its historical value.</emph> J.W.M. Bannerman. Cambridge Ph.D. 1964.</para>
<para id="p5"><emph type="i">The burgh of the Canongate and its court.</emph> A.H. Anderson. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1949.</para>
<para id="p6"><emph type="i">Scottish burghs: some aspects of their origins, development and plan.</emph> K. Alauddin. Glasgow B.Litt. 1969.</para>
<para id="p7"><emph type="i">The office of sheriff in Scotland; its origin and early development.</emph> C.A. Malcolm. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1922.</para>
<para id="p8"><emph type="i">Queen Margaret and the influence she exerted on the Celtic Church in Scotland.</emph> T.R. Barnett. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1925.</para>
<para id="p9"><emph type="i">Scottish monasticism: its relations with the Crown and the church to the year 1378.</emph> D.E. Easson. St. Andrews Ph.D. 1928.</para>
<para id="p10"><emph type="i">The historical geography of Strathmore and its highland boundary zone from A.D. 1100 to A.D. 1603.</emph> J. Gilbert. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1954.</para>
<para id="p11"><emph type="i">Scottish royal ecclesiastical policy, 1107&ndash;1214, with special reference to foreign influence in the spread of the monastic orders and the personnel of the episcopate in England.</emph> G.W.S. Barrow. Oxford B.Litt. 1950.</para>
<para id="p12"><emph type="i">The <emph type="i">De Tribus Processionibus</emph> of Richard St. Victor: a critical text with introduction.</emph> W.J. Tulloch. Liverpool M.A. 1945.</para>
<para id="p13"><emph type="i">Adam of Dryburgh.</emph> J.B.P. Bulloch. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1955.</para>
<para id="p14"><emph type="i">The sources of the Aberdeen breviary.</emph> J.D. Galbraith. Aberdeen M.Litt. 1970.</para>
<para id="p15"><emph type="i">History of the clan Macrae.</emph> A. Macrae. London M.A. 1905.</para>
<para id="p16"><emph type="i">Strategy and tactics in medieval Scotland.</emph> J.D. Forbes. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1927.</para>
<para id="p17"><emph type="i">The expansion of the English language in Scotland.</emph> L.W. Sharp. Cambridge Ph.D. 1926/7.</para>
<para id="p18"><emph type="i">Feudal tenures in Scotland in the 12th and 13th centuries.</emph> Mrs. Isabel A. Durack. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1953.</para>
<para id="p19"><emph type="i">An examination of the grants of land made to the Scottish Church in the 12th and 13th centuries, with special reference to secular services.</emph> T. Davidson. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1930.</para>
<para id="p20"><emph type="i">The diocese of Glasgow in the 12th and 13th centuries. With an edition of the bishops' <emph type="i">acta</emph> (<emph type="i">c</emph>.1140&ndash;1258).</emph> F.N. Shead. Glasgow B.Litt. 1966.</para>
<para id="p21"><emph type="i">Ecclesiastical patronage in the medieval period, with special reference to parochial benefices in Scotland.</emph> G.P. Innes. Glasgow Ph.D. 1960.</para>
<para id="p22"><emph type="i">Appropriation of parish churches in medieval Scotland.</emph> I.B. Cowan. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1961.</para>
<para id="p23"><emph type="i">An Anglo-Scottish baron of the 13th century: the acts of Roger de Quincy, earl of Winchester and constable of Scotland.</emph> G.G. Simpson. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1966.</para>
<para id="p24"><emph type="i">The relations between England and Scotland during the minority of Alexander III and during the Barons' Wars.</emph> W.A. Cane. Manchester M.A. 1923.</para>
<para id="p25"><emph type="i">The organisation of the English occupation in Scotland, 1296&ndash;1461.</emph> D.W.H. Marshall. Oxford B.Litt. 1926.</para>
<para id="p26"><emph type="i">Death practices and burial rites in Scotland from the later medieval period to 1780, with particular reference to the influence of theology.</emph> R.S. Fredericks. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1967.</para>
<para id="p27"><emph type="i">The defence of the north-western border against the Scots during the first half of the 14th century.</emph> T. Wood. Manchester M.A. 1937.</para>
<para id="p28"><emph type="i">The Scottish wars of Edward III, 1327&ndash;35.</emph> R.G. Nicholson. Oxford D.Phil. 1961.</para>
<page start="065"/>
<para id="p29"><emph type="i">Scotsmen at universities between 1340 and 1410 and their subsequent careers: a study of the contribution of graduates to the public life of their country.</emph> D.E.R. Watt. Oxford D.Phil. 1957.</para>
<para id="p30"><emph type="i">The medieval universities of Scotland, 1410&ndash;1560.</emph> J. Durkan. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1959.</para>
<para id="p31"><emph type="i">Scotland and the Wars of the Roses, 1435&ndash;85.</emph> C. Macrae. Oxford D.Phil. 1939.</para>
<para id="p32"><emph type="i">The exchequer and Crown revenue of Scotland, 1437&ndash;1542.</emph> A.L. Murray. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1961.</para>
<para id="p33"><emph type="i">The economic administration of Coupar Angus abbey, 1440&ndash;1560.</emph> J.L. Morgan. Glasgow Ph.D. 1929.</para>
<para id="p34"><emph type="i">James Kennedy, bishop of St. Andrews.</emph> Anne I. Cameron. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1924.</para>
<para id="p35"><emph type="i">The office of parish clerk in the Scottish Church between 1450 and 1560.</emph> D.A. McKay. London Ph.D. (Ext.) 1960.</para>
<para id="p36"><emph type="i">The rise of a Scottish navy, 1460&ndash;1513.</emph> F.W. Robertson. Edinburgh Ph.D. 1933/4.</para>
<para id="p37"><emph type="i">James III: a political study (1466&ndash;88).</emph> N.A.T. MacDougall. Glasgow Ph.D. 1968.</para>
</section>
</report>
